<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <atom:link href="https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Libraries</title>
    <link>https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>18 Sep 25 06:07 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.6</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Peer Review in Transition: Helen King and Christopher Leonard on AI and the Future of Peer Review</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/18/peer-review-in-transition-helen-king-and-christopher-leonard-on-ai-and-the-future-of-peer-review/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today, we talk to thought leaders Helen King and Chris Leonard, who offer a nuanced look at how peer review might adapt, fracture, or reinvent itself in the AI era.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/18/peer-review-in-transition-helen-king-and-christopher-leonard-on-ai-and-the-future-of-peer-review/">Peer Review in Transition: Helen King and Christopher Leonard on AI and the Future of Peer Review</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60982</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Tackling Textbook Affordability</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/tackling-textbook-affordability/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Earlier this month, Empire State University announced that, with funding from ECMC Foundation and in collaboration with Ithaka S+R, Buffalo State University, and SUNY Fredonia, it is undertaking a new project to analyze, pilot, and evaluate affordable course material models. Ithaka S+R is excited to be part of this important work and continue our research [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/tackling-textbook-affordability/">Tackling Textbook Affordability</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323645</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Peer Review in the Era of AI: Risks, Rewards, and Responsibilities</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/17/peer-review-in-the-era-of-ai-risks-rewards-and-responsibilities/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The future of peer review isn’t about choosing between humans and AI, or between speed and quality, but about combining the strengths of both to enable speed with quality, to ensure quality, ethics, and trust in the scholarly record.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/17/peer-review-in-the-era-of-ai-risks-rewards-and-responsibilities/">Peer Review in the Era of AI: Risks, Rewards, and Responsibilities</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60967</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Open Access: ETH Zurich leads the way globally</title>
      <link>https://rc-blog.ethz.ch/en/open-access-eth-zurich-leads-the-way-globally/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Thanks to its unique conditions, ETH Zurich is an international leader in terms of its share of open access publications, as analyses by the ETH Library show. This leads to greater visibility and strengthens research. Read more]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://rc-blog.ethz.ch/?p=2893</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Misalliance, by George Bernard Shaw</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/misalliance</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[On a pleasant summer afternoon, a sudden plane crash followed by a would-be assassin interrupt a family’s conversations about marriage.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/misalliance/downloads/george-bernard-shaw_misalliance.epub?source=feed" length="543425" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/misalliance</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — Is It Enough to Say a Journal Is ‘Peer Reviewed’? The Case for Rating Journals Based on Peer Review Quality</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/16/guest-post-is-it-enough-to-say-a-journal-is-peer-reviewed-the-case-for-rating-journals-based-on-peer-review-quality/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Peer Review Quality Ratings could offer a powerful step toward restoring faith in the scholarly research system, highlight exemplary practices, and ensure that robust, verified science continues to illuminate the path forward for humanity.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/16/guest-post-is-it-enough-to-say-a-journal-is-peer-reviewed-the-case-for-rating-journals-based-on-peer-review-quality/">Guest Post — Is It Enough to Say a Journal Is &#8216;Peer Reviewed&#8217;? The Case for Rating Journals Based on Peer Review Quality</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60964</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Meet the candidates and cast your vote in our 2025 Board elections</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/2025-board-election/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>On behalf of the Nominating Committee, I’m pleased to share the slate of candidates for the 2025 board election.</p>
        <p>Each year we do an open call for board interest. This year, the Nominating Committee received 51 submissions from members worldwide to fill five open board seats.</p>
        <p>We have four large member seats and one small member seat open for election in 2025. We maintain a balanced board of 8 large member seats and 8 small member seats. Size is determined based on the organization&rsquo;s membership tier (small members fall in the $0-$1,650 tiers and large members in the $3,900 - $50,000 tiers).</p>
        <p>We were pleased to see the diversity in candidates, with applicants from 19 countries. The committee was keen to prepare a diverse slate of organization types, individual skills and perspectives, and global representation.</p>
        <h2 id="tier-1-small-member-seats-electing-one-candidate">Tier 1, Small member seats (electing one candidate)</h2>
        <ul>
        <li><strong>Rebecca Wambua</strong>, Distance, Open and e-Learning Practitioners&rsquo; Association of Kenya</li>
        <li><strong>Oscar Donde</strong>, Pan Africa Science Journal</li>
        <li><strong>Nwachukwu Egbunike</strong>, Pan-Atlantic University Press</li>
        </ul>
        <h2 id="tier-2-large-member-seats-electing-four-candidates">Tier 2, Large member seats (electing four candidates)</h2>
        <ul>
        <li><strong>Damian Bird</strong>, CABI</li>
        <li><strong>Rose L&rsquo;Huillier</strong>, Elsevier</li>
        <li><strong>John Sivo</strong>, IEEE</li>
        <li><strong>Nick Lindsay</strong>, The MIT Press</li>
        <li><strong>Anjalie Nawaratne</strong>, Springer Nature</li>
        </ul>
        <div class="shortcode-divwrap blue-highlight">
        <span><h3 id="please-read-the-candidates-statementsboard-and-governanceelections2025-slate"><a href="https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/elections/2025-slate/">Please read the candidates&rsquo; statements</a></h3>
        </span>
        </div>
        <h2 id="every-member-has-a-vote">Every member has a vote</h2>
        <p>If your organisation is a voting member in good standing as of September 5th, 2025, you are eligible to vote.</p>
        <p>The voting contact for your organisation will receive a ballot from eBallot, a third party election platform. You should receive your ballot by Wednesday, September 17th, and you will have until 12:00 UTC on October 22nd to submit your ballot.</p>
        <p>The election results will be announced at <a href="https://www.crossref.org/crossref-annual-meeting/">Crossref2025</a>, our annual online meeting on October 22nd, 2025.</p>
        <p>Special thanks to the committee: James Phillpotts of Oxford University Press, Wendy Patterson of Beilstein Institut, Abiodun Falodun of University of Benin, Amanda Ward of Taylor &amp; Francis, and Chaerul Umam of the National Library of Indonesia for the time they dedicated to reviewing the expressions of interest and participating in committee meetings.</p>
        <p>If you have any questions about our election process, please <a href="mailto:lofiesh@crossref.org">contact me</a></p>
        <p>Happy voting!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/2025-board-election/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>That Affair Next Door, by Anna Katharine Green</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anna-katharine-green/that-affair-next-door</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Mysterious midnight visitors to a New York mansion are observed by a spinster living next door.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anna-katharine-green/that-affair-next-door/downloads/anna-katharine-green_that-affair-next-door.epub?source=feed" length="709205" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anna-katharine-green/that-affair-next-door</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Travel Essays, by Robert Louis Stevenson</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/robert-louis-stevenson/travel-essays</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of Robert Louis Stevenson’s travel essays.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/robert-louis-stevenson/travel-essays/downloads/robert-louis-stevenson_travel-essays.epub?source=feed" length="35530205" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/robert-louis-stevenson/travel-essays</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Day in Review (September 15–18)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/uncategorized/day-in-review-september-15-18/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 15, 2025, 3:44 pm ET Sign up to receive the Day in Review by email. Jump to: Tuesday, September 16 &#124; Wednesday, September 17 &#124; Thursday,...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/uncategorized/day-in-review-september-15-18/">Day in Review (September 15–18)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=45972</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Day in Review (September 15–18)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-september-15-18/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 17, 2025, 1:35 pm ET Sign up to receive the Day in Review by email. Jump to: Tuesday, September 16 &#124; Wednesday, September 17 &#124; Thursday,...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-september-15-18/">Day in Review (September 15–18)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=45972</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>An Update on the Great 78s Lawsuit</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/09/15/an-update-on-the-great-78s-lawsuit/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[As noted in the recent court filings in UMG Recordings, Inc. v. Internet Archive, both parties have advised the Court that the matter has been settled. The parties have reached [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29305</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Master Mind of Mars, by Edgar Rice Burroughs</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edgar-rice-burroughs/the-master-mind-of-mars</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new hero from Earth reaches Mars and battles a merchant of purloined youth.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edgar-rice-burroughs/the-master-mind-of-mars/downloads/edgar-rice-burroughs_the-master-mind-of-mars.epub?source=feed" length="430418" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edgar-rice-burroughs/the-master-mind-of-mars</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ARL Celebrates Hispanic Heritage Month 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/arl-celebrates-hispanic-heritage-month-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 17, 2025, 4:56 pm ET Join us in honoring Hispanic Heritage Month (September 15–October 15). Below is a roundup of blog posts, exhibits, and other resources...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/arl-celebrates-hispanic-heritage-month-2025/">ARL Celebrates Hispanic Heritage Month 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=45954</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Reflections from the Pennsylvania Adult Learner Re-Engagement Community of Practice</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/reflections-from-the-pennsylvania-adult-learner-re-engagement-community-of-practice/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Adult learners are frequently overlooked, but are an increasingly important student population. According to a recent report from the National Student Clearinghouse Research Center, there are 37.6 million adult learners under 65 with some college credit, but no credential in the US and this number is increasing. In response to this challenge, Ithaka S+R is working across the United States to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of pathways for returning adult learners.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/reflections-from-the-pennsylvania-adult-learner-re-engagement-community-of-practice/">Reflections from the Pennsylvania Adult Learner Re-Engagement Community of Practice</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323605</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Ask the Chefs: What’s a Bold Experiment with AI in Peer Review You’d Like to See Tested?</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/15/ask-the-chefs-whats-a-bold-experiment-with-ai-in-peer-review-youd-like-to-see-tested/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>To kick off Peer Review Week, we asked the Chefs, What’s a bold experiment with AI in peer review you’d like to see tested?</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/15/ask-the-chefs-whats-a-bold-experiment-with-ai-in-peer-review-youd-like-to-see-tested/">Ask the Chefs: What’s a Bold Experiment with AI in Peer Review You’d Like to See Tested?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60972</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A second look at Crossref&#39;s carbon footprint - the 2024 report</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/a-second-look-at-crossrefs-carbon-footprint-the-2024-report/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In 2022, we wrote a blog post <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/bnv9r-q8f86" target="_blank">“Rethinking staff travel, meetings, and events”</a> outlining our new approach to staff travel, meetings, and events with the goal of not going back to ‘normal’ after the pandemic and said that in the future we would report on our efforts to balance online and virtual events, work life balance for staff, and track our carbon emissions. In December 2024, we wrote a blog post, <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/jjr25-es246" target="_blank">“Summary of the environmental impact of Crossref,”</a> that gave an overview of 2023 and provided the first report on our carbon emissions. Our report on 2023 only just made it into 2024, so we are happy to report on 2024 a little sooner in the year.</p>
        <p>On the positive side, there are a few things:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Our spending on travel and meetings (a proxy for emissions) in 2024 was 56% of what it was in 2019, keeping below the target of not more than 60% of our 2019 spend</li>
        <li>We were better at tracking hotel nights in 2024 compared to 2023</li>
        <li>We managed to balance in-person, regional, and online meetings to engage with our global community while still not having returned to the pre-pandemic “normal”</li>
        </ul>
        <p>In practice, our approach means thinking carefully about how to make the most of each trip. For example, when organising our Crossref Jakarta event, we travelled via Singapore and used the opportunity to meet with members there. Once in Jakarta, we combined our two-day event with an OJS workshop with colleagues from PKP, and another event with Universitas Indonesia. Similarly, when our colleague travelled by train to a conference in Amsterdam, they combined it with a day of visits to members in the area. These kinds of combinations reduce the need for separate trips and maximise the value of in-person travel.</p>
        <p>Some of the less positive things were:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>As our membership continues to grow globally and we expand our staff, (which are both great things in themselves), our emissions have also increased. Not only do we have more staff, but some staff travelled more in 2024 than in 2023. We’ll keep a close eye on this to avoid ever-increasing travel.</li>
        <li>Taking a train instead of flying can take longer, and clashes with our desire for staff needing to be away from home as little time as possible.</li>
        <li>It is difficult to find reliable data for some calculations - for example, we have decided not to try to calculate the impact of our Zoom use because there is no reliable way to do this.</li>
        <li>We don’t have good options for offsetting our emissions, and it’s unclear whether we would want to do this even if they were available.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>There is also the issue of whether it is worth it, or possible, to collect certain data, or whether it would change what we do. An example is Zoom. The estimate for the emissions from Zoom meetings in 2024 was 100 kg (that’s kilograms, not tonnes), but the calculations were made using a tool from 2020 that made many assumptions and estimates. We have no way of verifying whether the tool we used is accurate, so we decided not to update our previous calculation. In any case, we aren’t going to ration or reduce our teleconferencing, since it’s an essential tool, and especially if we want to fly less, have fewer in-person meetings, and operate effectively as a distributed organisation in multiple countries with no offices.</p>
        <p>In summary, our total reported carbon emissions increased 40% from 105 tCO2e in 2023 to 147 tCO2e in 2024 (see below for the details). The positive aspect of this is that the increase is partly due to our improved ability to track our travel and hotel stays. The more concerning side of this is that we are travelling more. This enables us to engage with our growing community. We are still thinking strategically about our travel and meetings, following the approach outlined in our 2022 blog post. However, we need to carefully consider air travel in 2026, as it is our largest source of emissions (93%).</p>
        <h2 id="total-travel-and-carbon-spending">Total travel and carbon spending</h2>
        <table>
        <thead>
        <tr>
        <th>Year</th>
        <th>Amount</th>
        <th>Percentage of 2019</th>
        <th>Total carbon spent</th>
        <th>Total hotel nights covered</th>
        </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
        <tr>
        <td>2019 actuals</td>
        <td>$585,482</td>
        <td>100%</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>2020 actuals</td>
        <td>$91,700</td>
        <td>16%</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>2021 actuals</td>
        <td>$19,066</td>
        <td>3%</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>2022 actuals</td>
        <td>$74,416</td>
        <td>13%</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>2023 actuals</td>
        <td>$305,737</td>
        <td>52%</td>
        <td>105 tCO2e</td>
        <td>did not record</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>2024 actuals</td>
        <td>$327,939</td>
        <td>56%</td>
        <td>147 tCO2e</td>
        <td>415</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>2025 budget</td>
        <td>$417,767 (reforecast)</td>
        <td>71%</td>
        <td>68 tCO2e (YTD)</td>
        <td>256 (YTD)</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>2026 budget</td>
        <td>$439,817</td>
        <td>75%</td>
        <td>TBD</td>
        <td>TBD</td>
        </tr>
        </tbody>
        </table>
        <p>In 2024, we met the target of keeping our travel expenses below 60% of our 2019 level. In 2025, we will exceed this. There are a number of reasons for this. We have more staff, more members, inflation has been high, and we are subsidising a lot more travel for others, such as our ambassadors, speakers, and collaborators at local events, and some board members (since 2019, we reduced from three to one in-person board meeting per year). This aligns with our goals of inclusivity for Crossref meetings, but we have to recognise there is a trade-off. The cost of travel, particularly airfare, has increased since 2019. Using US Bureau of Labor Statistics data from 2019 to 2025 the inflation multiplier for a dollar is 1.26 so adjusted for inflation the comparison figure for 2025 spending is $737,000 and forecasted 2025 spending is 60% of this. While we use cost as a proxy for travel volume, now that we’re better at tracking actual carbon emissions, we can try to set targets of keeping under a certain carbon tonne equivalent total instead of (only) a financial target.</p>
        <h2 id="total-carbon-emissions-for-2024">Total Carbon Emissions for 2024</h2>
        <p>Our total reported carbon emissions increased 40% from 105 tCO2e in 2023 to 147 tCO2e in 2024. In 2023, we didn’t report on the estimated emissions from hotel stays, but for 2024, we have. We recorded 415 hotel nights in 2024 for 4 tCO2e using an average of Europe/US hotel per night emissions estimates <a href="https://circularecology.com/news/the-carbon-emissions-of-staying-in-a-hotel" target="_blank">(Circular Ecology)</a>. The most carbon-intensive activity was flying. There were about 215 flights in 2024, accounting for emissions of 138 tCO2e - 93% of our total. Crossref staff and community members we covered took 88 train journeys with carbon emissions of .47 tCO2e - so the more travel by train, the better, but this isn’t always possible or feasible. We haven’t included estimates of the impact of home working (Crossref is fully distributed), but we have an initial estimate below and will look to improve this analysis for the 2025 analysis and going forward.</p>
        <h2 id="estimate-of-carbon-footprint-for-distributed-staff">Estimate of carbon footprint for distributed staff</h2>
        <p>Crossref is fully distributed with staff in 11 countries. We used Claude from Anthropic to calculate the emissions from home working for our staff in 2024 and asked for sources to be cited. It provided some approaches for how to go about the calculations but the results were not reliable - for our 46 staff in 10 countries (this is for 2024 - we now have 49 staff in 11 countries) estimates ranged from 5 tCO2e to 28 tCO2e depending on various assumptions such as whether to account for the grid intensity of the countries where staff are based <a href="https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/carbon-intensity-electricity" target="_blank">(Our World in Data has grid intensity figures)</a> and what estimate is used for the amount of energy an employee working from home uses each day. <a href="https://circularecology.com/news/the-carbon-emissions-of-homeworking-and-office-working" target="_blank">Circular Ecology</a> uses UK DEFRA figures to come up with 2.67 kgCO2e/day for home working. So a simple calculation of 46 staff working 230 days per year arrives at the 28 tCO2e amount. This is much less than the equivalent figure for office-based work, which is 70 tCO2e. A number of things aren’t factored into these calculations: staff with green energy tariffs, staff with solar panels and home batteries, or other renewable energy sources, and the different needs for heating and air conditioning in different countries.</p>
        <p>We decided not to include these figures in our overall emissions for 2024, but we are looking at a more reliable way to estimate this for 2025. However, we need to consider what we would do with the information and whether we would, or could, do anything to reduce this.</p>
        <h2 id="hosting-services">Hosting services</h2>
        <p>We use AWS for hosting our REST APIs, Metadata Search, and the website. In 2024, our main metadata registry was in a data centre in Massachusetts, which is not included in our calculations. In July 2025, we transitioned fully to AWS, so from 2025 onwards, our emissions from AWS will be higher and will encompass our entire system.</p>
        <p>In 2023, Amazon reports Crossref’s carbon emissions were 0.216 tCO2e compared with 0.266 tCO2e in 2022. In 2024, emissions were 0.132 tCO2e.</p>
        <p>Compared to travel, the footprint from AWS is minimal.</p>
        <h2 id="online-meetings">Online meetings</h2>
        <p>As a distributed, remote-first organisation, Crossref is a heavy Zoom user––it’s essential for staff and for engaging with our community. However, Zoom doesn’t provide tools or estimates of the carbon impact of Zoom meetings. We used a tool last year to provide an estimate, but we aren’t confident it’s accurate or meaningful. The tool was built in 2020 and made a lot of assumptions and guestimates.</p>
        <h2 id="tools-we-used">Tools we used</h2>
        <p>To calculate emissions for flights and train journeys, we chose to use <a href="https://www.carbonfootprint.com/calculator.aspx" target="_blank">Carbon Calculator</a>. For hotel stays and home working estimates, we used <a href="https://circularecology.com/news/the-carbon-emissions-of-staying-in-a-hotel" target="_blank">Circular Ecology</a>. For AWS, we used the <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/aws-cost-management/aws-customer-carbon-footprint-tool/" target="_blank">Customer Carbon Footprint Tool (CCFT)</a> provided by AWS.</p>
        <h2 id="offsetting">Offsetting</h2>
        <p>We don’t offset our emissions from travel or other operations and don’t have plans to do this. Offsetting emissions is problematic in a number of different ways, so we don’t feel confident in doing it.</p>
        <h2 id="in-conclusion">In conclusion</h2>
        <p>In general, it feels good to have had a few years of tracking this, learning more, finding the right tools, and trying to stick to a target to limit our increases. While of course there are always reasons for the target to increase—as we grow and are able to subsidise others beyond our staff more—we remain committed to not just monitoring our carbon spend but also maintaining it at a reasonable level and finding ways to limit and mitigate our impact on the environment. This kind of sustainability isn’t included in the POSI Principles for open scholarly infrastructures, but we’d love to see other similar organisations share their tips and measurements so that, as a community, we can learn how to do even better.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/a-second-look-at-crossrefs-carbon-footprint-the-2024-report/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The House of the Dead, by Fyodor Dostoevsky</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/fyodor-dostoevsky/the-house-of-the-dead/constance-garnett</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A ex-convict in 19th-century Russia reminisces on his experiences in a Siberian prison.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/fyodor-dostoevsky/the-house-of-the-dead/constance-garnett/downloads/fyodor-dostoevsky_the-house-of-the-dead_constance-garnett.epub?source=feed" length="726923" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/fyodor-dostoevsky/the-house-of-the-dead/constance-garnett</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Blind Mice, by C. Kay Scott</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/c-kay-scott/blind-mice</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A woman struggles to save her friendships and her marriage when her difficult and melodramatic mother comes for an extended visit.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/c-kay-scott/blind-mice/downloads/c-kay-scott_blind-mice.epub?source=feed" length="775612" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/c-kay-scott/blind-mice</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Directions in Scholarly Publishing: What We’re Looking Forward to This Year</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/12/new-directions-in-scholarly-publishing-what-were-looking-forward-to-this-year/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>What can you expect from this fall’s New Directions in Scholarly Publishing Seminar in Washington, DC?</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/12/new-directions-in-scholarly-publishing-what-were-looking-forward-to-this-year/">New Directions in Scholarly Publishing: What We’re Looking Forward to This Year</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60947</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>John Unsworth on Libraries, Higher Education, and Anti-Fascism</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/john-unsworth-on-libraries-higher-education-and-anti-facism/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 12, 2025, 1:12 pm ET John Unsworth retired this month as university librarian and dean of libraries at the University of Virginia (UVA), after more than...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/john-unsworth-on-libraries-higher-education-and-anti-facism/">John Unsworth on Libraries, Higher Education, and Anti-Fascism</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=45000</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Bridal Wreath, by Sigrid Undset</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/sigrid-undset/the-bridal-wreath/charles-archer_j-s-scott</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In 14th-century Norway, a nobleman’s daughter grows up and faces passion, sin, and filial piety.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/sigrid-undset/the-bridal-wreath/charles-archer_j-s-scott/downloads/sigrid-undset_the-bridal-wreath_charles-archer-j-s-scott.epub?source=feed" length="909754" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/sigrid-undset/the-bridal-wreath/charles-archer_j-s-scott</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Short Fiction, by Clifford D. Simak</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clifford-d-simak/short-fiction</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of short fiction by Clifford D. Simak, ordered by date of original publication.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clifford-d-simak/short-fiction/downloads/clifford-d-simak_short-fiction.epub?source=feed" length="527833" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clifford-d-simak/short-fiction</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Student Success Research Featured in Special Edition of Peabody Journal of Education</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/student-success-research-featured-in-special-edition-of-peabody-journal-of-education/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We are excited to announce the publication of a special issue of the Peabody Journal of Education, now available online and in print, featuring a series of original research articles that examine strategies for improving lower-income student success at high-graduation-rate institutions. You can read about the American Talent Initiative grant program that funded this research [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/student-success-research-featured-in-special-edition-of-peabody-journal-of-education/">Student Success Research Featured in Special Edition of Peabody Journal of Education</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323568</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>When the Scoreboard Becomes the Game, It’s Time to Recalibrate Research Metrics</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/11/guest-post-when-the-scoreboard-becomes-the-game-its-time-to-recalibrate-research-metrics/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's post discusses research metrics and their relationship to research integrity, inclusivity, and long-term impact.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/11/guest-post-when-the-scoreboard-becomes-the-game-its-time-to-recalibrate-research-metrics/">When the Scoreboard Becomes the Game, It’s Time to Recalibrate Research Metrics</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60936</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Welcoming a New Chef in the Kitchen, Maryam Sayab</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/11/welcoming-a-new-chef-in-the-kitchen-maryam-sayab/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today we welcome a new Chef in the Kitchen, Maryam Sayab.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/11/welcoming-a-new-chef-in-the-kitchen-maryam-sayab/">Welcoming a New Chef in the Kitchen, Maryam Sayab</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60957</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Deprecating co-access: Crossref plans and timelines</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/deprecating-co-access-crossref-plans-and-timelines/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>TL;DR</p>
        <p>To date, there are about 100 Crossref members who have made use of our co-access service for one or more of their books. The service was designed to be a last-resort measure when multiple parties - book publishers, aggregators, and other members - had rights to register book content. Unfortunately, the service allowed members to register multiple DOIs for shared books and book chapters, thereby violating our own core tenet of one DOI per content item. We should not have created a service that violated that tenet, resulting in duplicate DOIs. As we are able to offer an alternative in the form of the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/register-maintain-records/creating-and-managing-dois/multiple-resolution/">multiple resolution service</a>, it is time to switch co-access off. Among other benefits – for the publisher and the authors, creation of a single DOI for each item, regardless of where it might be hosted, will result in more accurate citation counts and usage statistics. We’re retiring co-access at the end of 2026.</p>
        <h3 id="an-idiom-to-start">An idiom to start</h3>
        <p>There&rsquo;s an idiom used in technology circles called &lsquo;<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eating_your_own_dog_food" target="_blank">eating your own dog food</a>.&rsquo; It&rsquo;s used to describe an organization that tests or uses its own products in the real world. I&rsquo;m no developer and only have a handful of years of exposure to this phrase, but I&rsquo;ve always wanted to work it into one of my blog posts. The visceral reactions I have observed when it&rsquo;s been used on internal calls are just too tempting. That, and I think it applies to our own rollout of and missteps with a service we call co-access. The decision to enable co-access reflected the priorities of that period, but we can now improve on it with an upgraded multiple resolution service. That rickety footing for co-access doomed it from the start. Now&rsquo;s the time to face the music and swallow our own kibble.</p>
        <p>Always meant as a last-resort measure, co-access allows multiple Crossref members to register metadata for shared book and book chapter content. Thus, use of co-access results in multiple, duplicate DOIs registered for the same book content. There are well over 500,000 DOIs in co-access within our corpus today. At least half of those are duplicates (more on this below).</p>
        <p>This is far from ideal and has adverse consequences for the integrity of the scholarly record and the community. As we are able to offer an alternative in the form of the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/register-maintain-records/creating-and-managing-dois/multiple-resolution/">multiple resolution service</a>, it is time to switch co-access off.</p>
        <p>Among other benefits &ndash; for the publisher and the authors, creation of a single DOI for each item, regardless of where it might be hosted, will result in more accurate citation counts and usage statistics.</p>
        <h3 id="duplicate-dois">Duplicate DOIs</h3>
        <p>We frequently receive questions from members, metadata users, and others in the community, like <a href="https://community.crossref.org/t/duplicate-dois-keep-being-minted/3554" target="_blank">this one</a>, asking us what we are doing to combat the very real problem of registration and propagation of duplicate DOIs. We do <a href="https://community.crossref.org/t/the-problem-with-duplicate-dois-and-how-you-can-help/2634" target="_blank">take measures</a> to prevent the registration of duplicate DOIs, including flagging registration of potential duplicate records to our members using what we call conflicts and <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/reports/conflict-report/">conflict reports</a>. As you might expect, this has been a sensitive topic for us, because we have one glaring service, yes, co-access, that has been actively exacerbating the issue of duplicate DOIs.</p>
        <p>So, while we have been actively trying to counter the rise of duplicate DOIs, co-access enabled duplicate registrations of book DOIs. For every prefix that we configured for the service, we knew we were contributing to the problem (<a href="https://doi.org/10.21428/785a6451.fb6181fd" target="_blank">our members noticed too</a>. As I said above, co-access allows multiple members to register their own DOI for shared book content. That means that book content in co-access has at least two DOIs registered. In some cases, there is book content with five or more registered DOIs for a single book. That&rsquo;s a great many duplicates that this service is responsible for.</p>
        <h3 id="replacing-co-access">Replacing co-access </h3>
        <p>We plan to replace co-access with an existing tool, multiple resolution, which allows for more than one resolution URL to be registered to a single DOI. A user resolving the DOI is presented with an <a href="https://doi.org/10.54675/cklg5881" target="_blank">interim page</a>, allowing them to choose from the various content sources registered with this DOI. We&rsquo;ve made some <a href="https://community.crossref.org/t/upcoming-changes-to-multiple-resolution-and-co-access-templates/3908" target="_blank">progress</a> toward making multiple resolution simpler for members to implement, but we still have more to do.</p>
        <div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/multiple-resolution-ui.png"
        alt="Screenshot of multiple resolution UI" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        <p>We&rsquo;re aware that the technical steps involved in adopting multiple resolution might present a barrier to implementation for some of our members. To help with the transition, we are working on a basic tool (currently in beta) that simplifies the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/register-maintain-records/creating-and-managing-dois/multiple-resolution/#00118">process</a>. We will make it available to members between now and the middle of 2026.</p>
        <h3 id="our-timeline">Our timeline</h3>
        <p>We are not going to make these changes tomorrow. We&rsquo;re going to give members who have been using co-access time to adjust. Right now, we trigger co-access when a secondary DOI is registered by a secondary registrant (member) that: 1) is already in a co-access group within our system with the DOI prefix that registered the original DOI, 2) has at least one shared ISBN with the metadata of that original DOI, and 3) has a title (in the title element of the book or chapter XML) that exactly matches the title of the original DOI. We&rsquo;re going to stop triggering co-access for book and book chapter registrations <strong>starting 2026 July 1</strong>. No new DOIs will be placed in co-access starting then.</p>
        <p>From there, there will be six months to clean up records already in co-access. One definitive DOI should be selected by the parties in a co-access group; the DOIs that will no longer be maintained for those books and book chapters should be aliased to the primary (definitive) DOI that will be maintained going forward. The primary DOI should be the DOI used on all landing pages for that book (or, book chapter).</p>
        <p>In January 2027, if co-access DOIs have not been aliased to one another, we will force alias the DOIs in the record to the DOI registered by the organization identified as the publisher in the metadata records already in our system. At any point in this timeline, our team will be happy to help with the registration of secondary URLs in order to move books from co-access to multiple resolution. As a result, we will encourage members, end users, and the broader community to move back to using a single, definitive source of truth for these books and book chapters.</p>
        <h3 id="what-will-registration-of-books-and-book-chapters-look-like-post-co-access">What will registration of books and book chapters look like post-co-access?</h3>
        <p>Coordinated. We expect that our members and their publishing partners will define the single DOI for each book and book chapter well upstream of Crossref, so all entities and their systems will use that one definitive DOI.</p>
        <p>As for the registration process and our system, the first member to register the book (and its ISBNs) will establish the DOI for that book and its chapters. Following attempts to register the same content, with a duplicate book-level DOI(s), will fail the registration. Multiple DOIs for the same book or book chapter should be avoided starting <strong>2026 July 01</strong>, as we will no longer be able to place books and book chapters into co-access.</p>
        <p>We believe this will result in increased cited-by and usage metrics for that single DOI, and a cleaner, more accurate scholarly record.</p>
        <p>We&rsquo;d love to hear your reaction to this news in our <a href="https://community.crossref.org/tag/blog" target="_blank">Community Forum</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/deprecating-co-access-crossref-plans-and-timelines/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>preLights: biology preprint server reviewed by young researchers from around the world</title>
      <link>https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/09/10/prelights-biology-preprint-server/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Preprints have been gaining attention and interest from the scientific community as a means to quickly disseminate research results, ensure recognition for discoveries, and, above all, receive feedback before submitting manuscripts to scientific journals. In 2018, the publisher The Company of Biologists established a biological sciences preprint platform called preLights, formed by young researchers to evaluate preprints and post comments online, which function as post-publication peer review. <span class="ellipsis">&#8230;</span> <span class="more-link-wrap"><a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/09/10/prelights-biology-preprint-server/" class="more-link"><span>Read More &#8594;</span></a></span></p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/09/10/prelights-biology-preprint-server/">preLights: biology preprint server reviewed by young researchers from around the world</a> first appeared on <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en">SciELO in Perspective</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.scielo.org/en/?p=5661</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>What the Proposed Federal Data Collection Changes Mean for IPEDS</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/what-the-proposed-federal-data-collection-changes-mean-for-ipeds/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>On August 15, 2025, the US Department of Education published a notice in the Federal Register announcing proposed revisions to the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System (IPEDS). The proposed changes would expand data collection to include new items on college admissions and applicants, such as standardized test scores, family income, information on students who apply [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/what-the-proposed-federal-data-collection-changes-mean-for-ipeds/">What the Proposed Federal Data Collection Changes Mean for IPEDS</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323554</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>CARTA: A Collective Approach to the Preservation of Online Art Resources</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/09/10/carta/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Art historians, critics, curators, and humanities scholars rely on the records of artists, galleries, museums, and arts organizations to understand and contextualize contemporary artistic practice. Yet, much of the art-related [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29272</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post – Where Do We All Fit In? Reflections on Belonging, Purpose, and Progress in Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/10/guest-post-where-do-we-all-fit-in-reflections-on-belonging-purpose-and-progress-in-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest post by Deja Forte declares: Publishing isn’t just about systems and standards; it’s about people. Each of us has the power to build bridges between knowledge and the lives it’s meant to benefit.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/10/guest-post-where-do-we-all-fit-in-reflections-on-belonging-purpose-and-progress-in-scholarly-publishing/">Guest Post – Where Do We All Fit In? Reflections on Belonging, Purpose, and Progress in Scholarly Publishing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60943</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Purposeful Cross-Sector Collaboration Boosts Learning Mobility and Student Success</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/purposeful-cross-sector-collaboration-boosts-learning-mobility-and-student-success/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>As the “normal” higher education experience continues to evolve, to better serve students colleges and universities must not only work closely together across systems and regions, but they must also collaborate with K-12, employer, and community partners. These essential collaborations, when effective, can result in an interconnected ecosystem of learning opportunities that seamlessly connect students [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/purposeful-cross-sector-collaboration-boosts-learning-mobility-and-student-success/">Purposeful Cross-Sector Collaboration Boosts Learning Mobility and Student Success</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323516</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post – ODI Survey on AI and Web-Scale Discovery</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/09/guest-post-odi-survey-on-ai-and-web-scale-discovery/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>NISO's Open Discovery Initiative (ODI) survey reflects the positive and negative expectations of generative AI in web-scale discovery tools.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/09/guest-post-odi-survey-on-ai-and-web-scale-discovery/">Guest Post – ODI Survey on AI and Web-Scale Discovery</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60930</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>HighWire Press&#39;s DigiCorePro and ROR</title>
      <link>https://ror.org/blog/2025-09-09-digicorepro/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In this interview with HighWire Press&#39;s Tony Alves, we learn that thanks to customer requests and a PID-aware development process, the publishing platform DigiCore Pro uses ROR in form lookups and automatic extraction processes for author affiliations, funder identification, peer reviewer affiliations, user disambiguation, and research integrity.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://doi.org/10.71938/97e0-5q39</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Celebrating one year of Crossref Grant IDs at NWO</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/celebrating-one-year-of-crossref-grant-ids-at-nwo/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This month marks one year since the Dutch Research Council (NWO) introduced grant IDs—an important milestone in our journey toward more transparent and trackable research funding. We created over <a href="https://api.crossref.org/members/47652/works?" target="_blank">1,600 Crossref Grant IDs</a> with associated metadata. We are beginning to see them appear in publications. These early examples show the enormous potential Grant IDs have. They also highlight that publishers could extend their efforts to improve the quality of funding metadata of publications.</p>
        <h2 id="the-promise-of-grant-linking">The promise of grant linking</h2>
        <p>For decades, funders have struggled with a seemingly simple challenge: tracking the research outputs that arise from their funding. The traditional approach—requiring grantees to cite their grants in acknowledgement sections of their papers—has all kinds of problems. Authors make many errors in providing this information, and even when funding organizations and schemes are cited correctly, there is no guarantee that a grant number is globally unique and not already in use by another funding council in the world.</p>
        <p>To address these issues, and in collaboration with the research funding community, Crossref introduced the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/" target="_blank">Grant Linking System (GLS)</a> six years ago. The system allows funding organizations to assign globally unique and persistent identifiers to their grants, but - more importantly - the system allows connecting these grants with the outputs arising from them. The vision is straightforward: authors include Grant IDs (which are Crossref DOIs) in the funding acknowledgements of their research articles. Publishers either take these IDs from the acknowledgement or proactively ask authors for these IDs in their submission system. Next, when a publisher registers their publication with Crossref, it includes the grant identifier in the metadata of that publication, creating an unambiguous link between the publication and the grants from which the research was funded.</p>
        <p>This last step—including the Grant ID in the metadata of the article when registering the publication with Crossref—is a crucial part of the system as it enables anyone to automatically retrieve all publications arising from a given grant over time via the Crossref API. Funding organizations interested in tracking the impact of their funding could then stop asking their grantees to manually report on the outputs of their funding, as most still do today. Instead, this information would become open data that funding organizations harvest directly themselves, reducing administrative burden on researchers while enhancing the ability to track the impact of their funding.</p>
        <p>As <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/xqr28-ee750" target="_blank">Robert Kiley</a>, former head of Open Research at the Wellcome Trust, which piloted the GLS in 2018, put it: &ldquo;&hellip;if every funder were to adopt such a system and expose their grant metadata in a consistent, machine-readable way, it would facilitate the development of applications to help funders get a greatly enhanced picture of the global funding landscape, which in turn would inform strategic planning and resource allocation.&rdquo;</p>
        <h2 id="nwos-implementation-journey">NWO&rsquo;s implementation journey</h2>
        <p>NWO joined Crossref&rsquo;s Grant Linking System in 2024. It reflects our broader commitment to open science and aligns with our <a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.4674512" target="_blank">Persistent Identifier Strategy</a> published in 2021, and our support for the <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/" target="_blank">Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information</a>. Since August 2024, all new grants awarded from July 2024 onward receive a Crossref Grant ID that persistently resolves to the information about the grant on our website, displaying all basic award information including project titles, summaries, grantee names, and affiliations. NWO is <a href="https://api.crossref.org/types/grant/works?facet=publisher-name:*&amp;rows=0" target="_blank">one of the 44 funding organizations</a> worldwide that have introduced Crossref Grant IDs for their collective <a href="https://api.crossref.org/types/grant/works?facet=funder-name:*&amp;rows=0" target="_blank">111 funding programs</a>. Other organizations include the European Commission, OSTI-DOE, the Wellcome Trust, Moore Foundation, Fonds de Recherche du Québec, CSIRO, Japan Science and Technology Agency, and the <a href="https://www.fwf.ac.at/en/news/detail/neue-identifikations-nummer-fuer-fwf-projekte" target="_blank">Austrian Science Fund</a>.</p>
        <p>Although it took time, implementation at NWO in general proceeded smoothly. Over the course of a year, we&rsquo;ve registered <a href="https://api.crossref.org/members/47652/works?" target="_blank">over 1,500 grant records</a> without experiencing difficulties or complaints from researchers. On the contrary, after we announced the introduction of Grant IDs, some researchers expressed disappointment on our decision—for practical reasons—to only register DOIs for new grants instead of the entire historical record. This shows that researchers understand the importance of persistent identifiers. Already, a year after its introduction, we are seeing the first NWO Grant IDs appearing in publications— showing that researchers are taking the extra step to look up their Crossref Grant ID and include it in their articles, <a href="https://www.nwo.nl/en/acknowledgement-in-publications" target="_blank">as we are asking them to do</a>.
        However, publishers don’t always manage to handle these identifiers in the way we expect them to.</p>
        <h2 id="linking-grants-to-publications-in-real-life">Linking grants to publications in real life</h2>
        <p>One of the first publications to include an NWO Grant ID is a paper by <a href="https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevX.15.021080" target="_blank">Weile et al.</a>, published by the American Physical Society (APS) in the journal Physical Review X. On the left, we see the funding information provided by the authors, as included in the acknowledgement section of the published article. Funding by NWO from its Talent Scheme VIDI is identified with a Grant ID <a href="https://doi.org/10.61686/YDRHT18202" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.61686/YDRHT18202</a>.</p>
        <div class='shortcode-row '>
        <div class="col-md-6 col-sm-12 no-first-para-highlight"><div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/jk.png" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6 col-sm-12 no-first-para-highlight"><div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/18202.png" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>On the right, we see how APS has included this information <a href="https://api.crossref.org/works/https://www.doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevX.15.021080" target="_blank">in the metadata</a> of the publication: NWO is identified with its Funder ID and the grant with the Grant ID - forging an unambiguous link between funding and publication, initially between this particular grant and this particular publication, but potentially in the future between this grant and all other outputs arising from it. This works so long as all publishers include this information in the metadata of their publications; we need to encourage more publishers and other Crossref members (e.g., preprint services, repositories, blog platforms) to follow the APS example and do the same.</p>
        <h2 id="where-publishers-fall-short">Where publishers fall short</h2>
        <p>There are big differences among publishers in their ability to include funding metadata. Many have been including funder IDs in the metadata for more than a decade, but some are still struggling to do that. Most are yet to catch up to start including Crossref Grant IDs, too.</p>
        <p>Let’s demonstrate that in an example. On the left, we see the acknowledgements section of a paper by <a href="https://www.doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502496" target="_blank">Van Zundert et al</a>. in the journal Small, published by Wiley. The authors acknowledge a host of funding organizations and grants, including NWO with Grant ID <a href="https://doi.org/10.61686/LVZRW92421" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.61686/LVZRW92421</a>. On the right, we see that the publisher has correctly included NWO <a href="https://api.crossref.org/works/https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202502496" target="_blank">in the metadata</a> as the funder with our Funder ID, but there’s no reference to our Grant ID, instead mentioning an award number, which seems to refer to a Marie Sklodowska-Curie grant for the same research with their internal award identifier.</p>
        <div class='shortcode-row '>
        <div class="col-md-6 col-sm-12 no-first-para-highlight"><div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/ivz.png" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6 col-sm-12 no-first-para-highlight"><div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/api-code-blog.png" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>Likewise, a publication by <a href="https://www.doi.org/10.1016/j.plrev.2025.07.003" target="_blank">Criscuolo et al</a> in Physics of Life Reviews (a journal published by Elsevier) correctly identified NWO using our Funder ID, but omitted our Grant ID <a href="https://api.crossref.org/works/https://www.doi.org/10.1016/j.plrev.2025.07.003" target="_blank">in the metadata</a>, despite its clear inclusion by the author in the acknowledgements (left). Apparently, this persistent link and open metadata is being thrown out of the infrastructure at a crucial time, when the article record could be connecting up with the grant record and making it easy and open for us all to track and report on the connection.</p>
        <div class='shortcode-row '>
        <div class="col-md-6 col-sm-12 no-first-para-highlight"><div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/acknowledgement-blog-2.png" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        </div>
        <div class="col-md-6 col-sm-12 no-first-para-highlight"><div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/api-funder.png" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>Several publishers do not seem to register funding data at all, despite the opportunity existing for almost 15 years, and sometimes even when comprehensive funding information is provided by authors.</p>
        <h2 id="the-broader-implications">The broader implications</h2>
        <p>It has <a href="https://doi.org/10.1162/qss_a_00210" target="_blank">been known for some time</a> that publishers struggle with registering complete, high-quality funding metadata for their publications. They sometimes <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/3f63f-yt393" target="_blank">blame authors</a> for not providing the required information or making errors in reporting their funding. Or they call on funders to identify their funding more precisely by introducing persistent Grant IDs for their grants. While these are legitimate issues, and it’s true that more funders could also do this, the examples presented here suggest this narrative is incomplete—when authors provide clear, standardized funding information using persistent identifiers, many publishers still fail to capture it accurately.</p>
        <p>The Grant Linking System is still relatively new in terms of open infrastructure and open metadata development, and adoption from funders is still in the tens rather than the tens of thousands, with publishers being more accustomed to creating and providing millions of open metadata records for their publications. Most participating funders, like us, have only started registering grants in the past couple of years. Now that Crossref Grant IDs are becoming more widespread, and with publishers’ experience in creating open metadata, we would love to see publishers prioritise collecting and including Grant IDs in their Crossref metadata. By updating their production practices, they would be supporting the community at large in reaping the benefits of open grant metadata.</p>
        <p>To address these challenges, we are organizing <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/working_groups/" target="_blank">a roundtable session under the Barcelona Declaration</a> in October to discuss concrete solutions for these issues. We invite publishers who are interested in participating <a href="mailto:contact@barcelona-declaration.org">to contact us</a>. This follows a <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/3f63f-yt393" target="_blank">2023 workshop</a> where many publishers were very open in discussing the challenges and working towards improving the process together with funders.</p>
        <h2 id="looking-ahead">Looking ahead</h2>
        <p>The introduction of Crossref Grant IDs represents just the first step in a longer journey toward more open research information for NWO. We are happy to see how quickly researchers are adopting the system by including Crossref Grant IDs in their work. For Grant IDs to truly become a Grant Linking System and fulfil its promise, however, publishers must act on the need to collect and process funding information in their publishing workflows, just as they do for other joint efforts, such as for ORCID iDs for contributors. The information is there—authors are providing it in the acknowledgement sections of their articles (and probably would too if asked directly in a submission form). The question now is: can we encourage more publishers to take up the request to capture and transmit this information accurately and register it with Crossref?</p>
        <p>We’re hopeful. This first year has demonstrated the enormous potential of Crossref Grant IDs in action for NWO. We call on publishers to do their bit in ensuring this vital infrastructure reaches its full potential for the research community.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/celebrating-one-year-of-crossref-grant-ids-at-nwo/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Day in Review (September 8–11)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-september-08-11/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 11, 2025, 2:28 pm ET Sign up to receive the Day in Review by email. Jump to: Tuesday, September 9 &#124; Wednesday, September 10 &#124; Thursday,...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-september-08-11/">Day in Review (September 8–11)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=45902</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Sustaining Open Source Software in the Research Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/sustaining-open-source-software-in-the-research-enterprise-workshop/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>On August 8, 2025, we convened 40 people representing a wide range of perspectives to discuss strategies for sustaining open source software (OSS) that is used for research. Sustainability is a major challenge for even the most successful open source software, which requires ongoing community engagement to improve and maintain code. Sustainability also includes identifying [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/sustaining-open-source-software-in-the-research-enterprise-workshop/">Sustaining Open Source Software in the Research Enterprise</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323518</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Revisited: On Being a Leader Who Happens to Be a Woman of Color</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/08/revisited-on-being-a-leader-who-happens-to-be-a-woman-of-color/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>During the first Trump administration, Alice Meadows interviewed three women of color who are leaders in their fields about their experiences. In this post, they revisit the topic in the light of their new positions and today's political environment.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/08/revisited-on-being-a-leader-who-happens-to-be-a-woman-of-color/">Revisited: On Being a Leader Who Happens to Be a Woman of Color </a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60934</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Magic Mountain, by Thomas Mann</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/thomas-mann/the-magic-mountain/h-t-lowe-porter</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young man visits his cousin in a sanitarium in the mountains, only to see himself become one of its patients.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/thomas-mann/the-magic-mountain/h-t-lowe-porter/downloads/thomas-mann_the-magic-mountain_h-t-lowe-porter.epub?source=feed" length="1393005" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/thomas-mann/the-magic-mountain/h-t-lowe-porter</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The End of the Tether, by Joseph Conrad</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/joseph-conrad/the-end-of-the-tether</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An aging captain, having made a name for himself in the age of sail, is forced by circumstance to do a final run on a steamer.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/joseph-conrad/the-end-of-the-tether/downloads/joseph-conrad_the-end-of-the-tether.epub?source=feed" length="459985" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/joseph-conrad/the-end-of-the-tether</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Demian, by Hermann Hesse</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/hermann-hesse/demian/n-h-priday</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A boy goes on a journey of spiritual growth.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/hermann-hesse/demian/n-h-priday/downloads/hermann-hesse_demian_n-h-priday.epub?source=feed" length="683948" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/hermann-hesse/demian/n-h-priday</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Wild Animals I Have Known, by Ernest Thompson Seton</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ernest-thompson-seton/wild-animals-i-have-known</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Eight short stories about the lives of various animals across several regions of North America.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ernest-thompson-seton/wild-animals-i-have-known/downloads/ernest-thompson-seton_wild-animals-i-have-known.epub?source=feed" length="801366" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ernest-thompson-seton/wild-animals-i-have-known</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Summer Library Conferences and Serving the Justice Impacted</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/reflections-on-summer-library-conferences-and-serving-the-justice-impacted/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This summer I attended and presented at two library conferences, the annual American Library Association (ALA) and the annual American Association of Law Librarians meetings. I participated in four panel discussions that focused on how libraries can better serve people inside and outside of prison. If you weren’t able to attend, I have provided some [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/reflections-on-summer-library-conferences-and-serving-the-justice-impacted/">Reflections on Summer Library Conferences and Serving the Justice Impacted</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323511</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Transparency in Research Reporting: An Evolving Culture</title>
      <link>https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/09/04/transparency-in-research-reporting-an-evolving-culture/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>More than two decades ago, Richard Horton, editor of <em>The Lancet</em>, raised thought-provoking questions about scientific authorship and its representation in published articles. He noted that research reports often overlook disagreements among co-authors over the interpretation of results. Bringing to light elements of this so-called "hidden paper" has become essential for the reliability of scientific reporting. This is an evolving process likely to gain even greater relevance in graduate education, especially in the current context of intellectual production increasingly permeated by Generative Artificial Intelligence. <span class="ellipsis">&#8230;</span> <span class="more-link-wrap"><a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/09/04/transparency-in-research-reporting-an-evolving-culture/" class="more-link"><span>Read More &#8594;</span></a></span></p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/09/04/transparency-in-research-reporting-an-evolving-culture/">Transparency in Research Reporting: An Evolving Culture</a> first appeared on <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en">SciELO in Perspective</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.scielo.org/en/?p=5656</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>DWeb Camp Cascadia 2025: Canada’s First Regional Decentralized Web Camp in the Pacific Northwest</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/09/03/dweb-camp-cascadia-2025-canadas-first-regional-decentralized-web-camp-in-the-pacific-northwest/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[We’re thrilled to see how much our hope for DWeb to decentralize globally has been fulfilled this year. In our blog announcing the Core team’s decision to take a hiatus [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29220</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Integrating AI Literacy into the Curricula</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/integrating-ai-literacy-into-the-curricula-september-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In September 2025, we are convening a new Integrating AI Literacy into the Curricula cohort to help colleges and universities move from ad hoc experimentation to sustainable, curriculum-integrated practice. Building on the momentum of our spring activities with 45 participating institutions, we will apply the same cross-campus approach that centers collaboration between libraries and educators, [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/integrating-ai-literacy-into-the-curricula-september-2025/">Integrating AI Literacy into the Curricula</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323499</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>August 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/our-priorities/advocacy-public-policy/public-policy-briefing/august-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 3, 2025, 9:44 am ET Subscribe to the Public Policy Briefing ARL Public Policy Briefing (August 2025) This issue includes: Copyright and Fair Use/Fair Dealing Library...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/our-priorities/advocacy-public-policy/public-policy-briefing/august-2025/">August 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=45847</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Local Voices, Lasting Impact: Digitizing a Community Magazine in Hancock County, Mississippi</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/09/03/local-voices-lasting-impact-digitizing-a-community-magazine-in-hancock-county-mississippi/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The following guest post from Ash Parker, Collections &#38; Digital Services Librarian at the Hancock County Library System in Mississippi, is part of a series written by members of Internet [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29162</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Adjacent Possible in the Decentralized Web</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/09/03/the-adjacent-possible-in-the-decentralized-web/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[As I understand it, the concept of the “adjacent possible” describes changes just within reach given the current state of a system’s knowledge, resources, and components. It’s a “shadow future” [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29209</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Poetry, by Matthew Arnold</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/matthew-arnold/poetry</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of occasional and dramatic poems by a Victorian poet, educator, and critic.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/matthew-arnold/poetry/downloads/matthew-arnold_poetry.epub?source=feed" length="835206" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/matthew-arnold/poetry</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Day in Review (September 2–4)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-august-29-september-1-5/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 4, 2025, 1:52 pm ET Sign up to receive the Day in Review by email. Jump to: Wednesday, September 3 &#124; Thursday, September 4 Tuesday, September...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-august-29-september-1-5/">Day in Review (September 2–4)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=45829</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Looking back on “Preserving the Internet” from 1996</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/09/02/looking-back-on-preserving-the-internet-from-1996/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[As the Internet Archive celebrates 1 trillion web pages archived, it’s worth revisiting what founder Brewster Kahle imagined back in 1996—when the web was still young and the Wayback Machine [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29207</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How States and Institutions Are Using PSEO to Show College Graduate Employment Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/how-states-are-using-pseo-to-show-college-graduate-employment-outcomes/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Higher education leaders have long struggled to answer two deceptively simple questions: “where do our graduates work?” and “what are they earning?” Response rates to surveys that historically collect this information are declining, individual state data systems typically do not track graduates across state lines, and commercial datasets with these data are opaque and costly. [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/how-states-are-using-pseo-to-show-college-graduate-employment-outcomes/">How States and Institutions Are Using PSEO to Show College Graduate Employment Outcomes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323495</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Road to Oz, by L. Frank Baum</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/l-frank-baum/the-road-to-oz</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young girl takes a passerby down the road near her farm when they find themselves transported to another land.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/l-frank-baum/the-road-to-oz/downloads/l-frank-baum_the-road-to-oz.epub?source=feed" length="1159795" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/l-frank-baum/the-road-to-oz</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Fit in research data management</title>
      <link>https://rc-blog.ethz.ch/en/fit-in-research-data-management/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Get yourself and your research project in shape with our research data management workshop programme. You can now register for the Autumn Semester 2025 workshops. Read more]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://rc-blog.ethz.ch/?p=2884</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Women, by Zofia Nałkowska</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/zofia-nalkowska/women/michael-henry-dziewicki</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A Polish woman aims to find love in a society of shifting moral norms.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/zofia-nalkowska/women/michael-henry-dziewicki/downloads/zofia-nalkowska_women_michael-henry-dziewicki.epub?source=feed" length="496584" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/zofia-nalkowska/women/michael-henry-dziewicki</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>From India to the World: A Scholar’s Tribute to the Internet Archive</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/08/29/from-india-to-the-world-a-scholars-tribute-to-the-internet-archive/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Every day, people around the world use the Internet Archive to learn, research, and discover. Aadarsh Pathak, a scholar in India, called the Internet Archive “a guardian of our collective [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29181</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The New Freedom, by Woodrow Wilson</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/woodrow-wilson/the-new-freedom</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The 28th president of the United States presents the risks and opportunities for freedom and democracy through a series of campaign speeches.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/woodrow-wilson/the-new-freedom/downloads/woodrow-wilson_the-new-freedom.epub?source=feed" length="422895" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/woodrow-wilson/the-new-freedom</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Celebrando Cultura 2025: Spotlight on the Latinx/é Diaspora.</title>
      <link>https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/2025/08/29/celebrando-cultura-2025-spotlight-on-the-latinx-e-diaspora/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="200" src="https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2025/08/Untitled-design2-300x200.png" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" srcset="https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2025/08/Untitled-design2-300x200.png 300w, https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2025/08/Untitled-design2-768x512.png 768w, https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2025/08/Untitled-design2.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>Each year, from September 15 to October 15, we observe Latinx/é Heritage Heritage Month, a time to recognize and celebrate the contributions of Latinx/é Americans.&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/?p=7406</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Kitchen is Closed for US Labor Day</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/08/29/kitchen-is-closed-for-us-labor-day/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The Chefs are now off for the US Labor Day Holiday, enjoying the last official getaway for summer.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/08/29/kitchen-is-closed-for-us-labor-day/">Kitchen is Closed for US Labor Day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60897</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ETH Library and ICSTI invite you to the 2025 Annual Conference</title>
      <link>https://rc-blog.ethz.ch/en/eth-library-and-icsti-invite-you-to-the-2025-annual-conference/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Together with the International Council for Scientific and Technical Information (ICSTI), the ETH Library is hosting this year&#8217;s ICSTI Annual Conference at ETH Zurich on September 18 and 19, 2025.  Read more]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://rc-blog.ethz.ch/?p=2880</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post – Code Plagiarism and AI Create New Challenges for Publishing Integrity</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/08/28/guest-post-code-plagiarism-and-ai-create-new-challenges-for-publishing-integrity/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>This post explores author, reviewer, and publisher ethics and responsibilities related to the use of AI in coding and publishing research software.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/08/28/guest-post-code-plagiarism-and-ai-create-new-challenges-for-publishing-integrity/">Guest Post – Code Plagiarism and AI Create New Challenges for Publishing Integrity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60920</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>An eLife filled with possibility thanks to great metadata</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/an-elife-filled-with-possibility-thanks-to-great-metadata/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="https://elifesciences.org/" target="_blank">eLife</a> recently <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/xh94q-w7335" target="_blank">won a Crossref Metadata Award</a> for the completeness of its metadata, showing itself as the clear leader among our medium-sized members. In this post, the eLife team answers our questions about how and why they produce such high-quality open metadata. For eLife, the work of creating and sharing excellent metadata aligns with their mission to foster open science and supports their preprint-centred publication model, but it also lays the groundwork for all kinds of exciting potential uses.</p>
        <div class="quotecite">
        <blockquote>
        <p>Having complete and rich metadata puts you in the best position to fulfil future, as-yet-undetermined requirements.</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p><cite>&ndash; Fred Atherden, eLife</cite></p>
        </div>
        <h2 id="what-motivates-your-organisationteam-to-work-towards-high-quality-metadata-what-objectives-does-it-support-for-your-organisation">What motivates your organisation/team to work towards high-quality metadata? What objectives does it support for your organisation?</h2>
        <p>eLife is a mission-driven organisation tasked by its founders to help scientists accelerate discovery and encourage responsible behaviours in science. As such, we’re passionate about open science and metadata, and we&rsquo;re vocal advocates of the benefits these provide to academic communities and beyond.</p>
        <p>Given Crossref’s position as a hub at the centre of scholarly communication, providing Crossref with complete metadata furthers our mission. It facilitates the discovery and reuse of research and enables linkage to key but often overlooked outputs such as datasets and software. As signatories of <a href="https://sfdora.org/" target="_blank">DORA</a> and supporters of the <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/" target="_blank">Barcelona Declaration</a>, we are keenly aware of the wider context - that these efforts enable research assessment and policy decisions to be derived from open and transparent information, moving beyond closed systems that have proliferated the damaging use of anachronistic metrics.</p>
        <h2 id="do-you-have-a-strategy-for-complete-metadata-which-elements-did-you-prioritise-what-workflows-tools-or-collaborations-helped-you-get-there">Do you have a strategy for complete metadata? Which elements did you prioritise? What workflows, tools, or collaborations helped you get there?</h2>
        <p>There are plenty of existing guidelines that provide a great skeleton to follow. For example, we follow <a href="https://www.go-fair.org/fair-principles/" target="_blank">FAIR data</a> and <a href="https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj-cs.86" target="_blank">FORCE11 software citation principles</a>, which ensure the capture of metadata for supporting datasets and software packages. There’s not any one particular element that we’ve prioritised, although we’re keen to ensure we follow best practices while also exploring the bleeding edge.</p>
        <p>We’ve collaborated with and relied on the advice of many organisations over the years, including (but not limited to) Crossref, Research Organization Registry <a href="https://ror.org" target="_blank">(ROR)</a>, <a href="https://jats4r.niso.org/" target="_blank">JATS4R</a>, <a href="https://force11.org" target="_blank">FORCE11</a>, <a href="https://www.softwareheritage.org/" target="_blank">Software Heritage</a>, <a href="https://openrxiv.org/" target="_blank">openRxiv</a>, and our production vendors <a href="https://www.kriyadocs.com/exeterpremedia" target="_blank">Exeter Premedia</a>.</p>
        <p>We’ve developed our own <a href="https://github.com/elifesciences/elife-crossref-xml-generation" target="_blank">open source Crossref metadata generation library</a>. Keeping this process in-house has proven really fruitful. It allows us to quickly and continuously improve upon the metadata we provide.</p>
        <p>And we have a data team that has created a centralised data hub, serving as a really useful authoritative resource that can be queried, instead of always making use of disparate systems.</p>
        <h2 id="how-have-you-integrated-these-into-your-metadata-processes">How have you integrated these into your metadata processes?</h2>
        <p>At submission, we collect ROR IDs for (a subset of) affiliations, and structured data for funding, datasets, and other information. Our publication model is centred around preprints, so it’s necessary to capture related information such as the preprint DOI, preprint posted date, the version that pertains to each specific revision (and so on). Without this information, we could not post public reviews to the correct preprint version on the preprint server, or indeed ensure the article we publish is the correct iteration of that work.</p>
        <p>The systems that enable the publication of eLife Reviewed preprints are dependent on <a href="https://docmaps.knowledgefutures.org/" target="_blank">DocMaps</a>, a framework for a machine-readable representation of the processes involved in the creation of a document. These are provided by our Data Hub and enable us to capture structured information about the peer review process and accompanying metadata for each article.</p>
        <p>Our proofing system for journal articles only permits login via <a href="https://orcid.org" target="_blank">ORCID authentication</a>, and we don’t capture unauthenticated ORCID IDs that have been copied or keyed (see <a href="https://info.orcid.org/whats-so-special-about-signing-in/" target="_blank">‘What’s So Special About Signing In?’)</a>. It also makes use of both the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/retrieve-metadata/rest-api/">Crossref API</a> and the <a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/tools/developers/" target="_blank">PubMed Central API</a> to ensure we have persistent identifiers where possible for references. We have an in-house content validator, which uses <a href="https://ror.readme.io/docs/rest-api" target="_blank">ROR’s API</a> to ensure we have ROR IDs for affiliations and funders where possible. We use Software Heritage to archive author-generated code, and include their persistent ID <a href="https://www.softwareheritage.org/software-hash-identifier-swhid/" target="_blank">(SWHID)</a> in software references.</p>
        <p>All our published content is captured as <a href="https://jats.nlm.nih.gov/index.html" target="_blank">JATS XML</a> (the industry standard format for journal articles), which our metadata generation library uses as its input.</p>
        <h2 id="what-impact-of-good-metadata-can-you-see-for-your-organisation-is-it-supporting-the-business-andor-editorial-side-of-your-work">What impact of good metadata can you see for your organisation? Is it supporting the business and/or editorial side of your work?</h2>
        <p>Persistent identifiers are very useful for reporting. Creating a report that, for example, includes publication volumes from a particular institution is trivial when content is enriched with persistent identifiers. It’s more complex when all you have are messy author-supplied strings of text. They’re also useful for content validation. For example, when we have a persistent ID and a method to retrieve the related metadata, we can confirm that the information we’ve been provided is complete and correct.</p>
        <p>There are, of course, many other benefits, some of which are &ldquo;unknown unknowns.&rdquo; Having complete and rich metadata puts you in the best position to fulfil future, as-yet-undetermined requirements.</p>
        <h2 id="have-you-encountered-any-challenges-in-curating-or-improving-your-metadata-if-so-what-were-they-and-how-did-you-address-those">Have you encountered any challenges in curating or improving your metadata? If so, what were they, and how did you address those?</h2>
        <p>In 2024, we started introducing <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/grants/">persistent grant IDs</a> for our content. While we updated our submission system to collect these from authors, it’s apparent that many authors aren’t aware when/if these have been registered by funders, and they still provide us with the (internal) grant numbers instead.</p>
        <p>Our workaround was to pull grant data from Crossref and then replace the grant numbers with the persistent IDs when we’re confident of a match. Since the grant number registered at Crossref might not exactly match the grant number the authors have given us, potential matches are confirmed by a team member or our production vendors. Since many organisations do a great job of creating informative landing pages (for example, <a href="https://europepmc.org/" target="_blank">EuropePMC</a> for Wellcome funding), this is feasible, but we’re investigating ways we can make this less manual while remaining careful that we don’t introduce false positives.</p>
        <h2 id="have-your-efforts-around-metadata-led-to-real-benefits-for-your-community-is-this-something-your-editors-authors-or-readers-are-aware-of-and-appreciate-if-so-why">Have your efforts around metadata led to real benefits for your community? Is this something your editors, authors, or readers are aware of and appreciate? If so, why?</h2>
        <p>Yes, I think this is something that is becoming increasingly visible. Authors are very mindful of the benefits that good metadata can bring for discoverability and promotion. And much is lost without the increased interoperability it brings, both for publishers themselves but also the wider ecosystem. For example, we’ve had some great feedback from numerous organisations that appreciate that the outputs we publish directly link to the preprints they are based on.</p>
        <p>In recent years, there’s been an increased focus on research integrity, and this is likely to remain the case. Metadata has an obvious and key role in providing trust and transparency, whether that’s through the presence of trust markers like ORCID IDs or through the inclusion of complete post-publication metadata such as correction, retraction, or withdrawal information.</p>
        <h2 id="looking-ahead-how-are-you-planning-to-build-on-your-metadata-quality-are-there-new-elements-or-practices-youre-exploring-and-what-advice-would-you-give-to-others-just-starting-to-strengthen-their-metadata">Looking ahead, how are you planning to build on your metadata quality? Are there new elements or practices you’re exploring? And what advice would you give to others just starting to strengthen their metadata?</h2>
        <p>Several years ago, <a href="https://elifesciences.org/about/peer-review" target="_blank">we introduced a &ldquo;publish, review, curate&rdquo; model of publishing</a>, where we publish ‘Reviewed preprints’ following each stage of review. We don’t collect the same level of structured information from authors at submission for these as we do for Versions of Record. This presents a challenge for retrieving and disseminating complete metadata for Reviewed preprints. We aim to start moving this forward so that comprehensive metadata is available at earlier stages of the publication process. For example, we recently started depositing (some) funding metadata for these.</p>
        <p>We’re also keen to explore the ways in which we can make our <a href="https://elifesciences.org/about/elife-assessments" target="_blank">eLife Assessments</a> more discoverable. Our Editors use a common vocabulary to describe the significance of the findings and strength of evidence in a paper. Other publishers moving beyond accept/reject publication models use different rubrics and taxonomies, so having one restrictive field in a schema for the entire corpus of research won’t cut it. But nevertheless making these terms more discoverable and interoperable would be preferential.</p>
        <p>We’ve found that the integration of public APIs/data within systems (such as ROR’s, Crossref’s, PubMed’s, and OpenAlex’s) to be really helpful in validating the correctness and completeness of content/metadata. The effort in adding these integrations will pay dividends in the future.</p>
        <p>Time to enjoy Fred’s acceptance video.</p>
        <div style="position: relative; width: 100%; height: 0; padding-top: 56.2500%;
        padding-bottom: 0; box-shadow: 0 2px 8px 0 rgba(63,69,81,0.16); margin-top: 1.6em; margin-bottom: 0.9em; overflow: hidden;
        border-radius: 8px; will-change: transform;">
        <iframe loading="lazy" style="position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%; top: 0; left: 0; border: none; padding: 0;margin: 0;"
        src="https://www.canva.com/design/DAGwnlQ6L28/02yxOhbLOdze9aVKwMwf5w/watch?embed" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" allow="fullscreen">
        </iframe>
        </div>
        <a href="https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.canva.com&#x2F;design&#x2F;DAGwnlQ6L28&#x2F;02yxOhbLOdze9aVKwMwf5w&#x2F;watch?utm_content=DAGwnlQ6L28&amp;utm_campaign=designshare&amp;utm_medium=embeds&amp;utm_source=link" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Metadata Awards video - eLife</a>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/an-elife-filled-with-possibility-thanks-to-great-metadata/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
