<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:source="https://source.scripting.com/">
  <atom:link href="https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Library and Archives organizations</title>
    <link>https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>08 Jan 26 08:13 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.18</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Takes on the First Quarter of 21st Century Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/08/hot-takes-on-first-quarter-century-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Todd Carpenter looks back on the past quarter century of a digital revolution in scholarly publishing.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/08/hot-takes-on-first-quarter-century-scholarly-publishing/">Hot Takes on the First Quarter of 21st Century Scholarly Publishing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Todd Carpenter looks back on the past quarter century of a digital revolution in scholarly publishing.

The post [Hot Takes on the First Quarter of 21st Century Scholarly Publishing](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/08/hot-takes-on-first-quarter-century-scholarly-publishing/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61403</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Grant DOI registration fees: a boost for the Research Nexus</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/reduction-of-grant-doi-registration-fees-a-boost-for-the-research-nexus/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that&mdash;effective 1st January 2026&mdash;we have made two changes to grant record registration fees that aim to accelerate adoption of Crossref&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/">Grant Linking System (GLS)</a> and provide a two-year window of opportunity to increase the number and availability of open persistent grant identifiers and boost the matching of relationships with research objects.</p>
        <div class="shortcode-divwrap align-right">
        <span><figure class="img-responsive"><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/community-images/gls/gls-benefits.png"
        alt="High-level benefits of the Crossref Grant Linking System (GLS)" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </span>
        </div>
        Launched in 2019 with close input from several funders and other infrastructure organisations, the GLS primarily offers the ability to create and steward Crossref Grant DOIs, along with several benefits such as dedicated grant/award metadata like funding type, value, contributors, and projects, as well as hosted landing pages, tools to create and update metadata, and of course both member-asserted and Crossref-automatic matching of relationships within the global corpus of 180 million other research objects. Essentially, we need to identify what research objects are produced as a result of the award, and these objects could be articles, preprints, data, code, blogs, posters, and more.
        <p>This connected network is what we call the Research Nexus, essential for exploring research activity in general, as well as evaluating reach and return on funding and other support like use of facilities/equipment.</p>
        <h3 id="a-fee-reduction-and-a-two-year-fee-waiver-pilot">A fee reduction and a two-year fee waiver pilot</h3>
        <p>Following a review by our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/committees/membership-and-fees/">Membership &amp; Fees Committee</a>, the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#board-members">Board</a> met in December and passed two related motions:</p>
        <ol>
        <li><strong>Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee has been cut in half to match other record types</strong>: The board approved the adjustment of the Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee down from $2.00 to $1.00 USD, effective 1st January 2026.</li>
        <li><strong>Back-Year (BY) grant registration fee is waived through 2027</strong>: The board approved a time-limited fee waiver as a pilot for Back-Year (BY) grant registration fees, bringing that per-record fee down from $0.30 to $0.00 for 2026 and 2027.</li>
        </ol>
        <p>We aim to boost registration of Back-Year (BY) records and accelerate the growth of the Research Nexus with millions more grant&lt;-&gt;output matches. During the course of the two-year pilot, the Membership &amp; Fees Committee and our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/">fee project work</a> that started in 2023 and also <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10" target="_blank">brought in other fee reductions</a>, will consider more adjustments across BY registration fees for the benefit of members beyond just funders and beyond just grants.</p>
        <p>All <a href="https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#motions">Board motions are publicly available</a> and we encourage questions from the community about our governance processes and the decisions on our members&rsquo; behalf; <a href="mailto:feedback@crossref.org">email us via feedback@crossref.org</a> anytime, or <a href="https://community.crossref.org/c/strategy/" target="_blank">post on the forum</a>.</p>
        <h3 id="supercharging-the-grant-linking-system">Supercharging the Grant Linking System</h3>
        <p>Leading up to the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/">GLS</a> launch in 2019, we worked with a group of funders and metadata experts to inform the design and implementation of the new service, including a funder governance and fees working group. That was seven years ago, and our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/working-groups/funders/">Funder Advisory Group</a> now includes nearly 100 funding community representatives the GLS has grown to almost 50 funder members that have registered more than 185,000 open grant metadata records. But they are mostly research councils and agencies or charities from Europe and North America, and we know that for a truly comprehensive and interconnected Research Nexus, more needs to be done to include organisations from all parts of the world. The other key driver is simply to boost more metadata connections; the more grant metadata we gather, the better we can match it to all kinds of research outputs, and <a href="">this metadata directly feeds thousands of services</a> available in our community, from Dimensions and Scopus, to OA.Report and OpenAlex, as well as funders&rsquo; own analytics tools. See our <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09" target="_blank">recent report about the latest dataset</a> and of course use <a href="htps://api.crossref.org">api.crossref.org</a> directly.</p>
        <p>Relatedly, we just added a <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/x7d4h-x3r11" target="_blank">new Grant DOI field</a> to our schema for all record types, to give our members a precise and accurate way of capturing funding metadata for all research outputs. With the new lower CY registration fee and a pilot waiver of BY fees for grant records, we hope to boost the creation of more Grant DOIs by more funders from more parts of the world&mdash;so that others also see and can build on the momentum and reuse the data in their own tools and services. <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/" target="_blank">All actors need to play their role</a>, and Crossref’s part is in running the global linking infrastructure at scale, connecting research objects and making them openly available while ensuring that the barriers for the registration, use and reuse of metadata remain as low as possible.</p>
        <p>We feel we&rsquo;re at a tipping point that only needs a small nudge to truly scale the Grant Linking System.</p>
        <p>By waiving BY fees entirely for two years, we&rsquo;re hoping to see members fill in historical data and create more comprehensive grant&lt;-&gt;outcome connections. There is often a long period of time between funding being awarded, and the resulting research objects being generated and communicated. That is why historical grant metadata is so important; we think that there will be many funding outcome relationships and insights just waiting to be uncovered!</p>
        <h3 id="why-give-funders-a-fee-break-and-not-others">Why give funders a fee break and not others?</h3>
        <p>We&rsquo;re not ruling out this kind of fee incentive in future for other members and other object types, but that needs more analysis (which we plan to do) and right now, the relatively small number of grant records, combined with a growing need for this kind of metadata, means the changes are small enough to have almost no impact on Crossref&rsquo;s healthy financial position.</p>
        <p>This decision is consistent with the goals of our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/">Resourcing Crossref for Future Sustainability (RCFS)</a> to review our fees to make sure they are equitable and clear, while ensuring Crossref retains a sustainable business model. Our fees can encourage or discourage the community to participate in Crossref. The RCFS project has also resulted in the creation of a <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/j2bgz-v7h50/" target="_blank">lower membership fee tier</a> for the very lowest-resourced members, and the tidying up of <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10" target="_blank">things like outlier volume discounts</a>.</p>
        <p>The BY fee waiver is positioned as a pilot to allow us to measure its impact over the next two years and feed into the Membership &amp; Fees Committee and RCFS project. We will evaluate the pilot results (i.e. does it indeed supercharge funding metadata connections and adoption?) and consider additional adjustments to other BY registration fees and whether such fee incentives might be extended to other members.</p>
        <p>We encourage all funders to take advantage of these reduced rates to contribute to the Research Nexus and help us build a more complete picture of the relationship between research funding and outcomes.</p>
        <p>Take a look at the recent case studies from early GLS adopters <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/n9n69-y5b75" target="_blank">FWF</a> (Austria), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69" target="_blank">NWO</a> (The Netherlands), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/9gjfp-5p698" target="_blank">FCCN|FCT</a> (Portugal), and <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/c1dh8-qn968" target="_blank">Wellcome/EuropePMC</a>, reach out to them or us with any questions, or peruse the <a href="https://community.crossref.org/c/crossref-services/grant-linking-system/" target="_blank">GLS community forum</a>!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We are pleased to announce that—effective 1st January 2026—we have made two changes to grant record registration fees that aim to accelerate adoption of Crossref’s [Grant Linking System (GLS)](https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/) and provide a two-year window of opportunity to increase the number and availability of open persistent grant identifiers and boost the matching of relationships with research objects.

![High-level benefits of the Crossref Grant Linking System (GLS)](https://www.crossref.org/images/community-images/gls/gls-benefits.png)

Launched in 2019 with close input from several funders and other infrastructure organisations, the GLS primarily offers the ability to create and steward Crossref Grant DOIs, along with several benefits such as dedicated grant/award metadata like funding type, value, contributors, and projects, as well as hosted landing pages, tools to create and update metadata, and of course both member-asserted and Crossref-automatic matching of relationships within the global corpus of 180 million other research objects. Essentially, we need to identify what research objects are produced as a result of the award, and these objects could be articles, preprints, data, code, blogs, posters, and more.

This connected network is what we call the Research Nexus, essential for exploring research activity in general, as well as evaluating reach and return on funding and other support like use of facilities/equipment.

### A fee reduction and a two-year fee waiver pilot

Following a review by our [Membership &#38; Fees Committee](https://www.crossref.org/committees/membership-and-fees/), the [Board](https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#board-members) met in December and passed two related motions:

1. **Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee has been cut in half to match other record types**: The board approved the adjustment of the Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee down from $2.00 to $1.00 USD, effective 1st January 2026.
2. **Back-Year (BY) grant registration fee is waived through 2027**: The board approved a time-limited fee waiver as a pilot for Back-Year (BY) grant registration fees, bringing that per-record fee down from $0.30 to $0.00 for 2026 and 2027.

We aim to boost registration of Back-Year (BY) records and accelerate the growth of the Research Nexus with millions more grant&#60;-&#62;output matches. During the course of the two-year pilot, the Membership &#38; Fees Committee and our [fee project work](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/) that started in 2023 and also [brought in other fee reductions](https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10), will consider more adjustments across BY registration fees for the benefit of members beyond just funders and beyond just grants.

All [Board motions are publicly available](https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#motions) and we encourage questions from the community about our governance processes and the decisions on our members’ behalf; [email us via feedback@crossref.org](mailto:feedback@crossref.org) anytime, or [post on the forum](https://community.crossref.org/c/strategy/).

### Supercharging the Grant Linking System

Leading up to the [GLS](https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/) launch in 2019, we worked with a group of funders and metadata experts to inform the design and implementation of the new service, including a funder governance and fees working group. That was seven years ago, and our [Funder Advisory Group](https://www.crossref.org/working-groups/funders/) now includes nearly 100 funding community representatives the GLS has grown to almost 50 funder members that have registered more than 185,000 open grant metadata records. But they are mostly research councils and agencies or charities from Europe and North America, and we know that for a truly comprehensive and interconnected Research Nexus, more needs to be done to include organisations from all parts of the world. The other key driver is simply to boost more metadata connections; the more grant metadata we gather, the better we can match it to all kinds of research outputs, and this metadata directly feeds thousands of services available in our community, from Dimensions and Scopus, to OA.Report and OpenAlex, as well as funders’ own analytics tools. See our [recent report about the latest dataset](https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09) and of course use [api.crossref.org](htps://api.crossref.org) directly.

Relatedly, we just added a [new Grant DOI field](https://doi.org/10.64000/x7d4h-x3r11) to our schema for all record types, to give our members a precise and accurate way of capturing funding metadata for all research outputs. With the new lower CY registration fee and a pilot waiver of BY fees for grant records, we hope to boost the creation of more Grant DOIs by more funders from more parts of the world—so that others also see and can build on the momentum and reuse the data in their own tools and services. [All actors need to play their role](https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/), and Crossref’s part is in running the global linking infrastructure at scale, connecting research objects and making them openly available while ensuring that the barriers for the registration, use and reuse of metadata remain as low as possible.

We feel we’re at a tipping point that only needs a small nudge to truly scale the Grant Linking System.

By waiving BY fees entirely for two years, we’re hoping to see members fill in historical data and create more comprehensive grant&#60;-&#62;outcome connections. There is often a long period of time between funding being awarded, and the resulting research objects being generated and communicated. That is why historical grant metadata is so important; we think that there will be many funding outcome relationships and insights just waiting to be uncovered!

### Why give funders a fee break and not others?

We’re not ruling out this kind of fee incentive in future for other members and other object types, but that needs more analysis (which we plan to do) and right now, the relatively small number of grant records, combined with a growing need for this kind of metadata, means the changes are small enough to have almost no impact on Crossref’s healthy financial position.

This decision is consistent with the goals of our [Resourcing Crossref for Future Sustainability (RCFS)](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/) to review our fees to make sure they are equitable and clear, while ensuring Crossref retains a sustainable business model. Our fees can encourage or discourage the community to participate in Crossref. The RCFS project has also resulted in the creation of a [lower membership fee tier](https://doi.org/10.64000/j2bgz-v7h50/) for the very lowest-resourced members, and the tidying up of [things like outlier volume discounts](https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10).

The BY fee waiver is positioned as a pilot to allow us to measure its impact over the next two years and feed into the Membership &#38; Fees Committee and RCFS project. We will evaluate the pilot results (i.e. does it indeed supercharge funding metadata connections and adoption?) and consider additional adjustments to other BY registration fees and whether such fee incentives might be extended to other members.

We encourage all funders to take advantage of these reduced rates to contribute to the Research Nexus and help us build a more complete picture of the relationship between research funding and outcomes.

Take a look at the recent case studies from early GLS adopters [FWF](https://doi.org/10.64000/n9n69-y5b75) (Austria), [NWO](https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69) (The Netherlands), [FCCN\|FCT](https://doi.org/10.64000/9gjfp-5p698) (Portugal), and [Wellcome/EuropePMC](https://doi.org/10.64000/c1dh8-qn968), reach out to them or us with any questions, or peruse the [GLS community forum](https://community.crossref.org/c/crossref-services/grant-linking-system/)!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/reduction-of-grant-doi-registration-fees-a-boost-for-the-research-nexus/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Journal Article: “Chatbots for Reference Services in Academic Libraries: Applications and Trends”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/07/new-journal-article-chatbots-for-reference-services-in-academic-libraries-applications-and-trends/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The article linked below was recently published by The Journal of Academic Librarianship. Title Chatbots for Reference Services in Academic Libraries: Applications and Trends Authors Guoying Liu University of Windsor Leddy Library, Canada Shu Liu Peking University Library, China Source The Journal of Academic Librarianship Volume 52, Issue 1, January 2026 First Online: Jan. 5, [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The article linked below was recently published by The Journal of Academic Librarianship. Title Chatbots for Reference Services in Academic Libraries: Applications and Trends Authors Guoying Liu University of Windsor Leddy Library, Canada Shu Liu Peking University Library, China Source The Journal of Academic Librarianship Volume 52, Issue 1, January 2026 First Online: Jan. 5, \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167477</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Kitchen Essentials: An Interview with Tanja Niemann of Érudit / Une Entrevue  avec Tanja Niemann d’Érudit</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/07/kitchen-essentials-an-interview-with-tanja-niemann-of-erudit-une-entrevue-avec-tanja-niemann-derudit/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>For today's Kitchen Essentials post, Alice Meadows interviews Tanja Niemann, Executive Director of Érudit, a Quebec-based non-profit open access publishing platform.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/07/kitchen-essentials-an-interview-with-tanja-niemann-of-erudit-une-entrevue-avec-tanja-niemann-derudit/">Kitchen Essentials: An Interview with Tanja Niemann of Érudit / Une Entrevue  avec Tanja Niemann d’Érudit</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>For today&#39;s Kitchen Essentials post, Alice Meadows interviews Tanja Niemann, Executive Director of Érudit, a Quebec-based non-profit open access publishing platform.

The post [Kitchen Essentials: An Interview with Tanja Niemann of Érudit / Une Entrevue avec Tanja Niemann d’Érudit](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/07/kitchen-essentials-an-interview-with-tanja-niemann-of-erudit-une-entrevue-avec-tanja-niemann-derudit/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61400</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rare Photos of Rosa Parks Discovered in the Archives of Stanford University Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/06/rare-photos-of-rosa-parks-discovered-in-the-archives-of-stanford-university-libraries/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From Stanford Report: Photographs of civil rights activist Rosa Parks were recently made public after they were discovered in the archives of Stanford University Libraries. Taken during the 1965 march from Selma to Montgomery, Alabama, the images reveal a side of Parks rarely shown to the public. After taking the photos, late photographer Matt Herron [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From Stanford Report: Photographs of civil rights activist Rosa Parks were recently made public after they were discovered in the archives of Stanford University Libraries. Taken during the 1965 march from Selma to Montgomery, Alabama, the images reveal a side of Parks rarely shown to the public. After taking the photos, late photographer Matt Herron \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167468</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Haunted Hotel, by Wilkie Collins</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-haunted-hotel</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The death in Venice of a wealthy man under very mysterious circumstances leads to suspicions of a supernatural cause.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The death in Venice of a wealthy man under very mysterious circumstances leads to suspicions of a supernatural cause.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-haunted-hotel/downloads/wilkie-collins_the-haunted-hotel.epub?source=feed" length="724057" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-haunted-hotel</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Brooklyn Murders, by G. D. H. Cole</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-d-h-cole/the-brooklyn-murders</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Scotland Yard and a pair of amateur sleuths investigate the case of two heirs to a fortune who apparently murdered each other.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Scotland Yard and a pair of amateur sleuths investigate the case of two heirs to a fortune who apparently murdered each other.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-d-h-cole/the-brooklyn-murders/downloads/g-d-h-cole_the-brooklyn-murders.epub?source=feed" length="532876" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-d-h-cole/the-brooklyn-murders</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ORCID Releases New Strategic Plan: “ORCID 2030: Advancing the Future of Research”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/06/orcid-releases-new-strategic-plan-orcid-2030-advancing-the-future-of-research/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From an ORCID Blog Post: Our new strategic plan, ORCID 2030: Advancing the Future of Research, outlines our commitment to meeting the challenges and opportunities presented by this dynamic future and underscores a significant evolution in our focus, moving from a foundation of establishing trust and value to a more active, expansive role in empowering the [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From an ORCID Blog Post: Our new strategic plan, ORCID 2030: Advancing the Future of Research, outlines our commitment to meeting the challenges and opportunities presented by this dynamic future and underscores a significant evolution in our focus, moving from a foundation of establishing trust and value to a more active, expansive role in empowering the \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167466</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Keywords Are Not Dead — But Discovery Is No Longer Just Search</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/06/keywords-are-not-dead-but-discovery-is-no-longer-just-search/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>As with previous shifts in content discovery, today's winners will be those who understand the strengths and limits of AI search, and design systems that let researchers move fluidly between precision and synthesis.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/06/keywords-are-not-dead-but-discovery-is-no-longer-just-search/">Keywords Are Not Dead — But Discovery Is No Longer Just Search</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>As with previous shifts in content discovery, today&#39;s winners will be those who understand the strengths and limits of AI search, and design systems that let researchers move fluidly between precision and synthesis.

The post [Keywords Are Not Dead — But Discovery Is No Longer Just Search](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/06/keywords-are-not-dead-but-discovery-is-no-longer-just-search/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61396</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The best way of acknowledging research funding in the metadata: Crossref Grant ID</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/the-best-way-of-acknowledging-research-funding-in-the-metadata-crossref-grant-id/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We are very pleased to kick off the New Year with another important schema update and the news that a Grant DOI field is now supported for all record types. This means that Crossref members can explicitly include the Crossref Grant IDs as part of their DOI metadata records for publications and any other output type, accurately linking research outputs to the funding that made it possible, all through metadata. We hope that our members will leverage this to respond to recent calls for <a href="https://council.science/statements/isc-position-on-research-funding-transparency/" target="_blank">stronger funding transparency</a> and best practices for <a href="https://publicationethics.org/guidance/discussion-document/declaring-funding-sources-research" target="_blank">reporting funding sources in research outputs</a>. </p>
        <p>Funding information is very important for the research community. As explored by <a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2025/12/11/open-funder-metadata-is-essential-for-true-research-transparency/" target="_blank">some key European funder representatives</a>, providing mechanisms to clearly link funding with its outputs is essential for the community to have a full picture of the research endeavour.</p>
        <div class="quotecite">
        <blockquote>
        <p>When funders systematically register grants with persistent identifiers and make this information openly available, they create a foundation that publishers and infrastructure providers such as repositories can reliably build upon when depositing output metadata.”</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p><cite>&ndash; Hans de Jonge, Katharina Rieck and Zoé Ancion</cite></p>
        </div>
        <p>Up until now, if a Crossref member wanted to include a Crossref Grant ID to unambiguously identify the output funding source, they would need to use other available fields, such as for an award number. While it was an important step towards increasing transparency and is heavily used for reporting and impact assessment, being an unstructured field, it was prone to errors, and of course, funders’ internal award identifiers are not unique, persistent, or necessarily open. This limited our ability to create unambiguous relationships with the Crossref Grant DOIs registered by our now ~50 funder members. As the new field becomes increasingly populated by our members, this rich metadata will pave the way for capturing and representing the funding relationships in a more accurate and complete way and fulfilling one of our commitments at the <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/" target="_blank">recent funding metadata workshop with the Barcelona Declaration.</a> </p>
        <p><strong>The Crossref Grant ID field in the schema is a clear signal of the growing demand for these persistent Grant IDs (Crossref DOIs), and the relationships these help us create.</strong> Those connections can in turn enable streamlined reporting for the grantees, as well as compliance tracking and programme evaluation for funders. </p>
        <p>As part of our work to enable the research nexus, Crossref has been proactively identifying funding information and prototyping metadata enrichment processes <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/">through matching projects</a>, ensuring that as many <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09" target="_blank">relationships as possible are established and made discoverable</a>. With this schema update, we aim to lower barriers and encourage more members to register output-funding relationships at source. This will facilitate the links that make the research nexus a connected, interoperable, and an important source of information that ensures a transparent and trustworthy research process. </p>
        <p><strong>We encourage all Crossref members to start incorporating Grant DOIs when available into your metadata submissions.</strong> By taking advantage of this new field, you&rsquo;ll help build a more complete and transparent record of research funding, making it easier for the community to understand and trace the impact of funded research. </p>
        <p>When collecting funding information for your publication, please consider asking the authors for the Grant DOI (Crossref Grant ID) as well as the funder’s details (such as their name and identifier). Here’s how the U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Scientific and Technical Information&rsquo;s (OSTI-DOE) grant <a href="https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611</a> can be included in the metadata for related works, from datasets, to preprints, conference proceedings, journal articles, and more:</p>
        <div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-JS" data-lang="JS"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;fundgroup&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;ror&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="nx">https</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="c1">//ror.org/04qxsr837&lt;/assertion&gt;
        </span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"></span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;grant_doi&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mf">10.46936</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="nx">aps</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">182101</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="mi">60010611</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span></code></pre></div><p>Similarly, a grant <a href="https://doi.org/10.3030/732489" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.3030/732489</a> from European Union H2020-EU.2.1.1. - INDUSTRIAL LEADERSHIP, would be represented in related work’s metadata as follows:</p>
        <div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-JS" data-lang="JS"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;fundgroup&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;funder_name”&gt;H2020 LEIT Information and Communication Technologies
        </span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="s2"> &lt;assertion name=&#34;</span><span class="nx">funder_identifier</span><span class="err">”</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mf">10.13039</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="mi">100010669</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;grant_doi&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mf">10.3030</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="mi">732489</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span></code></pre></div><p>For more technical documentation and implementation guidance, please visit <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/funding-information/">our funding data documentation</a>. If you have questions or need support integrating Grant IDs into your workflow, our support team is here to help!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We are very pleased to kick off the New Year with another important schema update and the news that a Grant DOI field is now supported for all record types. This means that Crossref members can explicitly include the Crossref Grant IDs as part of their DOI metadata records for publications and any other output type, accurately linking research outputs to the funding that made it possible, all through metadata. We hope that our members will leverage this to respond to recent calls for [stronger funding transparency](https://council.science/statements/isc-position-on-research-funding-transparency/) and best practices for [reporting funding sources in research outputs](https://publicationethics.org/guidance/discussion-document/declaring-funding-sources-research).

Funding information is very important for the research community. As explored by [some key European funder representatives](https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2025/12/11/open-funder-metadata-is-essential-for-true-research-transparency/), providing mechanisms to clearly link funding with its outputs is essential for the community to have a full picture of the research endeavour.

&#62; When funders systematically register grants with persistent identifiers and make this information openly available, they create a foundation that publishers and infrastructure providers such as repositories can reliably build upon when depositing output metadata.”

– Hans de Jonge, Katharina Rieck and Zoé Ancion

Up until now, if a Crossref member wanted to include a Crossref Grant ID to unambiguously identify the output funding source, they would need to use other available fields, such as for an award number. While it was an important step towards increasing transparency and is heavily used for reporting and impact assessment, being an unstructured field, it was prone to errors, and of course, funders’ internal award identifiers are not unique, persistent, or necessarily open. This limited our ability to create unambiguous relationships with the Crossref Grant DOIs registered by our now ~50 funder members. As the new field becomes increasingly populated by our members, this rich metadata will pave the way for capturing and representing the funding relationships in a more accurate and complete way and fulfilling one of our commitments at the [recent funding metadata workshop with the Barcelona Declaration.](https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/)

**The Crossref Grant ID field in the schema is a clear signal of the growing demand for these persistent Grant IDs (Crossref DOIs), and the relationships these help us create.** Those connections can in turn enable streamlined reporting for the grantees, as well as compliance tracking and programme evaluation for funders.

As part of our work to enable the research nexus, Crossref has been proactively identifying funding information and prototyping metadata enrichment processes [through matching projects](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/), ensuring that as many [relationships as possible are established and made discoverable](https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09). With this schema update, we aim to lower barriers and encourage more members to register output-funding relationships at source. This will facilitate the links that make the research nexus a connected, interoperable, and an important source of information that ensures a transparent and trustworthy research process.

**We encourage all Crossref members to start incorporating Grant DOIs when available into your metadata submissions.** By taking advantage of this new field, you’ll help build a more complete and transparent record of research funding, making it easier for the community to understand and trace the impact of funded research.

When collecting funding information for your publication, please consider asking the authors for the Grant DOI (Crossref Grant ID) as well as the funder’s details (such as their name and identifier). Here’s how the U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Scientific and Technical Information’s (OSTI-DOE) grant [https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611](https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611) can be included in the metadata for related works, from datasets, to preprints, conference proceedings, journal articles, and more:

```JS
&#60;assertion name=&#34;fundgroup&#34;&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;ror&#34;&#62;https://ror.org/04qxsr837&#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;grant_doi&#34;&#62;10.46936/aps-182101/60010611&#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;/assertion&#62;

```

Similarly, a grant [https://doi.org/10.3030/732489](https://doi.org/10.3030/732489) from European Union H2020-EU.2.1.1. - INDUSTRIAL LEADERSHIP, would be represented in related work’s metadata as follows:

```JS
&#60;assertion name=&#34;fundgroup&#34;&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;funder_name”&#62;H2020 LEIT Information and Communication Technologies
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;funder_identifier”&#62;10.13039/100010669&#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;grant_doi&#34;&#62;10.3030/732489&#60;/assertion&#62;
&#60;/assertion&#62;

```

For more technical documentation and implementation guidance, please visit [our funding data documentation](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/funding-information/). If you have questions or need support integrating Grant IDs into your workflow, our support team is here to help!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/the-best-way-of-acknowledging-research-funding-in-the-metadata-crossref-grant-id/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Apple Cart, by George Bernard Shaw</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/the-apple-cart</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An English king challenges his popular prime minister and cabinet.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>An English king challenges his popular prime minister and cabinet.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/the-apple-cart/downloads/george-bernard-shaw_the-apple-cart.epub?source=feed" length="535483" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/the-apple-cart</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Planet of the Damned, by Harry Harrison</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/harry-harrison/planet-of-the-damned</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A planetary champion finds himself employed to solve another planet’s pressing problem.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A planetary champion finds himself employed to solve another planet’s pressing problem.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/harry-harrison/planet-of-the-damned/downloads/harry-harrison_planet-of-the-damned.epub?source=feed" length="798387" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/harry-harrison/planet-of-the-damned</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Tennessee: Here’s Which Libraries Have Been Ordered to Review Book Collections</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/05/tennessee-heres-which-libraries-have-been-ordered-to-review-book-collections/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From The Tennessean:  &#124;&#124;&#124; Archived Version Some 181 libraries in the Tennessee Regional Library System, in 91 of the state&#8217;s 95 counties, received letters from the secretary of state in October calling for a full audit of the libraries&#8217; juvenile books to better align them with Trump administration standards on gender topics. The directive has caused [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From The Tennessean:  \|\|\| Archived Version Some 181 libraries in the Tennessee Regional Library System, in 91 of the state’s 95 counties, received letters from the secretary of state in October calling for a full audit of the libraries’ juvenile books to better align them with Trump administration standards on gender topics. The directive has caused \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167465</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Year in Review: 2025 in The Scholarly Kitchen</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/05/the-year-in-review-2025-in-the-scholarly-kitchen/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Before we plunge into 2026, a look back at 2025, a difficult year for many in the scholarly community.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/05/the-year-in-review-2025-in-the-scholarly-kitchen/">The Year in Review: 2025 in The Scholarly Kitchen</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Before we plunge into 2026, a look back at 2025, a difficult year for many in the scholarly community.

The post [The Year in Review: 2025 in The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/05/the-year-in-review-2025-in-the-scholarly-kitchen/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61392</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>CREATORS: You Still Have Time to Submit Your Public Domain Remix Film</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/03/creators-you-still-have-time-to-submit-your-public-domain-remix-film/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[You have until 11:59pm PST on January 7th to enter our annual Public Domain Film Remix Contest &#8211; full details &#38; contest guidelines.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>You have until 11:59pm PST on January 7th to enter our annual Public Domain Film Remix Contest – full details &#38; contest guidelines.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29875</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The City of God, by Augustine of Hippo</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/augustine-of-hippo/the-city-of-god/marcus-dods_george-wilson_j-j-smith</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Bishop Augustine of Hippo provides a defense of the Christian faith against its pagan critics, as well as explaining God’s work and purposes in world history, from beginning to end.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Bishop Augustine of Hippo provides a defense of the Christian faith against its pagan critics, as well as explaining God’s work and purposes in world history, from beginning to end.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/augustine-of-hippo/the-city-of-god/marcus-dods_george-wilson_j-j-smith/downloads/augustine-of-hippo_the-city-of-god_marcus-dods-george-wilson-j-j-smith.epub?source=feed" length="1555325" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/augustine-of-hippo/the-city-of-god/marcus-dods_george-wilson_j-j-smith</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>portal: Libraries and the Academy (Vol 26, No 1; Preprints For All Articles Now Available Online)</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/03/preprints-for-all-articles-now-available-portal-libraries-and-the-academy-vol-26-no-1/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Preprints for all articles found in in portal: Libraries and the Academy  (Vol 26, No 1) are now available online. Links below. From the ICU to Academia: A conversation with Maribeth Slebodnik (Editorial) Author(s): Ellysa Stern Cahoy, Maribeth Slebodnik Insights from a Burnout Debate: Occupational Health Psychology for Academic Librarianship (Worth Noting) Author(s): Matthew Weirick [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Preprints for all articles found in in portal: Libraries and the Academy  (Vol 26, No 1) are now available online. Links below. From the ICU to Academia: A conversation with Maribeth Slebodnik (Editorial) Author(s): Ellysa Stern Cahoy, Maribeth Slebodnik Insights from a Burnout Debate: Occupational Health Psychology for Academic Librarianship (Worth Noting) Author(s): Matthew Weirick \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167462</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>As I Lay Dying, by William Faulkner</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/william-faulkner/as-i-lay-dying</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[After a woman in rural Mississippi dies, her husband and five children begin an arduous journey to convey her coffin back to her hometown.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>After a woman in rural Mississippi dies, her husband and five children begin an arduous journey to convey her coffin back to her hometown.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/william-faulkner/as-i-lay-dying/downloads/william-faulkner_as-i-lay-dying.epub?source=feed" length="537998" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/william-faulkner/as-i-lay-dying</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Faraway Bride, by Stella Benson</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/stella-benson/the-faraway-bride</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young Russian man walks from Manchuria to Seoul to reclaim an old debt.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young Russian man walks from Manchuria to Seoul to reclaim an old debt.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/stella-benson/the-faraway-bride/downloads/stella-benson_the-faraway-bride.epub?source=feed" length="672589" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/stella-benson/the-faraway-bride</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Years of Grace, by Margaret Ayer Barnes</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/margaret-ayer-barnes/years-of-grace</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young woman comes of age in the American Midwest at the turn of the 20th century.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young woman comes of age in the American Midwest at the turn of the 20th century.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/margaret-ayer-barnes/years-of-grace/downloads/margaret-ayer-barnes_years-of-grace.epub?source=feed" length="1098366" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/margaret-ayer-barnes/years-of-grace</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Not Without Laughter, by Langston Hughes</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/langston-hughes/not-without-laughter</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An African-American boy comes of age in a small town in Kansas.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>An African-American boy comes of age in a small town in Kansas.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/langston-hughes/not-without-laughter/downloads/langston-hughes_not-without-laughter.epub?source=feed" length="443100" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/langston-hughes/not-without-laughter</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The End of the World, by Geoffrey Dennis</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/geoffrey-dennis/the-end-of-the-world</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A philosophical reflection on how the end of the world would unfold based on hypothetical variables and relevant knowledge and historical context.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A philosophical reflection on how the end of the world would unfold based on hypothetical variables and relevant knowledge and historical context.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/geoffrey-dennis/the-end-of-the-world/downloads/geoffrey-dennis_the-end-of-the-world.epub?source=feed" length="532439" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/geoffrey-dennis/the-end-of-the-world</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Castle, by Franz Kafka</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/franz-kafka/the-castle/willa-muir_edwin-muir</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A land surveyor accepts an appointment in a distant town, but is surprised to find that he is unwanted there.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A land surveyor accepts an appointment in a distant town, but is surprised to find that he is unwanted there.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/franz-kafka/the-castle/willa-muir_edwin-muir/downloads/franz-kafka_the-castle_willa-muir-edwin-muir.epub?source=feed" length="932102" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/franz-kafka/the-castle/willa-muir_edwin-muir</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Vile Bodies, by Evelyn Waugh</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/evelyn-waugh/vile-bodies</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young man in Roaring Twenties London endures ups and downs in varied situations and relationships.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young man in Roaring Twenties London endures ups and downs in varied situations and relationships.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/evelyn-waugh/vile-bodies/downloads/evelyn-waugh_vile-bodies.epub?source=feed" length="713210" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/evelyn-waugh/vile-bodies</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Miss Mole, by E. H. Young</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/e-h-young/miss-mole</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A middle-aged governess tries to find her purpose in life.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A middle-aged governess tries to find her purpose in life.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/e-h-young/miss-mole/downloads/e-h-young_miss-mole.epub?source=feed" length="1192504" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/e-h-young/miss-mole</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Cimarron, by Edna Ferber</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edna-ferber/cimarron</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A colorful frontiersman and his southern belle wife migrate to Oklahoma during the 1889 land rush to start a new life.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A colorful frontiersman and his southern belle wife migrate to Oklahoma during the 1889 land rush to start a new life.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edna-ferber/cimarron/downloads/edna-ferber_cimarron.epub?source=feed" length="711402" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edna-ferber/cimarron</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Strong Poison, by Dorothy L. Sayers</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/dorothy-l-sayers/strong-poison</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A gentleman detective works to exonerate a woman accused of poisoning her ex-lover.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A gentleman detective works to exonerate a woman accused of poisoning her ex-lover.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/dorothy-l-sayers/strong-poison/downloads/dorothy-l-sayers_strong-poison.epub?source=feed" length="641355" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/dorothy-l-sayers/strong-poison</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Maltese Falcon, by Dashiell Hammett</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/dashiell-hammett/the-maltese-falcon</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A detective becomes embroiled in a series of murders and intrigues, all seemingly related to a mysterious figurine.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A detective becomes embroiled in a series of murders and intrigues, all seemingly related to a mysterious figurine.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/dashiell-hammett/the-maltese-falcon/downloads/dashiell-hammett_the-maltese-falcon.epub?source=feed" length="1006533" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/dashiell-hammett/the-maltese-falcon</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Short Fiction, by Daphne du Maurier</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/daphne-du-maurier/short-fiction</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of short stories by Daphne du Maurier.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A collection of short stories by Daphne du Maurier.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/daphne-du-maurier/short-fiction/downloads/daphne-du-maurier_short-fiction.epub?source=feed" length="285848" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/daphne-du-maurier/short-fiction</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Secret of the Old Clock, by Carolyn Keene</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-secret-of-the-old-clock</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The sixteen-year-old daughter of a prominent attorney undertakes an investigation to search for a missing will.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The sixteen-year-old daughter of a prominent attorney undertakes an investigation to search for a missing will.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-secret-of-the-old-clock/downloads/carolyn-keene_the-secret-of-the-old-clock.epub?source=feed" length="448127" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-secret-of-the-old-clock</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Mystery at Lilac Inn, by Carolyn Keene</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-mystery-at-lilac-inn</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young amateur detective attempts to recover her friend’s stolen diamonds.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young amateur detective attempts to recover her friend’s stolen diamonds.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-mystery-at-lilac-inn/downloads/carolyn-keene_the-mystery-at-lilac-inn.epub?source=feed" length="654134" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-mystery-at-lilac-inn</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Hidden Staircase, by Carolyn Keene</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-hidden-staircase</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young amateur detective investigates a supposed haunting.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young amateur detective investigates a supposed haunting.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-hidden-staircase/downloads/carolyn-keene_the-hidden-staircase.epub?source=feed" length="650699" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/carolyn-keene/the-hidden-staircase</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Giant’s Bread, by Agatha Christie</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/agatha-christie/giants-bread</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The genesis of a monumental piece of music is described in the life of its composer.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The genesis of a monumental piece of music is described in the life of its composer.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/agatha-christie/giants-bread/downloads/agatha-christie_giants-bread.epub?source=feed" length="671950" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/agatha-christie/giants-bread</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Public Domain in 2026</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/01/welcome-to-the-public-domain-in-2026/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Celebrate the public domain with the Internet Archive in the following ways: On January 1, 2026, we celebrate published works from 1930 and published sound recordings from 1925 entering the [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Celebrate the public domain with the Internet Archive in the following ways: On January 1, 2026, we celebrate published works from 1930 and published sound recordings from 1925 entering the \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://ia801501.us.archive.org/16/items/marx_brothers_202101/Marx%20Brothers/Marx%20Brothers%20%5B1930%5D%20Animal%20Crackers.mp4" length="556330698" type="video/mp4" />
      <enclosure url="https://dn720209.ca.archive.org/0/items/the_three_stooges_specials/The%20Three%20Stooges%20-%200x001%20-%20Soup%20to%20Nuts%20%281930%29.mp4" length="446444421" type="video/mp4" />
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29835</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NY Times: “NASA’s Largest Library is Closing Amid Staff and Lab Cuts”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2025/12/31/ny-times-nasas-largest-library-is-closing-amid-staff-and-lab-cuts/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new NY Times article about the closing of the Goddard Space Flight Center Library closing. From the Article: The Trump administration is closing NASA’s largest research library on Friday, a facility that houses tens of thousands of books, documents and journals — many of them not digitized or available anywhere else. Jacob Richmond, a [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A new NY Times article about the closing of the Goddard Space Flight Center Library closing. From the Article: The Trump administration is closing NASA’s largest research library on Friday, a facility that houses tens of thousands of books, documents and journals — many of them not digitized or available anywhere else. Jacob Richmond, a \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167459</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Our Baseball Club and How It Won the Championship, by Noah Brooks</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/noah-brooks/our-baseball-club-and-how-it-won-the-championship</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A late-19th century Illinois baseball team journeys to compete for the championship.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A late-19th century Illinois baseball team journeys to compete for the championship.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/noah-brooks/our-baseball-club-and-how-it-won-the-championship/downloads/noah-brooks_our-baseball-club-and-how-it-won-the-championship.epub?source=feed" length="924064" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/noah-brooks/our-baseball-club-and-how-it-won-the-championship</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Outlaw of Torn, by Edgar Rice Burroughs</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edgar-rice-burroughs/the-outlaw-of-torn</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A powerful knight terrorizes the aristocracy and protects the poor in 13th century England.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A powerful knight terrorizes the aristocracy and protects the poor in 13th century England.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edgar-rice-burroughs/the-outlaw-of-torn/downloads/edgar-rice-burroughs_the-outlaw-of-torn.epub?source=feed" length="675066" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edgar-rice-burroughs/the-outlaw-of-torn</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Tintin, The Wayback Machine, and The Public Domain</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/12/26/wayback-machine-and-public-domain-research/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[What do a Belgian boy reporter, a forgotten 2008 webpage, and the Wayback Machine have in common? They all played a role in uncovering Tintin the Belgian detective’s earliest adventures [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>What do a Belgian boy reporter, a forgotten 2008 webpage, and the Wayback Machine have in common? They all played a role in uncovering Tintin the Belgian detective’s earliest adventures \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29676</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Hibernating Until Next Year</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/24/hibernating-until-next-year/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We're off for the holidays and will see you next in 2026. In the meantime, here's a favorite for your holiday playlist.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/24/hibernating-until-next-year/">Hibernating Until Next Year</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We&#39;re off for the holidays and will see you next in 2026. In the meantime, here&#39;s a favorite for your holiday playlist.

The post [Hibernating Until Next Year](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/24/hibernating-until-next-year/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61385</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Lone Wolf, by Louis Joseph Vance</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/louis-joseph-vance/the-lone-wolf</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A skilled thief, pursued for his past crimes, is faced with a choice between love or a life of crime.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A skilled thief, pursued for his past crimes, is faced with a choice between love or a life of crime.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/louis-joseph-vance/the-lone-wolf/downloads/louis-joseph-vance_the-lone-wolf.epub?source=feed" length="528901" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/louis-joseph-vance/the-lone-wolf</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Ask The Chefs: What Would You Ask of Academic Publishing Santa</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/23/ask-the-chefs-what-would-you-ask-of-academic-publishing-santa/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>To close out 2025, we asked the Chefs: What would you ask for from Academic Publishing Santa?</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/23/ask-the-chefs-what-would-you-ask-of-academic-publishing-santa/">Ask The Chefs: What Would You Ask of Academic Publishing Santa</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>To close out 2025, we asked the Chefs: What would you ask for from Academic Publishing Santa?

The post [Ask The Chefs: What Would You Ask of Academic Publishing Santa](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/23/ask-the-chefs-what-would-you-ask-of-academic-publishing-santa/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61380</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Top News Stories About the Internet Archive: 2025</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/12/22/top-news-stories-about-the-internet-archive-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In 2025, a global conversation emerged about memory, power and who controls the historical record. As governments deleted web pages, platforms broke links, and public data quietly (and not so [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In 2025, a global conversation emerged about memory, power and who controls the historical record. As governments deleted web pages, platforms broke links, and public data quietly (and not so \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29809</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Law and the Lady, by Wilkie Collins</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-law-and-the-lady</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[After a young woman discovers that her husband is concealing a terrible secret, she vows to discover the truth.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>After a young woman discovers that her husband is concealing a terrible secret, she vows to discover the truth.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-law-and-the-lady/downloads/wilkie-collins_the-law-and-the-lady.epub?source=feed" length="888972" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-law-and-the-lady</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Understanding AI at the Library: An Interview with Kurt Lemai-Nguyen</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2025/12/kurt-lemai-nguyen-interview/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In this interview, 2025 Library of Congress Junior Fellow Kurt Lemai-Nguyen reflects on his experience working to support understanding AI at the Library in the Library's Digital Strategy Directorate. This interview has been edited for length and clarity.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In this interview, 2025 Library of Congress Junior Fellow Kurt Lemai-Nguyen reflects on his experience working to support understanding AI at the Library in the Library&#39;s Digital Strategy Directorate. This interview has been edited for length and clarity.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/?p=36149</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Futility, by William Gerhardie</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/william-gerhardie/futility</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An English man befriends three young women from a soon-to-be-wealthy Russian family.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>An English man befriends three young women from a soon-to-be-wealthy Russian family.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/william-gerhardie/futility/downloads/william-gerhardie_futility.epub?source=feed" length="648369" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/william-gerhardie/futility</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Repertoires: How Researchers Struggle to Stay In Sync</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/repertoires-how-researchers-struggle-to-stay-in-sync/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on January 7, 2026, 11:40 am ET The last few working days of a very long year are an apt moment to reflect on how we experience time...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/repertoires-how-researchers-struggle-to-stay-in-sync/">Repertoires: How Researchers Struggle to Stay In Sync</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on January 7, 2026, 11:40 am ET The last few working days of a very long year are an apt moment to reflect on how we experience time...

The post [Repertoires: How Researchers Struggle to Stay In Sync](https://www.arl.org/blog/repertoires-how-researchers-struggle-to-stay-in-sync/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=46968</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — DEI Under Threat: Collaborative Strategies to #DefendResearch</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/22/guest-post-dei-under-threat-collaborative-strategies-to-defendresearch/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest post reflects on the recent panel discussion, "Collaborative strategies to #DefendResearch and ensure academic freedom," by speakers and organizers of the event.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/22/guest-post-dei-under-threat-collaborative-strategies-to-defendresearch/">Guest Post — DEI Under Threat: Collaborative Strategies to #DefendResearch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest post reflects on the recent panel discussion, &#34;Collaborative strategies to #DefendResearch and ensure academic freedom,&#34; by speakers and organizers of the event.

The post [Guest Post — DEI Under Threat: Collaborative Strategies to #DefendResearch](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/22/guest-post-dei-under-threat-collaborative-strategies-to-defendresearch/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61368</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Joyful Chaos of the Early Web: A Conversation with Creator Audrey Witters</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/12/22/audrey-witters/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Audrey Witters remembers the creativity of the early web. When she was launching her career in the mid-1990s, being online was more about exploring and having fun than figuring out [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Audrey Witters remembers the creativity of the early web. When she was launching her career in the mid-1990s, being online was more about exploring and having fun than figuring out \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29806</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Conference Paper: “Hallucinations in Scholarly LLMs: A Conceptual Overview and Practical Implications”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2025/12/20/conference-paper-hallucinations-in-scholarly-llms-a-conceptual-overview-and-practical-implications/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The paper linked below appears in the Proceedings of the 2nd AAAI (Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence). Bridge on Artificial Intelligence for Scholarly Communication. Title Hallucinations in Scholarly LLMs: A Conceptual Overview and Practical Implications Authors Naveen Lamba Sharda University, India Sanju Tiwari Sharda University, India Manas Gaur University of Maryland, Baltimore County [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The paper linked below appears in the Proceedings of the 2nd AAAI (Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence). Bridge on Artificial Intelligence for Scholarly Communication. Title Hallucinations in Scholarly LLMs: A Conceptual Overview and Practical Implications Authors Naveen Lamba Sharda University, India Sanju Tiwari Sharda University, India Manas Gaur University of Maryland, Baltimore County \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167453</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Policy Brief From PEN America: The Bills Igniting Book Bans</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2025/12/19/new-policy-brief-from-pen-america-the-bills-igniting-book-bans/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From PEN America: Thousands of books removed from schools out of fear of state governments nationwide. Judy Blume’s Forever… banned from every Utah public school; To Kill a Mockingbird and 39 other titles pulled from a Texas school district that used AI to review materials; a list of 400 titles removed in one district quietly circulated in Tennessee as a resource for other school [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From PEN America: Thousands of books removed from schools out of fear of state governments nationwide. Judy Blume’s Forever… banned from every Utah public school; To Kill a Mockingbird and 39 other titles pulled from a Texas school district that used AI to review materials; a list of 400 titles removed in one district quietly circulated in Tennessee as a resource for other school \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167449</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Powerhouse, by John Buchan</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/john-buchan/the-powerhouse</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A secret criminal organization is uncovered after an M.P.’s friend goes missing.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A secret criminal organization is uncovered after an M.P.’s friend goes missing.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/john-buchan/the-powerhouse/downloads/john-buchan_the-powerhouse.epub?source=feed" length="627287" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/john-buchan/the-powerhouse</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — How AI is Transforming Platform Strategy: Beyond the Hype</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/19/guest-post-how-ai-is-transforming-platform-strategy-beyond-the-hype/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest blogger challenges us to look beyond the hype of AI, and embrace AI agents handling platform grunt work, validation, and parallel processing that expands what we can accomplish with immediate and substantial productivity gains.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/19/guest-post-how-ai-is-transforming-platform-strategy-beyond-the-hype/">Guest Post — How AI is Transforming Platform Strategy: Beyond the Hype</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest blogger challenges us to look beyond the hype of AI, and embrace AI agents handling platform grunt work, validation, and parallel processing that expands what we can accomplish with immediate and substantial productivity gains.

The post [Guest Post — How AI is Transforming Platform Strategy: Beyond the Hype](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/19/guest-post-how-ai-is-transforming-platform-strategy-beyond-the-hype/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61357</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — DEI Under Threat: Collaborative Strategies to #DefendResearch</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/19/guest-post-dei-under-threat-collaborative-strategies-to-defendresearch/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest post reflects on the recent panel discussion, "Collaborative strategies to #DefendResearch and ensure academic freedom," by speakers and organizers of the event.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/19/guest-post-dei-under-threat-collaborative-strategies-to-defendresearch/">Guest Post — DEI Under Threat: Collaborative Strategies to #DefendResearch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest post reflects on the recent panel discussion, &#34;Collaborative strategies to #DefendResearch and ensure academic freedom,&#34; by speakers and organizers of the event.

The post [Guest Post — DEI Under Threat: Collaborative Strategies to #DefendResearch](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/19/guest-post-dei-under-threat-collaborative-strategies-to-defendresearch/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61368</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Payment Deferred, by C. S. Forester</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/c-s-forester/payment-deferred</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A family man desperate for money murders a rich relative, and has to deal with the consequences.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A family man desperate for money murders a rich relative, and has to deal with the consequences.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/c-s-forester/payment-deferred/downloads/c-s-forester_payment-deferred.epub?source=feed" length="707021" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/c-s-forester/payment-deferred</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Plum Bun, by Jessie Redmon Fauset</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/jessie-redmon-fauset/plum-bun</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A light-skinned African-American woman passes as white when she launches her artistic career in New York City.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A light-skinned African-American woman passes as white when she launches her artistic career in New York City.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/jessie-redmon-fauset/plum-bun/downloads/jessie-redmon-fauset_plum-bun.epub?source=feed" length="594603" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/jessie-redmon-fauset/plum-bun</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Can You Measure It?</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/can-you-measure-it/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The debate over the value of the liberal arts rages on. State policymakers and institutions face increasing pressure to demonstrate “value” to taxpayers and prospective students, which often means redirecting state funding to “credentials of value” as measured by students’ earnings. Yet those who have experienced a liberal arts and sciences education often describe deeply appreciating its value, even if they have difficulty quantifying that value or describing exactly which features of their education made it so meaningful.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/can-you-measure-it/">Can You Measure It?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The debate over the value of the liberal arts rages on. State policymakers and institutions face increasing pressure to demonstrate “value” to taxpayers and prospective students, which often means redirecting state funding to “credentials of value” as measured by students’ earnings. Yet those who have experienced a liberal arts and sciences education often describe deeply appreciating its value, even if they have difficulty quantifying that value or describing exactly which features of their education made it so meaningful.

The post [Can You Measure It?](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/can-you-measure-it/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=324276</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Report From US GAO: Public Libraries: Many Buildings are Reported to Be in Poor Condition, with Increasing Deferred Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2025/12/18/new-report-from-us-gao-public-libraries-many-buildings-are-reported-to-be-in-poor-condition-with-increasing-deferred-maintenance/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The report linked below was published today by the US Government Accountability Office (US GAO). From the Report: Public libraries serve as cornerstones of many communities. But aging and outdated buildings can make it hard for libraries to meet increasing expectations to provide access to programming, technology, emergency services, and voting sites—in addition to books. [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The report linked below was published today by the US Government Accountability Office (US GAO). From the Report: Public libraries serve as cornerstones of many communities. But aging and outdated buildings can make it hard for libraries to meet increasing expectations to provide access to programming, technology, emergency services, and voting sites—in addition to books. \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167445</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — Three Ways to Innovate and Reimagine Publisher Value in an AI World</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/18/guest-post-three-ways-to-innovate-and-reimagine-publisher-value-in-an-ai-world/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>AI is presenting new challenges while also giving us tools to innovate in ways. The most successful publishers will be those willing to challenge the status quo.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/18/guest-post-three-ways-to-innovate-and-reimagine-publisher-value-in-an-ai-world/">Guest Post &#8212; Three Ways to Innovate and Reimagine Publisher Value in an AI World</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>AI is presenting new challenges while also giving us tools to innovate in ways. The most successful publishers will be those willing to challenge the status quo.

The post [Guest Post — Three Ways to Innovate and Reimagine Publisher Value in an AI World](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/12/18/guest-post-three-ways-to-innovate-and-reimagine-publisher-value-in-an-ai-world/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61362</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>DWeb in 2025: Looking Back at a Year of Decentralization</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/12/18/dweb-annual-recap-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[We’re thrilled to see all that our community has done this past year: gathering, developing, and dreaming together. Here is a look back at the major events and happenings across the DWeb Network!]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We’re thrilled to see all that our community has done this past year: gathering, developing, and dreaming together. Here is a look back at the major events and happenings across the DWeb Network!</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://archive.org/details/dweb-virtual-meetup-nov-2025-open-source-ag-tech/DWeb+Virtual+Meetup+-+Nov+2025-+video.mp4" length="0" type="video/mp4" />
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29784</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Highlights of a very busy year: our 2025 annual report</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/highlights-of-a-very-busy-year-our-2025-annual-report/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>As we finish <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/25years/">celebrating our 25th anniversary</a>, we can look back on a truly transformational year, defined by the successful delivery of several long-planned, foundational projects&mdash;as well as updates to our teams, services, and fees&mdash;that position Crossref for success over the next quarter century as essential open scholarly infrastructure. In our <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/bm6g0-gvy36" target="_blank">update at the end of 2024</a>, we highlighted that we had restructured our leadership team and paused some projects. The changes made in 2024 positioned us for a year of getting things done in 2025. We launched cross-functional programs, modernised our systems, strengthened connections with our growing global community, and streamlined a bunch of technical and business operations while continuing to grow our staff, members, content, relationships, and community connections.</p>
        <p>Read on for the highlights of a very busy year, grouped around our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/strategy/">four strategic themes</a>.</p>
        <h2 id="strategic-theme-1-contribute-to-an-environment-where-the-community-identifies-and-co-creates-solutions-for-broad-benefit">Strategic theme 1: Contribute to an environment where the community identifies and co-creates solutions for broad benefit</h2>
        <h3 id="enhanced-tools-and-services">Enhanced tools and services</h3>
        <p>In October, we released an <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/8d5ga-2n897" target="_blank">enhanced Participation Reports dashboard</a> that shows metadata coverage across all 180 million records and provides individual member organisations with actionable gap reports to guide them to improve metadata completeness. The new tool provides more complete coverage of all members and resource types, now including funders and grants, with up to 11 best-practice metadata elements publicly tracked.</p>
        <p>We launched support for journal articles in the <a href="https://manage.crossref.org/" target="_blank">New Metadata Manager record registration form</a> (initially only for grants), which includes built-in reference and relationships deposit capabilities. In the New Metadata Manager, it’s now also possible to search for previously registered DOIs to edit your metadata records. In the coming years, we are planning to expand the new Metadata Manager to support all the many different content types that you can register with Crossref DOIs.</p>
        <p>After a long break between regular updates, we have fixed our process for and <a href="https://gitlab.com/crossref/open_funder_registry" target="_blank">just released v.1.63 of the Open Funder registry</a>. With the updated process, we&rsquo;re now able to resume more frequent updates to the registry (while of course still working towards the transition to ROR for funders).</p>
        <p>Throughout 2025, we conducted a website information architecture review to improve the information we provide to our members and the wider community. Based on the recommendations from this review, we will be renewing our website and documentation in 2026.</p>
        <h3 id="deprecations-and-modernisation">Deprecations and modernisation</h3>
        <p>‘Old’ Metadata Manager is to be <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/ys7s6-pwn71" target="_blank">retired at the end of 2025</a>, with users transitioning to the &lsquo;New&rsquo; version or to our other helper tools for registering and updating DOIs. All users have been contacted during 2025 and received <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WN3M90LKNqs" target="_blank">training on how to use the New Metadata Manager</a>.</p>
        <p>We also <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/w6pw6-c7y02" target="_blank">announced the deprecation of Co-access</a>, which will end in 2026, bringing an end to the service that allowed duplicate DOIs for book content. Users of co-access have been informed and are in the process of transitioning to <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/register-maintain-records/creating-and-managing-dois/multiple-resolution/">multiple resolution</a>.</p>
        <p>Together with Turnitin and our members, we are working to transition all subscribers to our Similarity Check service to a new version of iThenticate 2.0. We are happy to report that all platforms with integrations with us transitioned to 2.0 during 2025, and we will continue working with our members to get everyone transitioned during 2026.</p>
        <h3 id="eating-our-own-doi-dogfood">Eating our own DOI dogfood</h3>
        <p>In June this year, we were particularly pleased to finally <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/552ec-b8g03" target="_blank">support the registration of DOIs for our own content, this very blog</a>, through partnering with Rogue Scholar. Blogs are a growing format for scholarly discourse and our own blog is no different as it’s the main way that we share guidelines and best practices, as well as news and stories from the scholarly community. With a Crossref DOI for all blogs going back to 2006, we’re setting ourselves up to ensure better future preservation of the discussion and information about Crossref.</p>
        <h3 id="community-connections">Community connections</h3>
        <p>We delivered 29 metadata health-check webinars over the course of the year, in French, Indonesian, Spanish, and English, reaching 2,166 participants with practical advice on identifying gaps in journal metadata using <a href="https://www.crossref.org/members/prep/" target="_blank">Participation Reports</a>.</p>
        <p><a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/x38ew-0n632" target="_blank">Crossref Accra</a> took place in March as our first in-person event in a <a href="https://www.crossref.org/gem/">GEM</a> country. We also held similar events in Ecuador and Türkiye with <a href="https://zenodo.org/records/17251274" target="_blank">Crossref Quito</a> in September and <a href="https://zenodo.org/records/17952555" target="_blank">Crossref Ankara</a> in November. At these three events, we welcomed key figures from each country&rsquo;s library, government, publishing, and academic communities and we learned so much about the thriving communities there, and also that even more dedicated workshops on the specifics of metadata quality improvements would be appreciated.</p>
        <p>Our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/events/metadata-sprint/">metadata sprint in Madrid</a> in April brought together community members to tackle specific problems collaboratively, with teams exploring coding, documentation, translation, and research using our open metadata. We&rsquo;re already planning our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/events/metadata-sprint/">next sprint in São Paulo</a> for March 2026, and it will be held in three languages: Portuguese, Spanish, and English.</p>
        <p>A strategic goal for Crossref is to grow research funders’ adoption of the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/">Grant Linking System</a>, and we produced the first in a series of interviews with funder members this year to highlight how and why Crossref DOIs are fulfilling goals to assess the reach and return of their research support for <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/n9n69-y5b75" target="_blank">FWF</a> (Austria), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69" target="_blank">NWO</a> (Netherlands), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/9gjfp-5p698" target="_blank">FCCN|FCT</a> (Portugal), and <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/c1dh8-qn968" target="_blank">Wellcome</a>. This year, we welcomed more funders including Fonds de recherche du Québec (Canada) and Independent Research Fund Denmark as part of their national research platform NORA; we look forward to reporting on their experiences and outcomes next year and others as they work towards Crossref Grant DOI adoption.</p>
        <p>We continued working closely with PKP and <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/r2zgm-99706" target="_blank">renewed our partnership to help drive better experience for OJS users</a> registering metadata with Crossref. We also delivered a proportion of the metadata health-checks together to maximise the learning opportunities for our members using OJS; and we joined PKP Sprint in Oslo to help make improvements to OJS and OMP.</p>
        <p>Crossref staff members serve on almost 50 committees, boards, and other community bodies alongside our own direct work. These include in the areas of research integrity, metascience, metadata and PID standards, open science policy or monitoring, development of new models (such as Diamond OA), editorial production, library and institutional publishing, and citation and other metadata analyses. We also work with other DOI Registration Agencies and support the sustainability of the DOI Foundation with an additional annual subsidy. Many DOI RAs are also Crossref Sponsors so that their members can access our unique reference matching service. While we often might advise, we also learn a huge amount from collaborating with the numerous systems and initiatives that make up thw wider research community.</p>
        <p>Our involvement with developing the <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/" target="_blank">Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information</a> led us to become the fiscal host and to participate in most of the working groups on open metadata. Of particular note this year was the Funding Metadata Working Group round table about <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/" target="_blank">moving forward the state of funding metadata</a>, which we co-hosted with Barcelona Declaration colleagues, and three funding bodies, NWO (Netherlands), FWF (Austria), and ANR (France) as we heard from publishers and their vendors about challenges and how to overcome them to increase the quantity and quality of available open funding metadata.</p>
        <p>All our community engagement activities have been enthusiastically supported and enriched by our indispensable <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/our-ambassadors/">Ambassadors</a> and our group of now 130 <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/sponsors/">Sponsors</a>, organisations that help thousands of Crossref members with local language and technical support and lower cost access to our membership.</p>
        <h2 id="strategic-theme-2-a-sustainable-source-of-complete-open-and-global-scholarly-metadata-and-relationships">Strategic theme 2: A sustainable source of complete, open, and global scholarly metadata and relationships</h2>
        <h3 id="schema-developments">Schema developments</h3>
        <p>The <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/grants-schema/">grant schema version 0.2.0 was released in January</a>, adding support for ROR identifiers to identify funders and new funding types for in our taxonomy, including APC, BPC, and infrastructure. All of these funding types can be specified in the metadata of our grant-giving members alongside the existing types such as use of facilities or salary/training awards, etc.</p>
        <p>Version <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/325070" target="_blank">5.4 of our publications schema was released in March</a>, marking our first update in many years and a great opportunity to learn how to do this and make the process more efficient. This release introduced typed references to denote the type of object referenced (dataset, blog, software, etc.), preprint status indicators, and version numbering.</p>
        <p>Just last week, we also added a dedicated field for <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/funding-information">grant DOIs to our publications schema</a>. This means it’s now possible to indicate in an article&rsquo;s metadata which grant(s) funded the research using the persistent identifier. This is an essential step toward better alignment between grant funding and research, enriching the Research Nexus.</p>
        <p>We also launched our new <a href="https://www.crossref.org/working-groups/metadata-advisory/">Metadata Advisory Group</a> and they have already devised sub-working groups in the three focus topic areas:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Multilingual metadata</li>
        <li>Subjects and keywords</li>
        <li>Relationships</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="public-data-file">Public data file</h3>
        <p>We released the <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/614659" target="_blank">2025 public data file</a> in March, containing metadata for (at the time) over 165 million research outputs from more than 22,000 organisations.</p>
        <h3 id="inaugural-metadata-awards">Inaugural Metadata Awards</h3>
        <p>In May, we launched the <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/xh94q-w7335" target="_blank">first-ever Metadata Awards</a> to recognise members demonstrating excellence in metadata completeness and enrichment. Winners included <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/v2v2s-r9037" target="_blank">Noyam Publishers</a> (Ghana), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/z2qhj-7nd90" target="_blank">GigaScience Press</a> (Hong Kong), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/3gcdf-23s29" target="_blank">eLife</a> (UK), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/xxwy3-xhf38" target="_blank">American Society for Microbiology</a> (USA), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/51bv6-89j85" target="_blank">Universidad La Salle Arequipa</a> (Peru), and <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/hkxmk-5qe50" target="_blank">Instituto Geologico y Minero de España</a> (Spain). The awards will be held biennially going forward.</p>
        <h3 id="metadata-matching-project">Metadata Matching project</h3>
        <p>In April, we launched the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/">metadata matching</a> project with the aim of building a more complete picture of <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/">the research nexus</a> over time by automatically identifying missing relationships between entities across the scholarly record. The project’s goal is to modernise Crossref’s enrichment workflows by rebuilding them using modern software development and data science practices.</p>
        <p>We are in the throws of developing a consolidated matching workflow that will eventually replace all existing production matching processes, with results exposed through the REST API. All new matching strategies will be rigorously evaluated, and the resulting data will be accompanied by clear provenance information. This project covers six matching tasks:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>bibliographic reference matching</li>
        <li>funder name matching</li>
        <li>preprint matching</li>
        <li>affiliation matching</li>
        <li>grant matching</li>
        <li>title matching</li>
        </ul>
        <p>In the meantime, while work continues on integrating matching results into the REST API, we’ve been releasing standalone matching datasets for separate download and analysis. These include <a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15124417" target="_blank">relationships between preprints and journal articles</a>, <a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993" target="_blank">relationships involving research organisations</a>, and <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/waej1een" target="_blank">relationships between grants and research outputs</a>.</p>
        <h3 id="data-infrastructure-and-research-nexus-participation-dashboard">Data infrastructure and Research Nexus participation dashboard</h3>
        <p>Staying on the data science front, we’ve established an internal data environment that combines all relevant data sources (scholarly metadata, logs and usage data, and external datasets) in their raw forms into a single place. This environment is supported by a suite of modern tools and data processing techniques, enabling data science experiments and analytics pipelines to run effectively at scale.</p>
        <p>Building on this foundation, we plan to develop a series of dashboards to monitor the state of the scholarly record over time. These dashboards will feature both work-level and member-level statistics (for example, how many works of a given type have been registered, or how many members are registering grant IDs) as well as more detailed insights at the relationship level (for example, how many bibliographic references have been automatically matched, or how many times ROR IDs are included in funder assertions). Some of these <a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1jYXAILYgGWth-1lJhsJZPJJVSpyydenjK6E8fL4r1q0/edit?gid=2029795659#gid=2029795659" target="_blank">statistics are already available</a> in a public spreadsheet for now, pending the dashboard.</p>
        <h3 id="retraction-watch-integration">Retraction Watch integration</h3>
        <p>In 2023, Crossref <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/c23rw1d9" target="_blank">acquired the Retraction Watch database</a> to make it open data. Initially, this was done through sharing simple CSV files, but this year we have set up a pipeline to feed this information into our REST API, which means that Retraction Watch data is now fully available through the REST API, integrated with Crossref member-supplied retraction and correction metadata. This is the first example of Crossref integrating third-party metadata, and we&rsquo;re learning a lot about how to best incorporate other datasets in future.</p>
        <h3 id="metadata-api-and-services-improvements">Metadata API and services improvements</h3>
        <p>From 1 December 2025, we <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/wadve-3tj60" target="_blank">revised rate limits for the REST API</a> to ensure system stability whilst maintaining free access to metadata for everyone. Changes were made to the rate limits for our ‘public’ and ‘polite’ APIs, while the limits for our Metadata Plus users stayed the same. We continue to make all metadata openly available to the whole community.</p>
        <p>We also improved how information from our content system feeds into the REST API. A tool we call ‘pusher’&mdash;because it pushes information from the content system to the REST API&mdash;was rebuilt so that we now have a more reliable transfer of information between our two systems.</p>
        <p>While adding to technical improvements, we’ve also worked to better understand the use of and streamline the service offering for paid options. We’ll share more about this year’s Metadata Plus consultation soon. And based on feedback, we have already retired the ‘Query Affiliate’ service, where a handful of organisations still paid us a fee to access our XML API, whereas no credentials have been required for some time.</p>
        <h2 id="strategic-theme-3-manage-crossref-openly-and-sustainably-modernising-and-making-transparent-all-operations-so-that-we-are-accountable-to-the-communities-that-govern-us">Strategic theme 3: Manage Crossref openly and sustainably, modernising and making transparent all operations so that we are accountable to the communities that govern us</h2>
        <h3 id="infrastructure-modernisation">Infrastructure modernisation</h3>
        <div class="shortcode-divwrap align-left">
        <span><figure class="img-responsive"><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/data-centre-out.jpg"
        alt="Saying goodbye to the Crossref data centre" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </span>
        </div>
        <p>One of our biggest projects of 2025&mdash;if not <strong>the</strong> biggest&mdash;was the move from our data centre into the cloud (AWS). For 25 years, Crossref had been running a physical data centre in Massachusetts, USA, but as part of modernising our systems, it was high time to move everything into the cloud. The move to AWS took several months, but <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/wd6rx-vpq73" target="_blank">we successfully completed this move to the cloud</a> in July this year. We’re spending these last weeks of 2025 fully decommissioning our data centre, which means that we are removing all the equipment we had there and locking the door for the last time.</p>
        <p>A part of the move to AWS included moving onto an open-source database solution, PostgreSQL. This reduced our reliance on closed, costly licensed solutions, while also aligning with our POSI commitment to open-source. Running our entire system in AWS provides a more stable, modern approach to our infrastructure, but it also is expensive. We expect to spend about 2 million USD on AWS fees next year, with the majority of this cost coming from REST API usage. Some of the improvements described above will help us manage those costs and better observe traffic patterns.</p>
        <p>Our new cloud infrastructure is a bittersweet milestone: while we are happy to not have to rely on a physical presence to support a 24/7 global infrastructure, we also say a sad farewell of our much-loved and long-suffering Sys Admin, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/tim-pickard/">Tim Pickard</a>, who has been with Crossref since 2002, and has contributed significantly and unwaveringly to keeping our system up and running in the data centre. Tim will be leaving Crossref at the end of the year; we’re grateful to Tim for all his years of dedication, and we will greatly miss his impressive Hawaiian shirt game on our all-staff calls.</p>
        <p>After 25 years, it was also time to get serious about modernising our core content system, because even though it serves our community well, an older system with legacy code is a constant risk and frustration. We’ve therefore embarked on a multi-year modernisation project where we are replacing our old code piece by piece. We no longer want to have one big content system (a monolith), but are planning to identify different pieces of functionality and rebuild these as separate services (a modular, flexible, and robust approach). This year, we already managed to reconstruct some smaller pieces (for example, the ‘pusher’ mentioned above), and next year we will tackle larger projects, such as Metadata Matching and Authentication.</p>
        <p>We continue to prioritise open, timely communication for planned or unplanned service interruptions and encourage everyone to monitor our status page at <a href="https://status.crossref.org" target="_blank">status.crossref.org</a>. We’ll further hone our incident response processes in 2026, including openly posting incident reviews, and we’ll also centre system maintenance and documentation clarity in everything we do.</p>
        <h3 id="rcfs-projects">RCFS Projects</h3>
        <p>The <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/">Resourcing Crossref for Future Sustainability projects (RCFS)</a> and the work of our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/committees/membership-and-fees/">Membership &amp; Fees Committee</a> resulted in deciding not to change some things (such as the <em>basis</em> for annual membership fees), but to <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10" target="_blank">change three things about our fees, as reported in July</a>:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>A new lower membership fee tier of 200 USD for members with annual revenues/expenses of under 1000 USD - so far, this includes around 3000 members. <a href="#membership-growth-efficiencies-and-accessibility">See below</a> for more info.</li>
        <li>A removal of volume discounts to reduce complexity in our billing code; they were little used, and those who did use these were fine with the loss of the discount.</li>
        <li>A removal of the rule that only publishers of a title could register peer review reports (including comments and annotations) at the lower 0.25 USD fee for the first review; this lower fee is now available to any member to register any reviews of any other members’ works.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>A new late-breaking addition to these fee decisions is the reduction of fees for members registering Grant IDs. As of January 1st 2026, there will be no fee for back-year (BY) grant registration, to encourage the faster adoption of older grants, which are more likely to have research outputs to be matched. This will be a two-year pilot to trial how a reduced fee incentivises adoption and boosts metadata connections, and could be extended to other record types as we monitor its success and sustainability. In addition, the 2 USD fee per current-year (CY) grant record is being reduced to 1 USD in line with the next-nearest fee, this is a permanent change for the foreseeable future. More on this change in January.</p>
        <h3 id="membership-growth-efficiencies-and-accessibility">Membership growth, efficiencies, and accessibility</h3>
        <p>Crossref now serves 23,600 members across 164 countries, with continued growth particularly in Asia and Latin America. We&rsquo;ve continued our ongoing member onboarding activities to support new members joining the community. We see around 230 new members join each month, and have welcomed 2,700 this year so far. We recently reported on how the <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/tch5n-9px70" target="_blank">shape of membership has evolved over our 25 years</a> of operation.</p>
        <p>From January 2026, we&rsquo;re introducing a <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/j2bgz-v7h50" target="_blank">new lower membership fee tier</a> of 200 USD for organisations with annual revenue or expenses of 1,000 USD or less, making membership more accessible to low-resourced organisations. Already, over 3000 members have been eligible to move into or join under that fee, and the idea is to monitor how this affects Crossref’s financial sustainability and potentially adjust the 200 USD annual fee down again in future years.</p>
        <p>From 1 January 2026, the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/gem/">GEM program, which offers fee-free membership and content registration for all members from certain countries, will expand</a> to include 19 additional countries, further reducing financial barriers to participation in the scholarly record, so we expect several hundred further members to join the existing 600 organisations in this category.</p>
        <p>As our membership base continues to grow, the Membership and Finance teams are constantly exploring ways to make shared processes more efficient. A key component in this work has been the efforts to automate several tasks within both teams to help us manage the additional work caused by our growth and allow our teams to focus more on providing the best quality service we can.</p>
        <p>In March, the board voted to <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/dtrvw-8cm10" target="_blank">update membership terms and bylaws</a> to clarify processes for suspending and revoking membership, and to be more explicit about <a href="https://www.crossref.org/operations-and-sustainability/membership-operations/member-practices/">member practices that preserve the integrity of the scholarly record</a>. A short-term Member Practices Working Group will be meeting in the first half of 2026 to draft these.</p>
        <p>Our membership team continues to support our members, sponsors, service providers, metadata users and the wider community by email and through our <a href="https://community.crossref.org/" target="_blank">community forum</a>. The membership team includes staff members who focus on member support, and staff members who focus on technical support. During 2025 so far, we’ve received 36.8k member enquiries through our support system, a 17% increase from last year. This includes 22.6k inquiries related to general membership and 13k technical support enquiries. We’ve received 3.8k membership applications, and welcomed 2.7k new members.</p>
        <h3 id="growth-by-the-numbers">Growth by the numbers</h3>
        <p>Crossref continues its steady revenue growth in 2025 due to the expansion of our membership base. With the addition of new members and the general growth of Crossref, comes an increase in the transaction-based tasks our Finance team handles.</p>
        <p>So far in 2025 we have issued 14,833 invoices, which is a 9% increase since last year. We’ve seen an 11% increase in the number of payments received and applied, and a 12% increase in the amount of credit and debit memos applied over the same time last year. We have also seen a 42% increase in the number of billing-related tickets, totalling 20,723. A large segment of these tickets are related to fee updates associated with the new $200 membership tier.</p>
        <p>Not all transactional work in Finance has increased as steadily, with increased revenue of 8% we have also seen a 14% increase in operating expenses. Through the strategic consolidation of vendors and use of financial tools, we have only seen a 1% increase in Accounts Payable invoices processed.</p>
        <h3 id="organisational-sustainability">Organisational sustainability</h3>
        <p>Finance-wise, we’re doing well. We’re projecting to finish this year with revenue of 14,200,000 USD and expect revenue next year of 14,500,000 USD. We’re budgeting 2% growth in overall revenue, accounting for some of the changes to fees that will reduce our earnings on membership dues, but anticipating continued growth of content registration revenue.</p>
        <figure class="img-responsive"><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/financials/2024-YE-overall.jpg"
        alt="A chart showing Crossref&#39;s Revenue and expenses over the years" width="100%"><figcaption>
        <p>Revenue and expenses trends</p>
        </figcaption>
        </figure>
        <p>About 67% of our expenses come from personnel costs, and the other 33% include non-personnel costs like AWS, travel, legal fees, etc. As we continue to build out the team, we have ten new positions planned for the next year (recruitment for many of these is already underway or done). With additional staff roles and AWS expenses, we’re expecting expense growth of 16%. We post our financial statements and Form 990 filings on the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/operations-and-sustainability/financials">financials page on our website</a>.</p>
        <figure class="img-responsive"><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/financials/2024-rev-by-tier.jpg"
        alt="A chart showing revenue per member size (by tier) with smallest members providing highest revenue" width="100%"><figcaption>
        <p>Revenue per member size (by tier)</p>
        </figcaption>
        </figure>
        <p>As the chart above shows, we still &rsquo;the long tail&rsquo; of members in the smallest category (275 USD) contributing more revenue than those in the largest category (50,000 USD) at 5.8 million USD versus 5 million USD.</p>
        <p>Another aspect of sustainability is our impact on the world around us. And this year we were able to publish a second <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/4yc7f-4h586" target="_blank">report on Crossref’s carbon footprint</a>, having monitored and controlled for several carbon-heavy activities, primarily staff travel. Our reported emissions went up 40% from 2023 to 2024, due to more travel given our growth in staff and members, better recording our emissions (for example, with hotel stays), and including travel that we support for our partners, ambassadors and board members. In terms of travel spending, we are still well below 2019 when we were smaller, demonstrating that we are following through on not going back to the pre-pandemic norm.</p>
        <p>We were one of the first open infrastructure organisations to adopt the POSI Principles and now have a few years’ experience in trying to meet them. Together with other adopters, we <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/6148078" target="_blank">proposed updates and additions to the principles</a>, based on real-world practice, and gathered a lot of community comment, resulting in the group <a href="https://doi.org/10.14454/G8WV-VM65" target="_blank">publishing POSI v2</a> in October. We conduct a <a href="https://www.crossref.org/categories/posi">self-assessment</a> every other year and we’ll be involving all our staff in the next self-assessment, due later in 2026.</p>
        <h3 id="open-governance-through-board-election-and-annual-meeting">Open governance through board election and annual meeting</h3>
        <p>We continued our commitment to being member-led and community-driven. This year’s <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/0team-dyy285" target="_blank">anniversary Annual Meeting</a> in October brought together members to discuss strategy, metadata developments, and hear the results of their voting in our board election. It comprised two half-days of online conferencing and several in-person satellite meetings spread across five continents, gathering close to 500 members of our community. It was a platform to reflect together on the past quarter of the century of building community infrastructure and connections underpinning the progress of scholarship, and to share plans for the future.</p>
        <p>Each member has one vote, and together they elected the following organisations to serve a three-year term alongside the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#board-members">rest of the board</a>:</p>
        <p>Tier 1 candidates (electing one seat):</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Rebecca Wambua, Distance, Open and e-Learning Practitioners&rsquo; Association of Kenya</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Tier 2 candidates (electing four seats):</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Damian Bird, CABI</li>
        <li>Rose L&rsquo;Huillier, Elsevier*</li>
        <li>Anjalie Nawaratne, Springer Nature*</li>
        <li>Nick Lindsay, The MIT Press*</li>
        </ul>
        <p>*returning board member</p>
        <p>Congratulations to the remaining and incoming board members as we start their new term in January 2026. Have a look at <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/431937misogo" target="_blank">all the outputs from our Annual Meeting</a>.</p>
        <h2 id="strategic-theme-4-foster-a-strong-teambecause-reliable-infrastructure-needs-committed-people-who-contribute-to-and-realise-the-vision-and-thrive-doing-it">Strategic theme 4: Foster a strong team—because reliable infrastructure needs committed people who contribute to and realise the vision, and thrive doing it</h2>
        <h3 id="team-structure">Team structure</h3>
        <p>We reorganised the team heading into 2025 because we had ambitious goals that required a more structured, collaborative approach. We reorganised the work around three strategic, mission-driven areas of focus described above. This was our first full year with the <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/4s2ee-wkr84" target="_blank">cross-functional program groups</a> in place, and the activities reported here make it evident that our team members, both existing and new, are firing on all cylinders.</p>
        <h3 id="new-staff-and-new-roles">New staff and new roles</h3>
        <p>We welcomed eight new team members in 2025. In February, we welcomed our new Director of Programs &amp; Services, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/helena-cousijn">Helena Cousijn</a>, and a new member of the Technical Support team, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/arley-soto">Arley Soto</a>. In March, we welcomed our new Community Manager for funders, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/roc%C3%ADo-gaudioso-pedraza">Rocío Gaudioso Pedraza</a>. In April, we <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/6e4f8-3yj41" target="_blank">launched our new Data Science team</a> by welcoming <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/jason-portenoy">Jason Portenoy</a> and <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/alex-b%C3%A9dard-vall%C3%A9e">Alex Bédard-Vallée</a>. In November, we welcomed our new DevOps Engineer, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/thelma-laryea">Thelma Laryea,</a> and our new Program Technical Lead for the OSO program, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/bharath-govindarajan">Bharath Govindarajan.</a> In December, we welcomed another member of the Technical Support team, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/natali-giorgobiani">Natali Giorgobiani</a>.</p>
        <p>We also had team members step up into new roles. <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/dominika-tkaczyk">Dominika Tkaczyk</a> completed the new leadership team by taking on the Director of Technology role, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/paul-davis">Paul Davis </a>has started his new role as Product Manager, and <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/michelle-cancel/">Michelle Cancel</a> has taken on the Head of Human Resources role. And there’s more to come! As next year begins, two team members will step into Program Technical Lead roles: <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/carlos-del-ojo-elias">Carlos del Ojo Elias</a> for the CRN program and <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/patrick-vale">Patrick Vale</a> for the CCT program. Together with the Program Technical Lead for the OSO program and the Head of Infrastructure Services, these roles will complete the new structure of the technology team. This structure is more closely aligned with how our work is organised and will enable stronger coordination both within and across cross-functional programs.</p>
        <h3 id="supporting-a-thriving-global-culture">Supporting a thriving global culture</h3>
        <p>As our team grows in different aspects within our new <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/org-chart/">org structure</a> to meet the needs of the community, we remain committed to supporting a thriving culture through training, conducting regular temperature checks, and organising our annual staff retreat. This year, we continued our work on psychological safety and introduced workshops on giving and receiving feedback and on consensus building. We were able to put some of this training into practice at our in-person all-staff event in Split, Croatia, where we all came together to <a href="https://roadmap.productboard.com/e6fdeba8-a5b3-4aef-8104-d48863ba975e" target="_blank">build our roadmap</a>.</p>
        <p>We are ending the year with 51 staff in 14 countries and look forward to diversifying and evolving even further as a team in 2026&mdash;we’re currently hiring in UX, Communications, and Membership&mdash;and keep an eye on our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/jobs">jobs</a> page for forthcoming opportunities in Software, DevOps, Metadata, and Operations!</p>
        <hr>
        <p>Thank you to our community of members, partners, board, ambassadors, sponsors, metadata users, service providers, integrators—and of course our team—for making 2025 such a productive year. Together, we&rsquo;re building a richer, more connected research ecosystem for the benefit of society. We can’t wait to continue the work together in 2026.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>As we finish [celebrating our 25th anniversary](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/25years/), we can look back on a truly transformational year, defined by the successful delivery of several long-planned, foundational projects—as well as updates to our teams, services, and fees—that position Crossref for success over the next quarter century as essential open scholarly infrastructure. In our [update at the end of 2024](https://doi.org/10.64000/bm6g0-gvy36), we highlighted that we had restructured our leadership team and paused some projects. The changes made in 2024 positioned us for a year of getting things done in 2025. We launched cross-functional programs, modernised our systems, strengthened connections with our growing global community, and streamlined a bunch of technical and business operations while continuing to grow our staff, members, content, relationships, and community connections.

Read on for the highlights of a very busy year, grouped around our [four strategic themes](https://www.crossref.org/strategy/).

## Strategic theme 1: Contribute to an environment where the community identifies and co-creates solutions for broad benefit

### Enhanced tools and services

In October, we released an [enhanced Participation Reports dashboard](https://doi.org/10.64000/8d5ga-2n897) that shows metadata coverage across all 180 million records and provides individual member organisations with actionable gap reports to guide them to improve metadata completeness. The new tool provides more complete coverage of all members and resource types, now including funders and grants, with up to 11 best-practice metadata elements publicly tracked.

We launched support for journal articles in the [New Metadata Manager record registration form](https://manage.crossref.org/) (initially only for grants), which includes built-in reference and relationships deposit capabilities. In the New Metadata Manager, it’s now also possible to search for previously registered DOIs to edit your metadata records. In the coming years, we are planning to expand the new Metadata Manager to support all the many different content types that you can register with Crossref DOIs.

After a long break between regular updates, we have fixed our process for and [just released v.1.63 of the Open Funder registry](https://gitlab.com/crossref/open_funder_registry). With the updated process, we’re now able to resume more frequent updates to the registry (while of course still working towards the transition to ROR for funders).

Throughout 2025, we conducted a website information architecture review to improve the information we provide to our members and the wider community. Based on the recommendations from this review, we will be renewing our website and documentation in 2026.

### Deprecations and modernisation

‘Old’ Metadata Manager is to be [retired at the end of 2025](https://doi.org/10.64000/ys7s6-pwn71), with users transitioning to the ‘New’ version or to our other helper tools for registering and updating DOIs. All users have been contacted during 2025 and received [training on how to use the New Metadata Manager](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WN3M90LKNqs).

We also [announced the deprecation of Co-access](https://doi.org/10.64000/w6pw6-c7y02), which will end in 2026, bringing an end to the service that allowed duplicate DOIs for book content. Users of co-access have been informed and are in the process of transitioning to [multiple resolution](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/register-maintain-records/creating-and-managing-dois/multiple-resolution/).

Together with Turnitin and our members, we are working to transition all subscribers to our Similarity Check service to a new version of iThenticate 2.0. We are happy to report that all platforms with integrations with us transitioned to 2.0 during 2025, and we will continue working with our members to get everyone transitioned during 2026.

### Eating our own DOI dogfood

In June this year, we were particularly pleased to finally [support the registration of DOIs for our own content, this very blog](https://doi.org/10.64000/552ec-b8g03), through partnering with Rogue Scholar. Blogs are a growing format for scholarly discourse and our own blog is no different as it’s the main way that we share guidelines and best practices, as well as news and stories from the scholarly community. With a Crossref DOI for all blogs going back to 2006, we’re setting ourselves up to ensure better future preservation of the discussion and information about Crossref.

### Community connections

We delivered 29 metadata health-check webinars over the course of the year, in French, Indonesian, Spanish, and English, reaching 2,166 participants with practical advice on identifying gaps in journal metadata using [Participation Reports](https://www.crossref.org/members/prep/).

[Crossref Accra](https://doi.org/10.64000/x38ew-0n632) took place in March as our first in-person event in a [GEM](https://www.crossref.org/gem/) country. We also held similar events in Ecuador and Türkiye with [Crossref Quito](https://zenodo.org/records/17251274) in September and [Crossref Ankara](https://zenodo.org/records/17952555) in November. At these three events, we welcomed key figures from each country’s library, government, publishing, and academic communities and we learned so much about the thriving communities there, and also that even more dedicated workshops on the specifics of metadata quality improvements would be appreciated.

Our [metadata sprint in Madrid](https://www.crossref.org/events/metadata-sprint/) in April brought together community members to tackle specific problems collaboratively, with teams exploring coding, documentation, translation, and research using our open metadata. We’re already planning our [next sprint in São Paulo](https://www.crossref.org/events/metadata-sprint/) for March 2026, and it will be held in three languages: Portuguese, Spanish, and English.

A strategic goal for Crossref is to grow research funders’ adoption of the [Grant Linking System](https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/), and we produced the first in a series of interviews with funder members this year to highlight how and why Crossref DOIs are fulfilling goals to assess the reach and return of their research support for [FWF](https://doi.org/10.64000/n9n69-y5b75) (Austria), [NWO](https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69) (Netherlands), [FCCN\|FCT](https://doi.org/10.64000/9gjfp-5p698) (Portugal), and [Wellcome](https://doi.org/10.64000/c1dh8-qn968). This year, we welcomed more funders including Fonds de recherche du Québec (Canada) and Independent Research Fund Denmark as part of their national research platform NORA; we look forward to reporting on their experiences and outcomes next year and others as they work towards Crossref Grant DOI adoption.

We continued working closely with PKP and [renewed our partnership to help drive better experience for OJS users](https://doi.org/10.64000/r2zgm-99706) registering metadata with Crossref. We also delivered a proportion of the metadata health-checks together to maximise the learning opportunities for our members using OJS; and we joined PKP Sprint in Oslo to help make improvements to OJS and OMP.

Crossref staff members serve on almost 50 committees, boards, and other community bodies alongside our own direct work. These include in the areas of research integrity, metascience, metadata and PID standards, open science policy or monitoring, development of new models (such as Diamond OA), editorial production, library and institutional publishing, and citation and other metadata analyses. We also work with other DOI Registration Agencies and support the sustainability of the DOI Foundation with an additional annual subsidy. Many DOI RAs are also Crossref Sponsors so that their members can access our unique reference matching service. While we often might advise, we also learn a huge amount from collaborating with the numerous systems and initiatives that make up thw wider research community.

Our involvement with developing the [Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information](https://barcelona-declaration.org/) led us to become the fiscal host and to participate in most of the working groups on open metadata. Of particular note this year was the Funding Metadata Working Group round table about [moving forward the state of funding metadata](https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/), which we co-hosted with Barcelona Declaration colleagues, and three funding bodies, NWO (Netherlands), FWF (Austria), and ANR (France) as we heard from publishers and their vendors about challenges and how to overcome them to increase the quantity and quality of available open funding metadata.

All our community engagement activities have been enthusiastically supported and enriched by our indispensable [Ambassadors](https://www.crossref.org/community/our-ambassadors/) and our group of now 130 [Sponsors](https://www.crossref.org/community/sponsors/), organisations that help thousands of Crossref members with local language and technical support and lower cost access to our membership.

## Strategic theme 2: A sustainable source of complete, open, and global scholarly metadata and relationships

### Schema developments

The [grant schema version 0.2.0 was released in January](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/grants-schema/), adding support for ROR identifiers to identify funders and new funding types for in our taxonomy, including APC, BPC, and infrastructure. All of these funding types can be specified in the metadata of our grant-giving members alongside the existing types such as use of facilities or salary/training awards, etc.

Version [5.4 of our publications schema was released in March](https://doi.org/10.13003/325070), marking our first update in many years and a great opportunity to learn how to do this and make the process more efficient. This release introduced typed references to denote the type of object referenced (dataset, blog, software, etc.), preprint status indicators, and version numbering.

Just last week, we also added a dedicated field for [grant DOIs to our publications schema](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/funding-information). This means it’s now possible to indicate in an article’s metadata which grant(s) funded the research using the persistent identifier. This is an essential step toward better alignment between grant funding and research, enriching the Research Nexus.

We also launched our new [Metadata Advisory Group](https://www.crossref.org/working-groups/metadata-advisory/) and they have already devised sub-working groups in the three focus topic areas:

- Multilingual metadata
- Subjects and keywords
- Relationships

### Public data file

We released the [2025 public data file](https://doi.org/10.13003/614659) in March, containing metadata for (at the time) over 165 million research outputs from more than 22,000 organisations.

### Inaugural Metadata Awards

In May, we launched the [first-ever Metadata Awards](https://doi.org/10.64000/xh94q-w7335) to recognise members demonstrating excellence in metadata completeness and enrichment. Winners included [Noyam Publishers](https://doi.org/10.64000/v2v2s-r9037) (Ghana), [GigaScience Press](https://doi.org/10.64000/z2qhj-7nd90) (Hong Kong), [eLife](https://doi.org/10.64000/3gcdf-23s29) (UK), [American Society for Microbiology](https://doi.org/10.64000/xxwy3-xhf38) (USA), [Universidad La Salle Arequipa](https://doi.org/10.64000/51bv6-89j85) (Peru), and [Instituto Geologico y Minero de España](https://doi.org/10.64000/hkxmk-5qe50) (Spain). The awards will be held biennially going forward.

### Metadata Matching project

In April, we launched the [metadata matching](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/) project with the aim of building a more complete picture of [the research nexus](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/) over time by automatically identifying missing relationships between entities across the scholarly record. The project’s goal is to modernise Crossref’s enrichment workflows by rebuilding them using modern software development and data science practices.

We are in the throws of developing a consolidated matching workflow that will eventually replace all existing production matching processes, with results exposed through the REST API. All new matching strategies will be rigorously evaluated, and the resulting data will be accompanied by clear provenance information. This project covers six matching tasks:

- bibliographic reference matching
- funder name matching
- preprint matching
- affiliation matching
- grant matching
- title matching

In the meantime, while work continues on integrating matching results into the REST API, we’ve been releasing standalone matching datasets for separate download and analysis. These include [relationships between preprints and journal articles](https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15124417), [relationships involving research organisations](https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993), and [relationships between grants and research outputs](https://doi.org/10.13003/waej1een).

### Data infrastructure and Research Nexus participation dashboard

Staying on the data science front, we’ve established an internal data environment that combines all relevant data sources (scholarly metadata, logs and usage data, and external datasets) in their raw forms into a single place. This environment is supported by a suite of modern tools and data processing techniques, enabling data science experiments and analytics pipelines to run effectively at scale.

Building on this foundation, we plan to develop a series of dashboards to monitor the state of the scholarly record over time. These dashboards will feature both work-level and member-level statistics (for example, how many works of a given type have been registered, or how many members are registering grant IDs) as well as more detailed insights at the relationship level (for example, how many bibliographic references have been automatically matched, or how many times ROR IDs are included in funder assertions). Some of these [statistics are already available](https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1jYXAILYgGWth-1lJhsJZPJJVSpyydenjK6E8fL4r1q0/edit?gid=2029795659#gid=2029795659) in a public spreadsheet for now, pending the dashboard.

### Retraction Watch integration

In 2023, Crossref [acquired the Retraction Watch database](https://doi.org/10.13003/c23rw1d9) to make it open data. Initially, this was done through sharing simple CSV files, but this year we have set up a pipeline to feed this information into our REST API, which means that Retraction Watch data is now fully available through the REST API, integrated with Crossref member-supplied retraction and correction metadata. This is the first example of Crossref integrating third-party metadata, and we’re learning a lot about how to best incorporate other datasets in future.

### Metadata API and services improvements

From 1 December 2025, we [revised rate limits for the REST API](https://doi.org/10.64000/wadve-3tj60) to ensure system stability whilst maintaining free access to metadata for everyone. Changes were made to the rate limits for our ‘public’ and ‘polite’ APIs, while the limits for our Metadata Plus users stayed the same. We continue to make all metadata openly available to the whole community.

We also improved how information from our content system feeds into the REST API. A tool we call ‘pusher’—because it pushes information from the content system to the REST API—was rebuilt so that we now have a more reliable transfer of information between our two systems.

While adding to technical improvements, we’ve also worked to better understand the use of and streamline the service offering for paid options. We’ll share more about this year’s Metadata Plus consultation soon. And based on feedback, we have already retired the ‘Query Affiliate’ service, where a handful of organisations still paid us a fee to access our XML API, whereas no credentials have been required for some time.

## Strategic theme 3: Manage Crossref openly and sustainably, modernising and making transparent all operations so that we are accountable to the communities that govern us

### Infrastructure modernisation

![Saying goodbye to the Crossref data centre](https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/data-centre-out.jpg)

One of our biggest projects of 2025—if not **the** biggest—was the move from our data centre into the cloud (AWS). For 25 years, Crossref had been running a physical data centre in Massachusetts, USA, but as part of modernising our systems, it was high time to move everything into the cloud. The move to AWS took several months, but [we successfully completed this move to the cloud](https://doi.org/10.64000/wd6rx-vpq73) in July this year. We’re spending these last weeks of 2025 fully decommissioning our data centre, which means that we are removing all the equipment we had there and locking the door for the last time.

A part of the move to AWS included moving onto an open-source database solution, PostgreSQL. This reduced our reliance on closed, costly licensed solutions, while also aligning with our POSI commitment to open-source. Running our entire system in AWS provides a more stable, modern approach to our infrastructure, but it also is expensive. We expect to spend about 2 million USD on AWS fees next year, with the majority of this cost coming from REST API usage. Some of the improvements described above will help us manage those costs and better observe traffic patterns.

Our new cloud infrastructure is a bittersweet milestone: while we are happy to not have to rely on a physical presence to support a 24/7 global infrastructure, we also say a sad farewell of our much-loved and long-suffering Sys Admin, [Tim Pickard](https://www.crossref.org/people/tim-pickard/), who has been with Crossref since 2002, and has contributed significantly and unwaveringly to keeping our system up and running in the data centre. Tim will be leaving Crossref at the end of the year; we’re grateful to Tim for all his years of dedication, and we will greatly miss his impressive Hawaiian shirt game on our all-staff calls.

After 25 years, it was also time to get serious about modernising our core content system, because even though it serves our community well, an older system with legacy code is a constant risk and frustration. We’ve therefore embarked on a multi-year modernisation project where we are replacing our old code piece by piece. We no longer want to have one big content system (a monolith), but are planning to identify different pieces of functionality and rebuild these as separate services (a modular, flexible, and robust approach). This year, we already managed to reconstruct some smaller pieces (for example, the ‘pusher’ mentioned above), and next year we will tackle larger projects, such as Metadata Matching and Authentication.

We continue to prioritise open, timely communication for planned or unplanned service interruptions and encourage everyone to monitor our status page at [status.crossref.org](https://status.crossref.org). We’ll further hone our incident response processes in 2026, including openly posting incident reviews, and we’ll also centre system maintenance and documentation clarity in everything we do.

### RCFS Projects

The [Resourcing Crossref for Future Sustainability projects (RCFS)](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/) and the work of our [Membership &#38; Fees Committee](https://www.crossref.org/committees/membership-and-fees/) resulted in deciding not to change some things (such as the _basis_ for annual membership fees), but to [change three things about our fees, as reported in July](https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10):

- A new lower membership fee tier of 200 USD for members with annual revenues/expenses of under 1000 USD - so far, this includes around 3000 members. [See below](#membership-growth-efficiencies-and-accessibility) for more info.
- A removal of volume discounts to reduce complexity in our billing code; they were little used, and those who did use these were fine with the loss of the discount.
- A removal of the rule that only publishers of a title could register peer review reports (including comments and annotations) at the lower 0.25 USD fee for the first review; this lower fee is now available to any member to register any reviews of any other members’ works.

A new late-breaking addition to these fee decisions is the reduction of fees for members registering Grant IDs. As of January 1st 2026, there will be no fee for back-year (BY) grant registration, to encourage the faster adoption of older grants, which are more likely to have research outputs to be matched. This will be a two-year pilot to trial how a reduced fee incentivises adoption and boosts metadata connections, and could be extended to other record types as we monitor its success and sustainability. In addition, the 2 USD fee per current-year (CY) grant record is being reduced to 1 USD in line with the next-nearest fee, this is a permanent change for the foreseeable future. More on this change in January.

### Membership growth, efficiencies, and accessibility

Crossref now serves 23,600 members across 164 countries, with continued growth particularly in Asia and Latin America. We’ve continued our ongoing member onboarding activities to support new members joining the community. We see around 230 new members join each month, and have welcomed 2,700 this year so far. We recently reported on how the [shape of membership has evolved over our 25 years](https://doi.org/10.64000/tch5n-9px70) of operation.

From January 2026, we’re introducing a [new lower membership fee tier](https://doi.org/10.64000/j2bgz-v7h50) of 200 USD for organisations with annual revenue or expenses of 1,000 USD or less, making membership more accessible to low-resourced organisations. Already, over 3000 members have been eligible to move into or join under that fee, and the idea is to monitor how this affects Crossref’s financial sustainability and potentially adjust the 200 USD annual fee down again in future years.

From 1 January 2026, the [GEM program, which offers fee-free membership and content registration for all members from certain countries, will expand](https://www.crossref.org/gem/) to include 19 additional countries, further reducing financial barriers to participation in the scholarly record, so we expect several hundred further members to join the existing 600 organisations in this category.

As our membership base continues to grow, the Membership and Finance teams are constantly exploring ways to make shared processes more efficient. A key component in this work has been the efforts to automate several tasks within both teams to help us manage the additional work caused by our growth and allow our teams to focus more on providing the best quality service we can.

In March, the board voted to [update membership terms and bylaws](https://doi.org/10.64000/dtrvw-8cm10) to clarify processes for suspending and revoking membership, and to be more explicit about [member practices that preserve the integrity of the scholarly record](https://www.crossref.org/operations-and-sustainability/membership-operations/member-practices/). A short-term Member Practices Working Group will be meeting in the first half of 2026 to draft these.

Our membership team continues to support our members, sponsors, service providers, metadata users and the wider community by email and through our [community forum](https://community.crossref.org/). The membership team includes staff members who focus on member support, and staff members who focus on technical support. During 2025 so far, we’ve received 36.8k member enquiries through our support system, a 17% increase from last year. This includes 22.6k inquiries related to general membership and 13k technical support enquiries. We’ve received 3.8k membership applications, and welcomed 2.7k new members.

### Growth by the numbers

Crossref continues its steady revenue growth in 2025 due to the expansion of our membership base. With the addition of new members and the general growth of Crossref, comes an increase in the transaction-based tasks our Finance team handles.

So far in 2025 we have issued 14,833 invoices, which is a 9% increase since last year. We’ve seen an 11% increase in the number of payments received and applied, and a 12% increase in the amount of credit and debit memos applied over the same time last year. We have also seen a 42% increase in the number of billing-related tickets, totalling 20,723. A large segment of these tickets are related to fee updates associated with the new $200 membership tier.

Not all transactional work in Finance has increased as steadily, with increased revenue of 8% we have also seen a 14% increase in operating expenses. Through the strategic consolidation of vendors and use of financial tools, we have only seen a 1% increase in Accounts Payable invoices processed.

### Organisational sustainability

Finance-wise, we’re doing well. We’re projecting to finish this year with revenue of 14,200,000 USD and expect revenue next year of 14,500,000 USD. We’re budgeting 2% growth in overall revenue, accounting for some of the changes to fees that will reduce our earnings on membership dues, but anticipating continued growth of content registration revenue.

![A chart showing Crossref&#39;s Revenue and expenses over the years](https://www.crossref.org/images/financials/2024-YE-overall.jpg)

Revenue and expenses trends

About 67% of our expenses come from personnel costs, and the other 33% include non-personnel costs like AWS, travel, legal fees, etc. As we continue to build out the team, we have ten new positions planned for the next year (recruitment for many of these is already underway or done). With additional staff roles and AWS expenses, we’re expecting expense growth of 16%. We post our financial statements and Form 990 filings on the [financials page on our website](https://www.crossref.org/operations-and-sustainability/financials).

![A chart showing revenue per member size (by tier) with smallest members providing highest revenue](https://www.crossref.org/images/financials/2024-rev-by-tier.jpg)

Revenue per member size (by tier)

As the chart above shows, we still ’the long tail’ of members in the smallest category (275 USD) contributing more revenue than those in the largest category (50,000 USD) at 5.8 million USD versus 5 million USD.

Another aspect of sustainability is our impact on the world around us. And this year we were able to publish a second [report on Crossref’s carbon footprint](https://doi.org/10.64000/4yc7f-4h586), having monitored and controlled for several carbon-heavy activities, primarily staff travel. Our reported emissions went up 40% from 2023 to 2024, due to more travel given our growth in staff and members, better recording our emissions (for example, with hotel stays), and including travel that we support for our partners, ambassadors and board members. In terms of travel spending, we are still well below 2019 when we were smaller, demonstrating that we are following through on not going back to the pre-pandemic norm.

We were one of the first open infrastructure organisations to adopt the POSI Principles and now have a few years’ experience in trying to meet them. Together with other adopters, we [proposed updates and additions to the principles](https://doi.org/10.13003/6148078), based on real-world practice, and gathered a lot of community comment, resulting in the group [publishing POSI v2](https://doi.org/10.14454/G8WV-VM65) in October. We conduct a [self-assessment](https://www.crossref.org/categories/posi) every other year and we’ll be involving all our staff in the next self-assessment, due later in 2026.

### Open governance through board election and annual meeting

We continued our commitment to being member-led and community-driven. This year’s [anniversary Annual Meeting](https://doi.org/10.64000/0team-dyy285) in October brought together members to discuss strategy, metadata developments, and hear the results of their voting in our board election. It comprised two half-days of online conferencing and several in-person satellite meetings spread across five continents, gathering close to 500 members of our community. It was a platform to reflect together on the past quarter of the century of building community infrastructure and connections underpinning the progress of scholarship, and to share plans for the future.

Each member has one vote, and together they elected the following organisations to serve a three-year term alongside the [rest of the board](https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#board-members):

Tier 1 candidates (electing one seat):

- Rebecca Wambua, Distance, Open and e-Learning Practitioners’ Association of Kenya

Tier 2 candidates (electing four seats):

- Damian Bird, CABI
- Rose L’Huillier, Elsevier\*
- Anjalie Nawaratne, Springer Nature\*
- Nick Lindsay, The MIT Press\*

\*returning board member

Congratulations to the remaining and incoming board members as we start their new term in January 2026. Have a look at [all the outputs from our Annual Meeting](https://doi.org/10.13003/431937misogo).

## Strategic theme 4: Foster a strong team—because reliable infrastructure needs committed people who contribute to and realise the vision, and thrive doing it

### Team structure

We reorganised the team heading into 2025 because we had ambitious goals that required a more structured, collaborative approach. We reorganised the work around three strategic, mission-driven areas of focus described above. This was our first full year with the [cross-functional program groups](https://doi.org/10.64000/4s2ee-wkr84) in place, and the activities reported here make it evident that our team members, both existing and new, are firing on all cylinders.

### New staff and new roles

We welcomed eight new team members in 2025. In February, we welcomed our new Director of Programs &#38; Services, [Helena Cousijn](https://www.crossref.org/people/helena-cousijn), and a new member of the Technical Support team, [Arley Soto](https://www.crossref.org/people/arley-soto). In March, we welcomed our new Community Manager for funders, [Rocío Gaudioso Pedraza](https://www.crossref.org/people/roc%C3%ADo-gaudioso-pedraza). In April, we [launched our new Data Science team](https://doi.org/10.64000/6e4f8-3yj41) by welcoming [Jason Portenoy](https://www.crossref.org/people/jason-portenoy) and [Alex Bédard-Vallée](https://www.crossref.org/people/alex-b%C3%A9dard-vall%C3%A9e). In November, we welcomed our new DevOps Engineer, [Thelma Laryea,](https://www.crossref.org/people/thelma-laryea) and our new Program Technical Lead for the OSO program, [Bharath Govindarajan.](https://www.crossref.org/people/bharath-govindarajan) In December, we welcomed another member of the Technical Support team, [Natali Giorgobiani](https://www.crossref.org/people/natali-giorgobiani).

We also had team members step up into new roles. [Dominika Tkaczyk](https://www.crossref.org/people/dominika-tkaczyk) completed the new leadership team by taking on the Director of Technology role, [Paul Davis](https://www.crossref.org/people/paul-davis) has started his new role as Product Manager, and [Michelle Cancel](https://www.crossref.org/people/michelle-cancel/) has taken on the Head of Human Resources role. And there’s more to come! As next year begins, two team members will step into Program Technical Lead roles: [Carlos del Ojo Elias](https://www.crossref.org/people/carlos-del-ojo-elias) for the CRN program and [Patrick Vale](https://www.crossref.org/people/patrick-vale) for the CCT program. Together with the Program Technical Lead for the OSO program and the Head of Infrastructure Services, these roles will complete the new structure of the technology team. This structure is more closely aligned with how our work is organised and will enable stronger coordination both within and across cross-functional programs.

### Supporting a thriving global culture

As our team grows in different aspects within our new [org structure](https://www.crossref.org/people/org-chart/) to meet the needs of the community, we remain committed to supporting a thriving culture through training, conducting regular temperature checks, and organising our annual staff retreat. This year, we continued our work on psychological safety and introduced workshops on giving and receiving feedback and on consensus building. We were able to put some of this training into practice at our in-person all-staff event in Split, Croatia, where we all came together to [build our roadmap](https://roadmap.productboard.com/e6fdeba8-a5b3-4aef-8104-d48863ba975e).

We are ending the year with 51 staff in 14 countries and look forward to diversifying and evolving even further as a team in 2026—we’re currently hiring in UX, Communications, and Membership—and keep an eye on our [jobs](https://www.crossref.org/jobs) page for forthcoming opportunities in Software, DevOps, Metadata, and Operations!

* * *

Thank you to our community of members, partners, board, ambassadors, sponsors, metadata users, service providers, integrators—and of course our team—for making 2025 such a productive year. Together, we’re building a richer, more connected research ecosystem for the benefit of society. We can’t wait to continue the work together in 2026.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/highlights-of-a-very-busy-year-our-2025-annual-report/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
