<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:source="https://source.scripting.com/">
  <atom:link href="https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Library and Archives organizations</title>
    <link>https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>16 Oct 25 06:53 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.15</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — Reporting from LIBER 2025: Policy Influence, Library Agency, and Researcher-First Open Access Moves</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/16/guest-post-reporting-from-liber-2025-policy-influence-library-agency-and-researcher-first-open-access-moves/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest bloggers reflect on the the LIBER Annual Conference in Lausanne (2–4 July).</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/16/guest-post-reporting-from-liber-2025-policy-influence-library-agency-and-researcher-first-open-access-moves/">Guest Post — Reporting from LIBER 2025: Policy Influence, Library Agency, and Researcher-First Open Access Moves</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest bloggers reflect on the the LIBER Annual Conference in Lausanne (2–4 July).

The post [Guest Post — Reporting from LIBER 2025: Policy Influence, Library Agency, and Researcher-First Open Access Moves](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/16/guest-post-reporting-from-liber-2025-policy-influence-library-agency-and-researcher-first-open-access-moves/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61097</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The White Company, by Arthur Conan Doyle</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/arthur-conan-doyle/the-white-company</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young English novice in the Middle Ages embarks on action-packed adventure as he joins a motley band of travelers seeking to join with a free company of archers.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young English novice in the Middle Ages embarks on action-packed adventure as he joins a motley band of travelers seeking to join with a free company of archers.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/arthur-conan-doyle/the-white-company/downloads/arthur-conan-doyle_the-white-company.epub?source=feed" length="750376" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/arthur-conan-doyle/the-white-company</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Shut Out by Distributors, Filmmaker Turns to Internet Archive to Share Documentary with the World</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/10/15/hacking-at-leaves/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[After Johannes Grenzfurthner began working on a new documentary in 2020, he soon realized that his original storyline was much more complicated than he first envisioned. The 50-year-old Austrian filmmaker [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>After Johannes Grenzfurthner began working on a new documentary in 2020, he soon realized that his original storyline was much more complicated than he first envisioned. The 50-year-old Austrian filmmaker \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29326</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Diamond Dreams, Unequal Realities: The Promise and Pitfalls of No-APC Open Access</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/15/diamond-dreams-unequal-realities-the-promise-and-pitfalls-of-no-apc-open-access/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Diamond Open Access promises equity, but sustainability challenges remain. Discover the hidden costs, global gaps, and paths toward lasting open publishing.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/15/diamond-dreams-unequal-realities-the-promise-and-pitfalls-of-no-apc-open-access/">Diamond Dreams, Unequal Realities: The Promise and Pitfalls of No-APC Open Access</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Diamond Open Access promises equity, but sustainability challenges remain. Discover the hidden costs, global gaps, and paths toward lasting open publishing.

The post [Diamond Dreams, Unequal Realities: The Promise and Pitfalls of No-APC Open Access](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/15/diamond-dreams-unequal-realities-the-promise-and-pitfalls-of-no-apc-open-access/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61074</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Integrating grant metadata for seamless research interconnectivity at FCCN|FCT</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/integrating-grant-metadata-for-seamless-research-interconnectivity-at-fccnfct/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><a href="#version-in-portuguese"><em>Click here for the version in Portuguese</em></a></p>
        <p>Welcome back to our series of case studies of research funders using the Grant Linking System. In this interview, I talk with Cátia Laranjeira, PTCRIS Program Manager at FCCN|FCT, Portugal’s main public funding agency, about the agency’s approach to metadata, persistent identifiers, Open Science and Open Infrastructure.
        With a holistic approach to the management, production and access to information on science, FCCN|FCT&rsquo;s decision to implement the Grant Linking System within their processes was not simply a technical upgrade, but a coordinated effort to continue building a strong culture of openness. With the mantra “register once, reuse always”, FCCN|FCT efforts to embrace open funding metadata was only logical.</p>
        <h3 id="could-you-introduce-your-organisation">Could you introduce your organisation?</h3>
        <p>We are FCCN, the digital services of the FCT, the Foundation for Science and Technology, which is the main public funding agency in Portugal. FCT supports research and innovation in Portugal through multiple funding instruments targeting researchers, projects, institutions and international partnerships. FCCN is focused on providing digital services to the scientific and academic community in Portugal.</p>
        <p>I am the manager of a program called <a href="http://www.ptcris.pt" target="_blank">PTCRIS</a>, part of the FCCN, within the ‘Scientific Knowledge’ pillar of the unit. PTCRIS is a broad program, whose main goal is to fulfill the mantra ‘register once, reuse always’. We aim to develop an integrated ecosystem of scientific information, so all the projects we run have this main goal and that’s what we work towards. We develop infrastructure and added-value services, such as the <a href="https://www.cienciavitae.pt/" target="_blank">scientific curriculum vitae management platform</a> and an indicator system that exposes information of all the funding that supports research and innovation in Portugal.</p>
        <h3 id="what-motivated-you-to-join-crossref">What motivated you to join Crossref?</h3>
        <p>We had already adopted ORCID and we also developed a national PID, connected to the citizen card additional to ORCIDs. In 2015 we adopted the <a href="https://isni.org/page/what-is-isni/" target="_blank">ISNI</a> and we also had DOIs for research outputs. So we were clearly missing one piece, which was metadata for funding.
        At the same time we started developing a national infrastructure on science and technology funding, to have an aggregated and holistic view of the funding that is distributed in Portugal.</p>
        <p>Before that the information was scattered across different databases and websites from many different funders, so we organised and aggregated this information into a platform called <a href="https://www.fccn.pt/en/atualidade/portal-sciproj-o-novo-servico-da-fct-para-a-pesquisa-do-financiamento-cientifico-em-portugal/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank">SciPROJ</a>, which brings together all the information on scientific funding in one place, with quick and flexible access. But we didn’t have persistent identifiers for grants, and this was at the same time that Crossref started to build the Grant Linking System, so we were actually one of the first organisations to join, and in 2023 we had a pilot, where we registered 6000 grants, and we have been registering funding metadata ever since.</p>
        <h3 id="can-you-tell-us-about-your-experience-using-the-grant-linking-system">Can you tell us about your experience using the Grant Linking System?</h3>
        <p>The beginning of the pilot was the most critical stage of the process; some effort was needed to map our data models to the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/grants-schema/" target="_blank">Crossref grant metadata schema</a>. FCCN wasn’t in a bad position to do this since we already had all that information in a registry and it was well organised, we just had to map them to make sure that the information we had could be shared following the Crossref metadata schema and <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/principles-practices/" target="_blank">best practices</a>.
        It has been two years since the pilot, which puts us in phase 2 of the implementation of the system. During the pilot we concentrated on registering both historical and current grants&rsquo; metadata, in the current phase, we are focusing on current grants’ metadata.</p>
        <h3 id="what-do-you-find-useful-about-registering-grant-metadata-with-crossref">What do you find useful about registering grant metadata with Crossref?</h3>
        <p><strong>Although this is the very beginning of this journey, we envision a world where we have the ability to link grants to any other object and entity that comprises the ecosystem: people that execute that funding, projects, institutions, outputs.</strong> Outputs are something particularly important to us, like for many other funders, because we want to be able to monitor the impact of our funding and that is something that is always at the back of our mind.</p>
        <p>We are actually developing more and more services that aim to show how these links can be very useful to retrieve information from the system. For example, we are developing an indicator system that is focusing on the funding but also on the outputs and the links between the two. We are also monitoring OA trends, to see how FCT funding is contributing to Open Science initiatives.</p>
        <p>Additionally, our <a href="https://www.fct.pt/en/sobre/estudos-e-planeamento-estrategico/politicas-de-ciencia-aberta/acesso-aberto-a-publicacoes-cientificas/" target="_blank">OA policy was recently launched</a> but we currently don’t have any system that allows us to track policy compliance. We are working towards that, but to achieve this <strong>it is absolutely fundamental that grants are linked to the outputs through metadata.</strong></p>
        <h3 id="what-are-your-hopes-for-the-gls-and-greater-transparency-in-funding-metadata-in-general">What are your hopes for the GLS and greater transparency in funding metadata in general?</h3>
        <p>The interconnectivity and interoperability of entities and objects, which is something that the field of scientific information management has always wanted to do, but that it’s very difficult to do. There have been attempts in the past to achieve this using information from the acknowledgement sections of publications, but this is fairly inefficient and there needs to be more structure to it. <strong>A critical piece of this puzzle would be to influence publishers, manuscript submission platforms to facilitate the systematic sharing of grant IDs and grant metadata by design.</strong> I think this is something that is still missing and that I would like to see happening soon.</p>
        <h3 id="has-anything-surprised-you-while-implementing-the-grant-linking-system">Has anything surprised you while implementing the Grant Linking System?</h3>
        <p>Something that we have seen that was surprising was that researchers, who in general are not that concerned about PIDs, when it came to grant IDs, they would ask us proactively what the Crossref grant ID for their award was! It was very refreshing to see that we didn’t need to do any advertising to socialize Crossref grant IDs among our grant holders. I think that tells you about the high level of awareness there is within our community of the importance of the Crossref grant ID, using it and putting it in the acknowledgment section of their publications.</p>
        <h3 id="based-on-your-experience-what-would-be-your-advice-for-colleagues-from-other-research-funders">Based on your experience, what would be your advice for colleagues from other research funders?</h3>
        <p>I would say go for it! The more the merrier! This is like any other similar information system – <strong>it only works if there are enough people using it</strong>, registering grants metadata that facilitate the links between objects.</p>
        <p>It is a very easy process to get into. Once you map the metadata schema to your own data it’s not a technically difficult thing to do. For us it’s an automated process that runs very smoothly, from grant registration to communicating this information to grant holders. We can see this in action in this example: the grantee published <a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14020298" target="_blank">an article</a> that acknowledges their funding through <a href="https://sciproj.ptcris.pt/157479UID" target="_blank">Crossref’s grants IDs</a> or funding received being acknowledged in the <a href="https://www.citab.utad.pt/the-centre/welcome-to-citab" target="_blank">website of a Research Center</a>.</p>
        <h3 id="if-you-could-change-something-about-the-gls-or-how-the-grant-metadata-you-register-is-used-what-would-it-be">If you could change something about the GLS or how the grant metadata you register is used, what would it be?</h3>
        <p>I would love to have access to a visualization of grants’ metadata, how many outputs are linked to, and how they relate to other objects and entities. That would really give us a clearer understanding of the impact that our funding is having.
        We’d also love to see better integration between Crossref and ORCID for grants—just like it works for publications. Ideally, when a grant is registered and linked to a researcher, they’d be notified and could easily add it to their ORCID record. This would allow the information to flow seamlessly into their national CV via <strong>PTCRISsync</strong>, ensuring consistency and reducing manual work.</p>
        <hr>
        <p>We are grateful to Cátia Laranjeira and FCT|FCCN for sharing their perspective and long-standing experience in this space. Their experience highlights the role that funding metadata plays in an interconnected and complete research and funding ecosystem.</p>
        <h3 id="version-in-portuguese">Version in Portuguese</h3>
        <p><em>Translation by Edilson Damasio</em></p>
        <h3 id="integração-de-metadados-de-financiamento-pela-fccnfct-para-reforçar-a-interoperabilidade-da-informação-sobre-a-atividade-científica">Integração de metadados de financiamento pela FCCN|FCT para reforçar a interoperabilidade da informação sobre a atividade científica</h3>
        <p>Bem-vindo(a) de volta à nossa série de estudos de caso sobre instituições financiadoras de investigação que utilizam o Grant Linking System. Nesta entrevista, conversamos com Cátia Laranjeira, gestora do programa PTCRIS na FCCN|FCT, a principal agência pública de financiamento à ciência em Portugal, sobre a abordagem da instituição aos metadados, identificadores persistentes, Ciência Aberta e Infraestruturas Abertas.</p>
        <p>Com uma abordagem holística à gestão, produção e acesso à informação científica, a decisão da FCCN|FCT de integrar o Grant Linking System nos seus processos não representou apenas uma evolução técnica, mas sim um esforço coordenado para consolidar uma forte cultura de abertura. Sob o lema “registar uma vez, reutilizar sempre”, a adoção de metadados abertos de financiamento pela FCCN|FCT foi um passo natural e coerente com essa visão.</p>
        <h3 id="poderia-apresentar-a-sua-organização">Poderia apresentar a sua organização?</h3>
        <p>A FCCN é a unidade de serviços digitais da FCT — Fundação para a Ciência e a Tecnologia, a principal agência pública de financiamento à ciência em Portugal. A FCT apoia a investigação e a inovação através de diversos instrumentos de financiamento dirigidos a investigadores, projetos, instituições e parcerias internacionais. A FCCN dedica-se a disponibilizar serviços digitais à comunidade científica e académica portuguesa.</p>
        <p>Na FCCN|FCT, sou gestora do PTCRIS, um programa integrado no pilar do Conhecimento Científico. O PTCRIS é um programa abrangente que tem como objetivo central concretizar o princípio “registar uma vez, reutilizar sempre”. Trabalhamos para desenvolver um ecossistema integrado de informação científica, e todos os projetos que conduzimos convergem nesse propósito. Desenvolvemos infraestruturas e serviços de valor acrescentado, como a plataforma de gestão do currículo científico <a href="https://www.cienciavitae.pt/" target="_blank">CIÊNCIAVITAE</a> e um sistema de indicadores que disponibiliza informação sobre todos os financiamentos que apoiam a investigação e a inovação em Portugal.</p>
        <h3 id="o-que-motivou-a-adesão-à-crossref">O que motivou a adesão à Crossref?</h3>
        <p>A FCCN tinha já adotado o ORCID e desenvolvido um identificador nacional persistente (PID), ligado ao cartão de cidadão, como complemento aos ORCIDs. Em 2015, adotámos o <a href="https://isni.org/page/what-is-isni/" target="_blank">ISNI</a> e também tínhamos DOIs para a produção científica. Ficava claramente em falta um elemento: os metadados de financiamento.</p>
        <p>Ao mesmo tempo, iniciámos o desenvolvimento de uma infraestrutura nacional de financiamentos de ciência e tecnologia, com o objetivo de ter uma visão agregada e holística do financiamento que suporta a investigação e inovação em Portugal.</p>
        <p>Antes disso, a informação estava dispersa por diferentes bases de dados e websites de múltiplos financiadores. Organizámos e agregámos esta informação numa plataforma chamada <a href="https://www.fccn.pt/en/atualidade/portal-sciproj-o-novo-servico-da-fct-para-a-pesquisa-do-financiamento-cientifico-em-portugal/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" target="_blank">SciPROJ</a>, que reúne toda a informação sobre financiamentos científicos num único local, com acesso rápido e flexível. No entanto, ainda não existiam identificadores persistentes para os financiamentos, coincidindo com o momento em que a Crossref começou a desenvolver o Grant Linking System. Fomos, assim, uma das primeiras organizações a aderir. Em 2023, realizámos um piloto com 6.000 financiamentos registados, e desde então temos vindo a registar continuamente os metadados de financiamento.</p>
        <h3 id="pode-falar-nos-sobre-a-sua-experiência-com-o-grant-linking-system">Pode falar-nos sobre a sua experiência com o Grant Linking System?</h3>
        <p>A FCCN iniciou a utilização do Grant Linking System com um piloto, que constituiu a fase mais crítica do processo. Foi necessário algum esforço para mapear os nossos modelos de dados para o <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/grants-schema/" target="_blank">esquema de metadados de financiamentos da Crossref</a>. A FCCN estava, no entanto, bem posicionada para isso, uma vez que já dispunha de toda a informação num registo organizado; o passo necessário foi apenas assegurar que esta informação pudesse ser partilhada de acordo com o esquema de metadados da Crossref e as <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/principles-pra" target="_blank">melhores práticas</a>.</p>
        <p>Já passaram dois anos desde o piloto, o que nos coloca na fase 2 de implementação do sistema. Durante o piloto, focámo-nos no registo de metadados de financiamentos históricos e atuais; na fase atual, estamos focados no registo de metadados de financiamentos atuais.</p>
        <h3 id="o-que-considera-útil-no-registo-de-metadados-de-financiamento-na-crossref">O que considera útil no registo de metadados de financiamento na Crossref?</h3>
        <p><strong>Embora este seja ainda o início deste percurso, a FCCN idealiza um ecossistema em que seja possível ligar financiamentos a qualquer outro objeto ou entidade do sistema científico — projetos, pessoas que executam esses financiamentos, instituições onde são executados e produções científicas que dele resultam.</strong> Estes últimos são particularmente importantes para nós, como para muitos outros financiadores, pois queremos monitorizar o impacto do financiamento — uma preocupação que está sempre presente no nosso trabalho.</p>
        <p>Estamos, de facto, a desenvolver serviços que demonstram o valor dessas ligações para a recuperação de informação no sistema. Um exemplo é o sistema de indicadores em desenvolvimento, que se centra nos financiamentos, nas produções científicas e nas relações entre ambos. Estamos também a acompanhar as tendências de Ciência Aberta, para perceber de que forma o financiamento da FCT está a contribuir para as iniciativas de Open Science.</p>
        <p>Além disso, a <a href="https://www.fct.pt/en/sobre/estudos-e-planeamento-estrategico/politicas-de-ciencia-aberta/acesso-aberto-a-publicacoes-cientificas/" target="_blank">política de Acesso Aberto da FCT</a> foi recentemente lançada, mas ainda não dispomos de um sistema que permita monitorizar a conformidade com essa política. Estamos a trabalhar nesse sentido, mas para o concretizar é <strong>absolutamente essencial que consigamos associar inequivocamente os financiamentos às produções científicas através de metadados.</strong></p>
        <h3 id="quais-são-as-suas-expectativas-para-o-gls-e-para-uma-maior-transparência-dos-metadados-de-financiamento-em-geral">Quais são as suas expectativas para o GLS e para uma maior transparência dos metadados de financiamento em geral?</h3>
        <p>A interconectividade e interoperabilidade entre entidades e objetos é algo que a área da gestão de informação científica sempre procurou alcançar — embora seja um objetivo difícil de concretizar. No passado, houve várias tentativas nesse sentido, recorrendo à informação presente nas secções de agradecimentos das publicações, mas esse método revelou-se pouco eficiente e carece de uma estrutura mais sistemática.</p>
        <p><strong>Uma peça essencial deste puzzle seria influenciar as editoras e as plataformas de submissão de manuscritos a facilitarem a partilha sistemática de identificadores e metadados de financiamento.</strong> Este é um elemento que ainda falta concretizar, mas que gostaríamos de ver implementado em breve.</p>
        <h3 id="algo-o-surpreendeu-durante-a-implementação-do-grant-linking-system">Algo o surpreendeu durante a implementação do Grant Linking System?</h3>
        <p>Algo que nos surpreendeu durante a implementação do Grant Linking System foi a reação dos investigadores. Normalmente, os investigadores não demonstram grande preocupação com identificadores persistentes (PIDs), mas, neste caso, começaram a procurar ativamente o identificador Crossref do seu financiamento! Foi muito positivo perceber que não foi necessário fazer qualquer esforço de divulgação para promover o uso dos Grant IDs da Crossref entre os beneficiários dos financiamentos. Isso mostra o nível de consciência existente na comunidade científica sobre a importância destes identificadores — usá-los e incluí-los na secção de agradecimentos das publicações.</p>
        <h3 id="com-base-na-sua-experiência-qual-seria-o-seu-conselho-para-colegas-de-outros-financiadores-de-investigação">Com base na sua experiência, qual seria o seu conselho para colegas de outros financiadores de investigação?</h3>
        <p>Com base na nossa experiência, o conselho para outros financiadores seria simples: avancem! Quanto mais, melhor! Este tipo de sistema de informação só é verdadeiramente eficaz quando há muitas entidades a utilizá-lo, a registar metadados de financiamento e a criar ligações entre objetos.</p>
        <p>É também um processo simples de implementar. Uma vez feito o mapeamento entre o esquema de metadados e os dados internos da instituição, não há grandes desafios técnicos. No nosso caso, o processo é totalmente automatizado e flui de forma eficiente, desde o registo do financiamento até à comunicação dessa informação aos beneficiários. É possível ver isso em prática em vários exemplos — desde <a href="https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14020298" target="_blank">artigos</a> que reconhecem o financiamento através dos <a href="https://sciproj.ptcris.pt/157479UID" target="_blank">Grant IDs da Crossref</a> até ao reconhecimento do apoio financeiro nos <a href="https://www.citab.utad.pt/the-centre/welcome-to-citab" target="_blank">sites dos centros de investigação</a>.</p>
        <h3 id="se-pudesse-alterar-algo-no-gls-ou-na-forma-como-os-metadados-dos-subsídios-que-regista-são-utilizados-o-que-seria">​​Se pudesse alterar algo no GLS ou na forma como os metadados dos subsídios que regista são utilizados, o que seria?</h3>
        <p>Se pudéssemos mudar algo no Grant Linking System ou na forma como os metadados de financiamento são utilizados, gostaríamos de ter acesso a uma visualização interativa que mostrasse quantas produções científicas estão ligadas a cada financiamento e como esses se relacionam com outras entidades e objetos. Isso permitiria compreender de forma muito mais clara o impacto real dos financiamentos.</p>
        <p>Gostaríamos também de ver uma melhor integração entre a Crossref e o ORCID no que respeita aos financiamentos — tal como já acontece com as publicações. Idealmente, quando um financiamento fosse registado e associado a um investigador, este seria notificado e poderia adicioná-lo facilmente ao seu registo ORCID. Assim, a informação fluiria automaticamente para o currículo nacional via <strong>PTCRISsync</strong>, garantindo consistência e reduzindo o trabalho manual.</p>
        <hr>
        <p>Agradecemos à Cátia Laranjeira e à FCT|FCCN por partilharem a sua perspetiva e longa experiência neste domínio. A sua experiência destaca o papel que os metadados de financiamento desempenham num ecossistema de investigação e financiamento interligado e completo.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>[_Click here for the version in Portuguese_](#version-in-portuguese)

Welcome back to our series of case studies of research funders using the Grant Linking System. In this interview, I talk with Cátia Laranjeira, PTCRIS Program Manager at FCCN\|FCT, Portugal’s main public funding agency, about the agency’s approach to metadata, persistent identifiers, Open Science and Open Infrastructure.
With a holistic approach to the management, production and access to information on science, FCCN\|FCT’s decision to implement the Grant Linking System within their processes was not simply a technical upgrade, but a coordinated effort to continue building a strong culture of openness. With the mantra “register once, reuse always”, FCCN\|FCT efforts to embrace open funding metadata was only logical.

### Could you introduce your organisation?

We are FCCN, the digital services of the FCT, the Foundation for Science and Technology, which is the main public funding agency in Portugal. FCT supports research and innovation in Portugal through multiple funding instruments targeting researchers, projects, institutions and international partnerships. FCCN is focused on providing digital services to the scientific and academic community in Portugal.

I am the manager of a program called [PTCRIS](http://www.ptcris.pt), part of the FCCN, within the ‘Scientific Knowledge’ pillar of the unit. PTCRIS is a broad program, whose main goal is to fulfill the mantra ‘register once, reuse always’. We aim to develop an integrated ecosystem of scientific information, so all the projects we run have this main goal and that’s what we work towards. We develop infrastructure and added-value services, such as the [scientific curriculum vitae management platform](https://www.cienciavitae.pt/) and an indicator system that exposes information of all the funding that supports research and innovation in Portugal.

### What motivated you to join Crossref?

We had already adopted ORCID and we also developed a national PID, connected to the citizen card additional to ORCIDs. In 2015 we adopted the [ISNI](https://isni.org/page/what-is-isni/) and we also had DOIs for research outputs. So we were clearly missing one piece, which was metadata for funding.
At the same time we started developing a national infrastructure on science and technology funding, to have an aggregated and holistic view of the funding that is distributed in Portugal.

Before that the information was scattered across different databases and websites from many different funders, so we organised and aggregated this information into a platform called [SciPROJ](https://www.fccn.pt/en/atualidade/portal-sciproj-o-novo-servico-da-fct-para-a-pesquisa-do-financiamento-cientifico-em-portugal/?utm_source=chatgpt.com), which brings together all the information on scientific funding in one place, with quick and flexible access. But we didn’t have persistent identifiers for grants, and this was at the same time that Crossref started to build the Grant Linking System, so we were actually one of the first organisations to join, and in 2023 we had a pilot, where we registered 6000 grants, and we have been registering funding metadata ever since.

### Can you tell us about your experience using the Grant Linking System?

The beginning of the pilot was the most critical stage of the process; some effort was needed to map our data models to the [Crossref grant metadata schema](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/grants-schema/). FCCN wasn’t in a bad position to do this since we already had all that information in a registry and it was well organised, we just had to map them to make sure that the information we had could be shared following the Crossref metadata schema and [best practices](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/principles-practices/).
It has been two years since the pilot, which puts us in phase 2 of the implementation of the system. During the pilot we concentrated on registering both historical and current grants’ metadata, in the current phase, we are focusing on current grants’ metadata.

### What do you find useful about registering grant metadata with Crossref?

**Although this is the very beginning of this journey, we envision a world where we have the ability to link grants to any other object and entity that comprises the ecosystem: people that execute that funding, projects, institutions, outputs.** Outputs are something particularly important to us, like for many other funders, because we want to be able to monitor the impact of our funding and that is something that is always at the back of our mind.

We are actually developing more and more services that aim to show how these links can be very useful to retrieve information from the system. For example, we are developing an indicator system that is focusing on the funding but also on the outputs and the links between the two. We are also monitoring OA trends, to see how FCT funding is contributing to Open Science initiatives.

Additionally, our [OA policy was recently launched](https://www.fct.pt/en/sobre/estudos-e-planeamento-estrategico/politicas-de-ciencia-aberta/acesso-aberto-a-publicacoes-cientificas/) but we currently don’t have any system that allows us to track policy compliance. We are working towards that, but to achieve this **it is absolutely fundamental that grants are linked to the outputs through metadata.**

### What are your hopes for the GLS and greater transparency in funding metadata in general?

The interconnectivity and interoperability of entities and objects, which is something that the field of scientific information management has always wanted to do, but that it’s very difficult to do. There have been attempts in the past to achieve this using information from the acknowledgement sections of publications, but this is fairly inefficient and there needs to be more structure to it. **A critical piece of this puzzle would be to influence publishers, manuscript submission platforms to facilitate the systematic sharing of grant IDs and grant metadata by design.** I think this is something that is still missing and that I would like to see happening soon.

### Has anything surprised you while implementing the Grant Linking System?

Something that we have seen that was surprising was that researchers, who in general are not that concerned about PIDs, when it came to grant IDs, they would ask us proactively what the Crossref grant ID for their award was! It was very refreshing to see that we didn’t need to do any advertising to socialize Crossref grant IDs among our grant holders. I think that tells you about the high level of awareness there is within our community of the importance of the Crossref grant ID, using it and putting it in the acknowledgment section of their publications.

### Based on your experience, what would be your advice for colleagues from other research funders?

I would say go for it! The more the merrier! This is like any other similar information system – **it only works if there are enough people using it**, registering grants metadata that facilitate the links between objects.

It is a very easy process to get into. Once you map the metadata schema to your own data it’s not a technically difficult thing to do. For us it’s an automated process that runs very smoothly, from grant registration to communicating this information to grant holders. We can see this in action in this example: the grantee published [an article](https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14020298) that acknowledges their funding through [Crossref’s grants IDs](https://sciproj.ptcris.pt/157479UID) or funding received being acknowledged in the [website of a Research Center](https://www.citab.utad.pt/the-centre/welcome-to-citab).

### If you could change something about the GLS or how the grant metadata you register is used, what would it be?

I would love to have access to a visualization of grants’ metadata, how many outputs are linked to, and how they relate to other objects and entities. That would really give us a clearer understanding of the impact that our funding is having.
We’d also love to see better integration between Crossref and ORCID for grants—just like it works for publications. Ideally, when a grant is registered and linked to a researcher, they’d be notified and could easily add it to their ORCID record. This would allow the information to flow seamlessly into their national CV via **PTCRISsync**, ensuring consistency and reducing manual work.

* * *

We are grateful to Cátia Laranjeira and FCT\|FCCN for sharing their perspective and long-standing experience in this space. Their experience highlights the role that funding metadata plays in an interconnected and complete research and funding ecosystem.

### Version in Portuguese

_Translation by Edilson Damasio_

### Integração de metadados de financiamento pela FCCN\|FCT para reforçar a interoperabilidade da informação sobre a atividade científica

Bem-vindo(a) de volta à nossa série de estudos de caso sobre instituições financiadoras de investigação que utilizam o Grant Linking System. Nesta entrevista, conversamos com Cátia Laranjeira, gestora do programa PTCRIS na FCCN\|FCT, a principal agência pública de financiamento à ciência em Portugal, sobre a abordagem da instituição aos metadados, identificadores persistentes, Ciência Aberta e Infraestruturas Abertas.

Com uma abordagem holística à gestão, produção e acesso à informação científica, a decisão da FCCN\|FCT de integrar o Grant Linking System nos seus processos não representou apenas uma evolução técnica, mas sim um esforço coordenado para consolidar uma forte cultura de abertura. Sob o lema “registar uma vez, reutilizar sempre”, a adoção de metadados abertos de financiamento pela FCCN\|FCT foi um passo natural e coerente com essa visão.

### Poderia apresentar a sua organização?

A FCCN é a unidade de serviços digitais da FCT — Fundação para a Ciência e a Tecnologia, a principal agência pública de financiamento à ciência em Portugal. A FCT apoia a investigação e a inovação através de diversos instrumentos de financiamento dirigidos a investigadores, projetos, instituições e parcerias internacionais. A FCCN dedica-se a disponibilizar serviços digitais à comunidade científica e académica portuguesa.

Na FCCN\|FCT, sou gestora do PTCRIS, um programa integrado no pilar do Conhecimento Científico. O PTCRIS é um programa abrangente que tem como objetivo central concretizar o princípio “registar uma vez, reutilizar sempre”. Trabalhamos para desenvolver um ecossistema integrado de informação científica, e todos os projetos que conduzimos convergem nesse propósito. Desenvolvemos infraestruturas e serviços de valor acrescentado, como a plataforma de gestão do currículo científico [CIÊNCIAVITAE](https://www.cienciavitae.pt/) e um sistema de indicadores que disponibiliza informação sobre todos os financiamentos que apoiam a investigação e a inovação em Portugal.

### O que motivou a adesão à Crossref?

A FCCN tinha já adotado o ORCID e desenvolvido um identificador nacional persistente (PID), ligado ao cartão de cidadão, como complemento aos ORCIDs. Em 2015, adotámos o [ISNI](https://isni.org/page/what-is-isni/) e também tínhamos DOIs para a produção científica. Ficava claramente em falta um elemento: os metadados de financiamento.

Ao mesmo tempo, iniciámos o desenvolvimento de uma infraestrutura nacional de financiamentos de ciência e tecnologia, com o objetivo de ter uma visão agregada e holística do financiamento que suporta a investigação e inovação em Portugal.

Antes disso, a informação estava dispersa por diferentes bases de dados e websites de múltiplos financiadores. Organizámos e agregámos esta informação numa plataforma chamada [SciPROJ](https://www.fccn.pt/en/atualidade/portal-sciproj-o-novo-servico-da-fct-para-a-pesquisa-do-financiamento-cientifico-em-portugal/?utm_source=chatgpt.com), que reúne toda a informação sobre financiamentos científicos num único local, com acesso rápido e flexível. No entanto, ainda não existiam identificadores persistentes para os financiamentos, coincidindo com o momento em que a Crossref começou a desenvolver o Grant Linking System. Fomos, assim, uma das primeiras organizações a aderir. Em 2023, realizámos um piloto com 6.000 financiamentos registados, e desde então temos vindo a registar continuamente os metadados de financiamento.

### Pode falar-nos sobre a sua experiência com o Grant Linking System?

A FCCN iniciou a utilização do Grant Linking System com um piloto, que constituiu a fase mais crítica do processo. Foi necessário algum esforço para mapear os nossos modelos de dados para o [esquema de metadados de financiamentos da Crossref](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/grants-schema/). A FCCN estava, no entanto, bem posicionada para isso, uma vez que já dispunha de toda a informação num registo organizado; o passo necessário foi apenas assegurar que esta informação pudesse ser partilhada de acordo com o esquema de metadados da Crossref e as [melhores práticas](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/principles-pra).

Já passaram dois anos desde o piloto, o que nos coloca na fase 2 de implementação do sistema. Durante o piloto, focámo-nos no registo de metadados de financiamentos históricos e atuais; na fase atual, estamos focados no registo de metadados de financiamentos atuais.

### O que considera útil no registo de metadados de financiamento na Crossref?

**Embora este seja ainda o início deste percurso, a FCCN idealiza um ecossistema em que seja possível ligar financiamentos a qualquer outro objeto ou entidade do sistema científico — projetos, pessoas que executam esses financiamentos, instituições onde são executados e produções científicas que dele resultam.** Estes últimos são particularmente importantes para nós, como para muitos outros financiadores, pois queremos monitorizar o impacto do financiamento — uma preocupação que está sempre presente no nosso trabalho.

Estamos, de facto, a desenvolver serviços que demonstram o valor dessas ligações para a recuperação de informação no sistema. Um exemplo é o sistema de indicadores em desenvolvimento, que se centra nos financiamentos, nas produções científicas e nas relações entre ambos. Estamos também a acompanhar as tendências de Ciência Aberta, para perceber de que forma o financiamento da FCT está a contribuir para as iniciativas de Open Science.

Além disso, a [política de Acesso Aberto da FCT](https://www.fct.pt/en/sobre/estudos-e-planeamento-estrategico/politicas-de-ciencia-aberta/acesso-aberto-a-publicacoes-cientificas/) foi recentemente lançada, mas ainda não dispomos de um sistema que permita monitorizar a conformidade com essa política. Estamos a trabalhar nesse sentido, mas para o concretizar é **absolutamente essencial que consigamos associar inequivocamente os financiamentos às produções científicas através de metadados.**

### Quais são as suas expectativas para o GLS e para uma maior transparência dos metadados de financiamento em geral?

A interconectividade e interoperabilidade entre entidades e objetos é algo que a área da gestão de informação científica sempre procurou alcançar — embora seja um objetivo difícil de concretizar. No passado, houve várias tentativas nesse sentido, recorrendo à informação presente nas secções de agradecimentos das publicações, mas esse método revelou-se pouco eficiente e carece de uma estrutura mais sistemática.

**Uma peça essencial deste puzzle seria influenciar as editoras e as plataformas de submissão de manuscritos a facilitarem a partilha sistemática de identificadores e metadados de financiamento.** Este é um elemento que ainda falta concretizar, mas que gostaríamos de ver implementado em breve.

### Algo o surpreendeu durante a implementação do Grant Linking System?

Algo que nos surpreendeu durante a implementação do Grant Linking System foi a reação dos investigadores. Normalmente, os investigadores não demonstram grande preocupação com identificadores persistentes (PIDs), mas, neste caso, começaram a procurar ativamente o identificador Crossref do seu financiamento! Foi muito positivo perceber que não foi necessário fazer qualquer esforço de divulgação para promover o uso dos Grant IDs da Crossref entre os beneficiários dos financiamentos. Isso mostra o nível de consciência existente na comunidade científica sobre a importância destes identificadores — usá-los e incluí-los na secção de agradecimentos das publicações.

### Com base na sua experiência, qual seria o seu conselho para colegas de outros financiadores de investigação?

Com base na nossa experiência, o conselho para outros financiadores seria simples: avancem! Quanto mais, melhor! Este tipo de sistema de informação só é verdadeiramente eficaz quando há muitas entidades a utilizá-lo, a registar metadados de financiamento e a criar ligações entre objetos.

É também um processo simples de implementar. Uma vez feito o mapeamento entre o esquema de metadados e os dados internos da instituição, não há grandes desafios técnicos. No nosso caso, o processo é totalmente automatizado e flui de forma eficiente, desde o registo do financiamento até à comunicação dessa informação aos beneficiários. É possível ver isso em prática em vários exemplos — desde [artigos](https://doi.org/10.3390/agriculture14020298) que reconhecem o financiamento através dos [Grant IDs da Crossref](https://sciproj.ptcris.pt/157479UID) até ao reconhecimento do apoio financeiro nos [sites dos centros de investigação](https://www.citab.utad.pt/the-centre/welcome-to-citab).

### ​​Se pudesse alterar algo no GLS ou na forma como os metadados dos subsídios que regista são utilizados, o que seria?

Se pudéssemos mudar algo no Grant Linking System ou na forma como os metadados de financiamento são utilizados, gostaríamos de ter acesso a uma visualização interativa que mostrasse quantas produções científicas estão ligadas a cada financiamento e como esses se relacionam com outras entidades e objetos. Isso permitiria compreender de forma muito mais clara o impacto real dos financiamentos.

Gostaríamos também de ver uma melhor integração entre a Crossref e o ORCID no que respeita aos financiamentos — tal como já acontece com as publicações. Idealmente, quando um financiamento fosse registado e associado a um investigador, este seria notificado e poderia adicioná-lo facilmente ao seu registo ORCID. Assim, a informação fluiria automaticamente para o currículo nacional via **PTCRISsync**, garantindo consistência e reduzindo o trabalho manual.

* * *

Agradecemos à Cátia Laranjeira e à FCT\|FCCN por partilharem a sua perspetiva e longa experiência neste domínio. A sua experiência destaca o papel que os metadados de financiamento desempenham num ecossistema de investigação e financiamento interligado e completo.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/integrating-grant-metadata-for-seamless-research-interconnectivity-at-fccnfct/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Driven Back to Eden, by Edward Payson Roe</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edward-payson-roe/driven-back-to-eden</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A family leaves their crowded New York City flat to find health, happiness, and wholesome work in the countryside.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A family leaves their crowded New York City flat to find health, happiness, and wholesome work in the countryside.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edward-payson-roe/driven-back-to-eden/downloads/edward-payson-roe_driven-back-to-eden.epub?source=feed" length="622776" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/edward-payson-roe/driven-back-to-eden</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Mr. Britling Sees It Through, by H. G. Wells</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/h-g-wells/mr-britling-sees-it-through</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A civilian in rural Essex attempts to understand the purpose of World War I.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A civilian in rural Essex attempts to understand the purpose of World War I.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/h-g-wells/mr-britling-sees-it-through/downloads/h-g-wells_mr-britling-sees-it-through.epub?source=feed" length="980838" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/h-g-wells/mr-britling-sees-it-through</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Day in Review (October 14–16)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-october-14-16/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on October 15, 2025, 12:54 pm ET Day in Review highlights news and other stories of interest to the research library community in the US and Canada. Released Monday...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-october-14-16/">Day in Review (October 14–16)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on October 15, 2025, 12:54 pm ET Day in Review highlights news and other stories of interest to the research library community in the US and Canada. Released Monday...

The post [Day in Review (October 14–16)](https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-october-14-16/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=46341</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Keeping the Value of the Liberal Arts in Mind as “Workforce Pell” Becomes Reality</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/keeping-the-value-of-the-liberal-arts-in-mind-as-workforce-pell-becomes-reality/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Federal financial aid for short-term certificate programs, dubbed “Workforce Pell,” is now the law of the land. By making it financially feasible for more students to enroll in these programs, this policy creates an opportunity for higher education institutions to expand existing short-term programs or offer new ones. With public confidence in higher education broadly [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/keeping-the-value-of-the-liberal-arts-in-mind-as-workforce-pell-becomes-reality/">Keeping the Value of the Liberal Arts in Mind as &#8220;Workforce Pell&#8221; Becomes Reality</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Federal financial aid for short-term certificate programs, dubbed “Workforce Pell,” is now the law of the land. By making it financially feasible for more students to enroll in these programs, this policy creates an opportunity for higher education institutions to expand existing short-term programs or offer new ones. With public confidence in higher education broadly \[…\]

The post [Keeping the Value of the Liberal Arts in Mind as “Workforce Pell” Becomes Reality](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/keeping-the-value-of-the-liberal-arts-in-mind-as-workforce-pell-becomes-reality/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323795</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Five Tips for Hosting a Sustainable Event</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/14/five-tips-for-hosting-a-sustainable-event/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Event planners are faced with the delicate balance between constructing spaces for deeper connection with the impact we’re having on our planet. Here’s what I’ve learned about planning events that prioritize sustainability.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/14/five-tips-for-hosting-a-sustainable-event/">Five Tips for Hosting a Sustainable Event</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Event planners are faced with the delicate balance between constructing spaces for deeper connection with the impact we’re having on our planet. Here’s what I’ve learned about planning events that prioritize sustainability.

The post [Five Tips for Hosting a Sustainable Event](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/14/five-tips-for-hosting-a-sustainable-event/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61087</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Welcoming a New Chef in the Kitchen and Saying Thanks to a Few Departing Chefs</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/14/welcoming-a-new-chef-in-the-kitchen-and-saying-thanks-to-a-few-departing-chefs/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today we welcome Stephanie Lovegrove Hansen to The Scholarly Kitchen as a full time Chef and say goodbye to several long-term Chefs (and offer our thanks for all the wisdom they've shared with us).</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/14/welcoming-a-new-chef-in-the-kitchen-and-saying-thanks-to-a-few-departing-chefs/">Welcoming a New Chef in the Kitchen and Saying Thanks to a Few Departing Chefs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today we welcome Stephanie Lovegrove Hansen to The Scholarly Kitchen as a full time Chef and say goodbye to several long-term Chefs (and offer our thanks for all the wisdom they&#39;ve shared with us).

The post [Welcoming a New Chef in the Kitchen and Saying Thanks to a Few Departing Chefs](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/14/welcoming-a-new-chef-in-the-kitchen-and-saying-thanks-to-a-few-departing-chefs/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61089</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Lazy Detective, by George Dilnot</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-dilnot/the-lazy-detective</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An indolent detective gets a case which leads him to suspect a hitherto untouchable criminal.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>An indolent detective gets a case which leads him to suspect a hitherto untouchable criminal.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-dilnot/the-lazy-detective/downloads/george-dilnot_the-lazy-detective.epub?source=feed" length="548084" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-dilnot/the-lazy-detective</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Seagull, by Anton Chekhov</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/the-seagull/constance-garnett</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A has-been actress, her ambitious playwright son, a male writer, and an aspiring young actress struggle to realize their romantic and artistic aims.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A has-been actress, her ambitious playwright son, a male writer, and an aspiring young actress struggle to realize their romantic and artistic aims.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/the-seagull/constance-garnett/downloads/anton-chekhov_the-seagull_constance-garnett.epub?source=feed" length="449595" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/the-seagull/constance-garnett</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Three Years After the Launch of ChatGPT, Do We Know Where This Is Heading?</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/13/three-years-after-the-launch-of-chatgpt-do-we-know-where-this-is-heading/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Nearly three years after ChatGPT’s debut, generative AI continues to reshape scholarly publishing. The sector has moved from experimentation toward integration, with advances in ethical writing tools, AI-driven discovery, summarization, and automated peer review. While workflows are becoming more efficient, the long-term impact on research creation and evaluation remains uncertain.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/13/three-years-after-the-launch-of-chatgpt-do-we-know-where-this-is-heading/">Three Years After the Launch of ChatGPT, Do We Know Where This Is Heading?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Nearly three years after ChatGPT’s debut, generative AI continues to reshape scholarly publishing. The sector has moved from experimentation toward integration, with advances in ethical writing tools, AI-driven discovery, summarization, and automated peer review. While workflows are becoming more efficient, the long-term impact on research creation and evaluation remains uncertain.

The post [Three Years After the Launch of ChatGPT, Do We Know Where This Is Heading?](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/13/three-years-after-the-launch-of-chatgpt-do-we-know-where-this-is-heading/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61084</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Waverley, by Walter Scott</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/walter-scott/waverley</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young English officer becomes involved in the Jacobite rebellion.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young English officer becomes involved in the Jacobite rebellion.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/walter-scott/waverley/downloads/walter-scott_waverley.epub?source=feed" length="1016341" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/walter-scott/waverley</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Enhancing repository integration with Crossref</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/enhancing-repository-integration-with-crossref/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Repositories are home to a wide range of scholarly content; they often archive theses, dissertations, preprints, datasets, and other valuable outputs. These records are an important part of the research ecosystem and should be connected to the broader scholarly record. But to truly serve their purpose, repository records need to be connected to each other, to the broader research ecosystem, and to the people behind the research. Metadata is what makes that possible. Enhancing metadata is a way to tell a fuller, more accurate story of research. It helps surface relationships between works, people, funders, and institutions, and allows us as a community to build and use a more connected, more useful network of knowledge - what Crossref calls the ‘<a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/" target="_blank">Research Nexus</a>’.</p>
        <p>The challenge many repositories face is that metadata can be incomplete, inconsistent, or disconnected. Think of references without DOIs, authors without ORCID iDs, or research outputs that aren&rsquo;t linked to funding. To address this, Crossref provides a range of services that repositories can use to improve the quality and interoperability of their metadata. Our REST API, which is openly and publicly accessible, allows repositories to retrieve structured metadata, such as DOIs, references, abstracts, contributors, ORCID iDs, and funder information, that can be used to enrich and update their local records. For repository members, with the Cited-by service and reference linking, repositories can also show how works are being cited and interconnect related content. The Grant Linking System (GLS) enables the clear indication of which research outputs are linked to specific grants, and funding bodies themselves are connected using Open Funder Registry and ROR, adding another layer of context. With Crossmark, repositories can flag updates, corrections, or retractions to ensure transparency and trust in the scholarly content they host.</p>
        <p>Enriching repository metadata using Crossref is a practical and empowering step toward making your records more discoverable, complete, and connected. The process is simple, and you don’t need to be a developer to get started. Repositories can query the Crossref REST API using a DOI or basic metadata like a title or author name, and receive structured, reliable information. This can include full author lists, ORCID iDs, reference lists, funding data, and licensing terms. You can then match and merge this data into your repository records. Adding Crossref DOIs to your metadata enables persistent linking, helping users trace research outputs back to their stewards. It also helps create rich relationships between articles, datasets, software, grants, and other research objects. All of this supports the FAIR principles and contributes to a more connected and reusable scholarly record. And because Crossref’s infrastructure is open, any repository can access and use this metadata to improve the quality, visibility, and long-term value of their collections.</p>
        <h3 id="steps-to-enrich-repository-metadata-with-crossref">Steps to enrich repository metadata with Crossref:</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Query the REST API using DOIs or basic metadata (visit our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/learning/" target="_blank">API learning hub</a> to learn how to use the Crossref API)</li>
        <li>Retrieve structured metadata like authors, ORCID iDs, funders, affiliations, ROR IDs, licenses, grants, and references</li>
        <li>Map and merge with your local records</li>
        <li>Display persistent links to all kinds of research objects using Crossref DOIs</li>
        <li>Support FAIR by including open, structured, and complete metadata</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Across the repository community, several institutions are already integrating Crossref metadata in meaningful ways to enrich their records and improve discoverability. DSpace users can enrich their deposits by using the platform’s <a href="https://wiki.lyrasis.org/display/DSDOC7x/Live&#43;Import&#43;from&#43;external&#43;sources" target="_blank">“Live Import” feature</a>, which allows them to pull in Crossref metadata, such as titles, authors, and DOIs, directly into items during the submission process. A deeper integration between DSpace and Crossref is currently in development. HAL in France uses the Crossref API to complete and standardise references, making its content more consistent and connected (hal.archives-ouvertes.fr). SciELO, a key open access platform in Latin America, leverages Crossref DOI links and citation metadata to strengthen the visibility of its journals (<a href="https://scielo.org" target="_blank">scielo.org</a>). In Canada, the University of Saskatchewan’s eCommons repository queries the Crossref API to enhance metadata accuracy and link records to the broader scholarly graph (ecommons.usask.ca). The Apollo repository at the University of Cambridge uses Crossref to connect theses and articles to their published versions, creating a clearer picture of research outcomes (repository.cam.ac.uk). Zenodo, hosted by CERN, draws on Crossref metadata to link deposited datasets and software with related publications, supporting transparency and reuse (<a href="https://zenodo.org/" target="_blank">zenodo.org</a>).</p>
        <p>These examples show how even modest integrations with Crossref can lead to substantial gains in metadata quality, interoperability, and global discoverability. Altogether, these activities and organisations are enhancing the Research Nexus, enriching a scholarly graph for the benefit of all.</p>
        <p>Want to learn more? You can explore the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/pdfs/enhancing-repository-integration-with-crossref-services.pdf">presentation slides (PDF)</a> from <strong>Open Repositories 2025</strong>, which cover the Crossref API and its capabilities, how repositories can use it to query and enrich metadata, the benefits for repository managers, researchers, and funders, as well as recent updates to our metadata schema.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Repositories are home to a wide range of scholarly content; they often archive theses, dissertations, preprints, datasets, and other valuable outputs. These records are an important part of the research ecosystem and should be connected to the broader scholarly record. But to truly serve their purpose, repository records need to be connected to each other, to the broader research ecosystem, and to the people behind the research. Metadata is what makes that possible. Enhancing metadata is a way to tell a fuller, more accurate story of research. It helps surface relationships between works, people, funders, and institutions, and allows us as a community to build and use a more connected, more useful network of knowledge - what Crossref calls the ‘ [Research Nexus](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/)’.

The challenge many repositories face is that metadata can be incomplete, inconsistent, or disconnected. Think of references without DOIs, authors without ORCID iDs, or research outputs that aren’t linked to funding. To address this, Crossref provides a range of services that repositories can use to improve the quality and interoperability of their metadata. Our REST API, which is openly and publicly accessible, allows repositories to retrieve structured metadata, such as DOIs, references, abstracts, contributors, ORCID iDs, and funder information, that can be used to enrich and update their local records. For repository members, with the Cited-by service and reference linking, repositories can also show how works are being cited and interconnect related content. The Grant Linking System (GLS) enables the clear indication of which research outputs are linked to specific grants, and funding bodies themselves are connected using Open Funder Registry and ROR, adding another layer of context. With Crossmark, repositories can flag updates, corrections, or retractions to ensure transparency and trust in the scholarly content they host.

Enriching repository metadata using Crossref is a practical and empowering step toward making your records more discoverable, complete, and connected. The process is simple, and you don’t need to be a developer to get started. Repositories can query the Crossref REST API using a DOI or basic metadata like a title or author name, and receive structured, reliable information. This can include full author lists, ORCID iDs, reference lists, funding data, and licensing terms. You can then match and merge this data into your repository records. Adding Crossref DOIs to your metadata enables persistent linking, helping users trace research outputs back to their stewards. It also helps create rich relationships between articles, datasets, software, grants, and other research objects. All of this supports the FAIR principles and contributes to a more connected and reusable scholarly record. And because Crossref’s infrastructure is open, any repository can access and use this metadata to improve the quality, visibility, and long-term value of their collections.

### Steps to enrich repository metadata with Crossref:

- Query the REST API using DOIs or basic metadata (visit our [API learning hub](https://www.crossref.org/learning/) to learn how to use the Crossref API)
- Retrieve structured metadata like authors, ORCID iDs, funders, affiliations, ROR IDs, licenses, grants, and references
- Map and merge with your local records
- Display persistent links to all kinds of research objects using Crossref DOIs
- Support FAIR by including open, structured, and complete metadata

Across the repository community, several institutions are already integrating Crossref metadata in meaningful ways to enrich their records and improve discoverability. DSpace users can enrich their deposits by using the platform’s [“Live Import” feature](https://wiki.lyrasis.org/display/DSDOC7x/Live+Import+from+external+sources), which allows them to pull in Crossref metadata, such as titles, authors, and DOIs, directly into items during the submission process. A deeper integration between DSpace and Crossref is currently in development. HAL in France uses the Crossref API to complete and standardise references, making its content more consistent and connected (hal.archives-ouvertes.fr). SciELO, a key open access platform in Latin America, leverages Crossref DOI links and citation metadata to strengthen the visibility of its journals ( [scielo.org](https://scielo.org)). In Canada, the University of Saskatchewan’s eCommons repository queries the Crossref API to enhance metadata accuracy and link records to the broader scholarly graph (ecommons.usask.ca). The Apollo repository at the University of Cambridge uses Crossref to connect theses and articles to their published versions, creating a clearer picture of research outcomes (repository.cam.ac.uk). Zenodo, hosted by CERN, draws on Crossref metadata to link deposited datasets and software with related publications, supporting transparency and reuse ( [zenodo.org](https://zenodo.org/)).

These examples show how even modest integrations with Crossref can lead to substantial gains in metadata quality, interoperability, and global discoverability. Altogether, these activities and organisations are enhancing the Research Nexus, enriching a scholarly graph for the benefit of all.

Want to learn more? You can explore the [presentation slides (PDF)](https://www.crossref.org/pdfs/enhancing-repository-integration-with-crossref-services.pdf) from **Open Repositories 2025**, which cover the Crossref API and its capabilities, how repositories can use it to query and enrich metadata, the benefits for repository managers, researchers, and funders, as well as recent updates to our metadata schema.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/enhancing-repository-integration-with-crossref/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The transparency paradox when using generative AI in academic research</title>
      <link>https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/10/10/the-transparency-paradox-when-using-generative-ai-in-academic-research/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The use of generative AI in academic research creates a paradox between transparency and credibility. Research shows that declaring the use of AI, although ethical, can diminish trust in the researcher. The lack of clear guidelines and the stigma associated with AI hinder the adoption of the transparency necessary to ensure scientific integrity. <span class="ellipsis">&#8230;</span> <span class="more-link-wrap"><a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/10/10/the-transparency-paradox-when-using-generative-ai-in-academic-research/" class="more-link"><span>Read More &#8594;</span></a></span></p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/10/10/the-transparency-paradox-when-using-generative-ai-in-academic-research/">The transparency paradox when using generative AI in academic research</a> first appeared on <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en">SciELO in Perspective</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The use of generative AI in academic research creates a paradox between transparency and credibility. Research shows that declaring the use of AI, although ethical, can diminish trust in the researcher. The lack of clear guidelines and the stigma associated with AI hinder the adoption of the transparency necessary to ensure scientific integrity. …[Read More →](https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/10/10/the-transparency-paradox-when-using-generative-ai-in-academic-research/)

The post [The transparency paradox when using generative AI in academic research](https://blog.scielo.org/en/2025/10/10/the-transparency-paradox-when-using-generative-ai-in-academic-research/) first appeared on [SciELO in Perspective](https://blog.scielo.org/en).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.scielo.org/en/?p=5681</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>SSP’s Generations Fund Crosses the Finish Line</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/10/ssps-generations-fund-crosses-the-finish-line/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>SSP Thanks Individual &#038; Organizational Contributors to the Generations Fund!</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/10/ssps-generations-fund-crosses-the-finish-line/">SSP’s Generations Fund Crosses the Finish Line</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>SSP Thanks Individual &#38; Organizational Contributors to the Generations Fund!

The post [SSP’s Generations Fund Crosses the Finish Line](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/10/ssps-generations-fund-crosses-the-finish-line/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60961</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>“Who Isn’t in the Room Yet?”</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/who-isnt-in-the-room-yet/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>On September 27, I joined more than 100 advocates for students’ basic needs at the second annual Carolinas College Food Insecurity Summit at Newberry College in South Carolina. Participants gathered from across North and South Carolina, as well as Georgia, to share ideas, strategies, and challenges in addressing students’ basic needs. The event began with [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/who-isnt-in-the-room-yet/">“Who Isn’t in the Room Yet?”</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>On September 27, I joined more than 100 advocates for students’ basic needs at the second annual Carolinas College Food Insecurity Summit at Newberry College in South Carolina. Participants gathered from across North and South Carolina, as well as Georgia, to share ideas, strategies, and challenges in addressing students’ basic needs. The event began with \[…\]

The post [“Who Isn’t in the Room Yet?”](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/who-isnt-in-the-room-yet/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323776</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — The Economics of AI in Academic Research</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/09/guest-post-the-economics-of-ai-in-academic-research/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In the fast-moving world of AI research tools, there are many community-focused concerns that vendors should have strong opinions on and plans for, from privacy and security to sustainability and copyright. But the most misunderstood issue, in my view, is the one at the heart of it all — how AI will reshape the economics of academic research.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/09/guest-post-the-economics-of-ai-in-academic-research/">Guest Post — The Economics of AI in Academic Research</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In the fast-moving world of AI research tools, there are many community-focused concerns that vendors should have strong opinions on and plans for, from privacy and security to sustainability and copyright. But the most misunderstood issue, in my view, is the one at the heart of it all — how AI will reshape the economics of academic research.

The post [Guest Post — The Economics of AI in Academic Research](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/09/guest-post-the-economics-of-ai-in-academic-research/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61080</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — Rethinking Disciplinary Data Regimes</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/08/guest-post-rethinking-disciplinary-data-regimes/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Between a political policy environment focused on defunding and deleting data collections – an environment in which little can be trusted – and an onslaught of new AI tools that feed indiscriminately on data, bits of information at the intersection of rows and columns are appearing in headlines more than ever before. To avoid cultural memory loss, we must build systems that save what humanity needs across disciplinary silos rather than saving some archives and losing others through an accident of history.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/08/guest-post-rethinking-disciplinary-data-regimes/">Guest Post &#8212; Rethinking Disciplinary Data Regimes</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Between a political policy environment focused on defunding and deleting data collections – an environment in which little can be trusted – and an onslaught of new AI tools that feed indiscriminately on data, bits of information at the intersection of rows and columns are appearing in headlines more than ever before. To avoid cultural memory loss, we must build systems that save what humanity needs across disciplinary silos rather than saving some archives and losing others through an accident of history.

The post [Guest Post — Rethinking Disciplinary Data Regimes](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/08/guest-post-rethinking-disciplinary-data-regimes/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61077</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Journey of a Curation Request: What Happens When You Ask for an Update to ROR</title>
      <link>https://ror.org/blog/2025-10-08-journey-of-a-curation-request/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Have you ever wondered exactly what happens once you request a new ROR record or suggest a change to an existing ROR record? In this blog post, we take you through all the steps involved in ROR&#39;s open, community-driven process for making sure that the information in the ROR registry is complete and accurate.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Have you ever wondered exactly what happens once you request a new ROR record or suggest a change to an existing ROR record? In this blog post, we take you through all the steps involved in ROR&#39;s open, community-driven process for making sure that the information in the ROR registry is complete and accurate.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://doi.org/10.71938/T128-EA02</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Now It Can Be Told, by Philip Gibbs</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/philip-gibbs/now-it-can-be-told</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A British war correspondent recalls his experiences during the Great War.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A British war correspondent recalls his experiences during the Great War.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/philip-gibbs/now-it-can-be-told/downloads/philip-gibbs_now-it-can-be-told.epub?source=feed" length="967290" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/philip-gibbs/now-it-can-be-told</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Magnolia Leaves, by Mary Weston Fordham</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/mary-weston-fordham/magnolia-leaves</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of poems by Mary Weston Fordham.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A collection of poems by Mary Weston Fordham.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/mary-weston-fordham/magnolia-leaves/downloads/mary-weston-fordham_magnolia-leaves.epub?source=feed" length="463474" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/mary-weston-fordham/magnolia-leaves</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Recollections of Full Years, by Helen Herron Taft</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/helen-herron-taft/recollections-of-full-years</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Helen Herron Taft, wife of William Howard Taft, the twenty-seventh President of the United States, recalls her life married to one of America’s most influential political figures.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Helen Herron Taft, wife of William Howard Taft, the twenty-seventh President of the United States, recalls her life married to one of America’s most influential political figures.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/helen-herron-taft/recollections-of-full-years/downloads/helen-herron-taft_recollections-of-full-years.epub?source=feed" length="10742348" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/helen-herron-taft/recollections-of-full-years</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — “Have You Proved You’re Human Today?” Open Content and Web Harvesting in the AI Era</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/07/guest-post-have-you-proved-youre-human-today-open-content-and-web-harvesting-in-the-ai-era/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>AI web harvesting bots are different from traditional web crawlers and violate many of the established rules and practices in place. Their rapidly expanding use is emerging as a significant IT management problem for content-rich websites across numerous industries.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/07/guest-post-have-you-proved-youre-human-today-open-content-and-web-harvesting-in-the-ai-era/">Guest Post &#8212; “Have You Proved You’re Human Today?” Open Content and Web Harvesting in the AI Era</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>AI web harvesting bots are different from traditional web crawlers and violate many of the established rules and practices in place. Their rapidly expanding use is emerging as a significant IT management problem for content-rich websites across numerous industries.

The post [Guest Post — “Have You Proved You’re Human Today?” Open Content and Web Harvesting in the AI Era](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/07/guest-post-have-you-proved-youre-human-today-open-content-and-web-harvesting-in-the-ai-era/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61071</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Calling All Libraries: Celebrate 1 Trillion Web Pages Archived with the Internet Archive</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/10/07/calling-all-libraries-celebrate-1-trillion-web-pages-archived-with-the-internet-archive/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Internet Archive has released a new resource guide to help libraries join in commemorating a once-in-a-generation milestone: 1 trillion web pages archived by the Internet Archive and available for [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The Internet Archive has released a new resource guide to help libraries join in commemorating a once-in-a-generation milestone: 1 trillion web pages archived by the Internet Archive and available for \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29417</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — Manifesto Time: Do You Need a Publishing Manifesto?</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/06/guest-post-manifesto-time-do-you-need-a-publishing-manifesto/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Does your publishing organization need a manifesto?  Writing a manifesto for your organization can be a great exercise for team building and planning, and a way to ignite action.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/06/guest-post-manifesto-time-do-you-need-a-publishing-manifesto/">Guest Post &#8212; Manifesto Time: Do You Need a Publishing Manifesto?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Does your publishing organization need a manifesto? Writing a manifesto for your organization can be a great exercise for team building and planning, and a way to ignite action.

The post [Guest Post — Manifesto Time: Do You Need a Publishing Manifesto?](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/06/guest-post-manifesto-time-do-you-need-a-publishing-manifesto/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61058</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Short Science Fiction, by Isaac Asimov</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/isaac-asimov/short-science-fiction</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of short science fiction by Isaac Asimov, ordered by date of original publication.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A collection of short science fiction by Isaac Asimov, ordered by date of original publication.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/isaac-asimov/short-science-fiction/downloads/isaac-asimov_short-science-fiction.epub?source=feed" length="502542" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/isaac-asimov/short-science-fiction</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Ponson Case, by Freeman Wills Crofts</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/freeman-wills-crofts/the-ponson-case</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The death of a wealthy industrialist initially seems like an accident, but soon sparks a murder inquiry.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The death of a wealthy industrialist initially seems like an accident, but soon sparks a murder inquiry.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/freeman-wills-crofts/the-ponson-case/downloads/freeman-wills-crofts_the-ponson-case.epub?source=feed" length="1026284" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/freeman-wills-crofts/the-ponson-case</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Uncle Vanya, by Anton Chekhov</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/uncle-vanya/constance-garnett</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An elderly professor and his young wife return to their country estate, where their family’s simmering resentments boil over.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>An elderly professor and his young wife return to their country estate, where their family’s simmering resentments boil over.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/uncle-vanya/constance-garnett/downloads/anton-chekhov_uncle-vanya_constance-garnett.epub?source=feed" length="797651" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/uncle-vanya/constance-garnett</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ARL Libraries Celebrate Banned Books Week 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/arl-libraries-celebrate-banned-books-week-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on October 14, 2025, 5:23 pm ET Banned Books Week celebrates the freedom to read and calls attention to the harms of censorship by spotlighting current and historical...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/arl-libraries-celebrate-banned-books-week-2025/">ARL Libraries Celebrate Banned Books Week 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on October 14, 2025, 5:23 pm ET Banned Books Week celebrates the freedom to read and calls attention to the harms of censorship by spotlighting current and historical...

The post [ARL Libraries Celebrate Banned Books Week 2025](https://www.arl.org/blog/arl-libraries-celebrate-banned-books-week-2025/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=46250</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Happy College Radio Day! Explore Student Radio’s Past and Present in the DLARC College Radio Collection</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/10/03/happy-college-radio-day-explore-student-radios-past-and-present-in-the-dlarc-college-radio-collection/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The 15th annual World College Radio Day takes place on Friday, October 3, 2025, with stations from around the globe celebrating and bringing attention to student radio as an enduring [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The 15th annual World College Radio Day takes place on Friday, October 3, 2025, with stations from around the globe celebrating and bringing attention to student radio as an enduring \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29395</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Scholarship is Like Music: Standing on the Shoulders of Giants</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/03/scholarship-is-like-music-standing-on-the-shoulders-of-giants/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Just as scholarly knowledge development is based on previous research findings, popular musicians stand on the shoulders of Pachelbel's Canon.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/03/scholarship-is-like-music-standing-on-the-shoulders-of-giants/">Scholarship is Like Music: Standing on the Shoulders of Giants</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Just as scholarly knowledge development is based on previous research findings, popular musicians stand on the shoulders of Pachelbel&#39;s Canon.

The post [Scholarship is Like Music: Standing on the Shoulders of Giants](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/03/scholarship-is-like-music-standing-on-the-shoulders-of-giants/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60894</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Advancing Open PID Infrastructure at Scale: A New Face and Exciting Projects for the ROR Technical Team</title>
      <link>https://ror.org/blog/2025-10-02-welcome-joseph-rhoads/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[We are thrilled to introduce the newest member of the ROR pride: Joseph Rhoads joined the ROR team in September as our new Technical Lead.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We are thrilled to introduce the newest member of the ROR pride: Joseph Rhoads joined the ROR team in September as our new Technical Lead.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://doi.org/10.71938/J5DS-GC46</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Peer-to-Peer Fundraising at the Internet Archive</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/10/02/peer-to-peer-fundraising-at-the-internet-archive/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Peer-to-peer (P2P) fundraising allows donors to create their own page and garner donations in support of the Internet Archive. Every donation is tax-deductible, and 100% of all gifts raised directly [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Peer-to-peer (P2P) fundraising allows donors to create their own page and garner donations in support of the Internet Archive. Every donation is tax-deductible, and 100% of all gifts raised directly \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29402</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Repertoires: How Social Science Theory Gets Made and Remade</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/repertoires-how-social-science-theory-gets-made-and-remade/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on October 2, 2025, 1:33 pm ET In 2008, technologist Chris Anderson famously predicted the end of theory, as massively abundant data reduced the need for researchers to...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/repertoires-how-social-science-theory-gets-made-and-remade/">Repertoires: How Social Science Theory Gets Made and Remade</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on October 2, 2025, 1:33 pm ET In 2008, technologist Chris Anderson famously predicted the end of theory, as massively abundant data reduced the need for researchers to...

The post [Repertoires: How Social Science Theory Gets Made and Remade](https://www.arl.org/blog/repertoires-how-social-science-theory-gets-made-and-remade/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=46235</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Great Roxhythe, by Georgette Heyer</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/georgette-heyer/the-great-roxhythe</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A Restoration-era courtier sacrifices his fortune, reputation, and chance at personal happiness to serve his king as a secret spy.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A Restoration-era courtier sacrifices his fortune, reputation, and chance at personal happiness to serve his king as a secret spy.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/georgette-heyer/the-great-roxhythe/downloads/georgette-heyer_the-great-roxhythe.epub?source=feed" length="557579" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/georgette-heyer/the-great-roxhythe</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — When Significance Hurts: What the SAMPL Guidelines Can Teach Us</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/02/guest-post-when-significance-hurts-what-the-sampl-guidelines-can-teach-us/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>If science is to be both honest and healthy, we must accept that statistically non-significant results are part of reality. The SAMPL guidelines, if adopted widely by scholarly publishers and journal editors, hold a solution for authors who worry their results are not "significant."</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/02/guest-post-when-significance-hurts-what-the-sampl-guidelines-can-teach-us/">Guest Post — When Significance Hurts: What the SAMPL Guidelines Can Teach Us</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>If science is to be both honest and healthy, we must accept that statistically non-significant results are part of reality. The SAMPL guidelines, if adopted widely by scholarly publishers and journal editors, hold a solution for authors who worry their results are not &#34;significant.&#34;

The post [Guest Post — When Significance Hurts: What the SAMPL Guidelines Can Teach Us](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/02/guest-post-when-significance-hurts-what-the-sampl-guidelines-can-teach-us/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61054</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>AI and the Research Enterprise at Emerging Research Institutions</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/ai-and-the-research-enterprise-at-emerging-research-institutions/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We recently convened the first workshop for the NSF-funded Advancing AI Implementation at Emerging Research Institutions, a project collaboratively led by Ithaka S+R, Montclair State University, and Chapman University. The workshop brought together 31 participants from 13 academic and medical institutions, as well as from an electronic research administration system provider to ask: how can research administrators at ERIs leverage AI to build more sustainable and equitable research capacity?</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/ai-and-the-research-enterprise-at-emerging-research-institutions/">AI and the Research Enterprise at Emerging Research Institutions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We recently convened the first workshop for the NSF-funded Advancing AI Implementation at Emerging Research Institutions, a project collaboratively led by Ithaka S+R, Montclair State University, and Chapman University. The workshop brought together 31 participants from 13 academic and medical institutions, as well as from an electronic research administration system provider to ask: how can research administrators at ERIs leverage AI to build more sustainable and equitable research capacity?

The post [AI and the Research Enterprise at Emerging Research Institutions](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/ai-and-the-research-enterprise-at-emerging-research-institutions/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323752</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rural Libraries Receive Support from the Internet Archive to Preserve Community Stories</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/10/01/rurallibraries/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Public librarians are shaping the future of the historic record. As experts in community knowledge dedicated to serving local information needs, these librarians are uniquely positioned to preserve and provide [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Public librarians are shaping the future of the historic record. As experts in community knowledge dedicated to serving local information needs, these librarians are uniquely positioned to preserve and provide \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29375</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Is Digital-first Publishing Finally a Reality? An Interview with Liz Ferguson of Wiley</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/01/is-digital-first-publishing-finally-a-reality-an-interview-with-liz-ferguson-of-wiley/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We're finally seeing a move to truly digital-first publishing systems and in today's post Alice Meadows interviews Liz Ferguson of Wiley about this transition, including their own Research Exchange platform.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/01/is-digital-first-publishing-finally-a-reality-an-interview-with-liz-ferguson-of-wiley/">Is Digital-first Publishing Finally a Reality? An Interview with Liz Ferguson of Wiley</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We&#39;re finally seeing a move to truly digital-first publishing systems and in today&#39;s post Alice Meadows interviews Liz Ferguson of Wiley about this transition, including their own Research Exchange platform.

The post [Is Digital-first Publishing Finally a Reality? An Interview with Liz Ferguson of Wiley](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/10/01/is-digital-first-publishing-finally-a-reality-an-interview-with-liz-ferguson-of-wiley/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61008</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Piecing together the Research Nexus: uncovering relationships with open funding metadata</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/piecing-together-the-research-nexus-uncovering-relationships-with-open-funding-metadata/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The Crossref <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/">Grant Linking System (GLS)</a> has been facilitating the registration, sharing and re-use of open funding metadata for six years now, and we have reached some important milestones recently! What started as an interest in identifying funders through the Open Funder Registry evolved to a more nuanced and comprehensive way to share and re-use open funding data systematically. That’s how, in collaboration with the funding community, the Crossref Grant Linking System was developed. Open funding metadata is fundamental for the transparency and integrity of the research endeavour, so we are happy to see them included in the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/">Research Nexus</a>.</p>
        <p>As emphasised recently by <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69" target="_blank">Hans de Jonge from NWO</a>, funding metadata’s value is in the transparency of the relationships it enables. The system is powered by the collective action of the research community– including research funders – that registers open metadata with Crossref, making these relationships possible. With close to 180,000 grant records in our corpus we wanted to know how far they reach and what story they tell.</p>
        <p>In March 2022, we <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/ske16-xve54" target="_blank">developed an approach for linking grants to research outputs</a> and analysed how many such relationships could be established. Now we’re able to present <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/aexidu9f" target="_blank">the latest dataset</a> that contains relationships between grants and research outputs, both those deposited by Crossref members and discovered by an automated matching strategy. It includes data deposited up to the end of July 2025.</p>
        <p>This work is part of our ongoing <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/">Metadata Matching</a> project.</p>
        <h2 id="what-exactly-is-in-this-new-open-dataset-of-grantoutput-relationships">What exactly is in this new open dataset of grant&lt;&gt;output relationships?</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>The dataset contains 250,163 total funding relationships between grants and research outputs. </li>
        <li>We welcomed a number of funders, such as the <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69" target="_blank">Dutch Research Council</a> and <a href="https://frq.gouv.qc.ca/en/persistent-unique-identifiers-doi/" target="_blank">Fonds de Recherche du Quebec</a>, which together registered almost 27,000 grants in the past year. </li>
        <li>It’s clear that the more grant metadata is registered the more funding relationships we can uncover. </li>
        <li>The percentage of relationships that are registered explicitly by Crossref members providing grants IDs in funding information has grown from less than 0.1% in 2023 to 1% (modest numbers but amazing growth!).</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="the-methodology">The methodology </h3>
        <p>We created <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/aexidu9f" target="_blank">a dataset of relationships between grants and research outputs</a> by analysing their metadata in several ways. A relationship is included in the dataset if at least one of the following conditions is met:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>A relationship was explicitly deposited by a Crossref member through a <em>finances</em> or <em>isFinancedBy</em> <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/relationships/">relationship</a>: 488 (0.2%) relationships</li>
        <li>The research output contains the grant DOI within the award number in the funding metadata: 2,003 (0.8%) relationships</li>
        <li>The award numbers in the grant and the research output are similar, and the associated funding organisations are either the same, or one is the sub-organisation of the other: 247,672 (99%) relationships </li>
        </ul>
        <p>The dataset includes data deposited until the end of July 2025 and contains 250,163 total relationships.</p>
        <p>The code used to generate the dataset is available <a href="https://gitlab.com/crossref/data-science/matching-tools/-/tree/main/grant_matching/offline_dataset?ref_type=heads" target="_blank">in our GitLab repository</a>.</p>
        <h3 id="the-results">The results</h3>
        <p>As you can see in the graph below, the number of relationships grant-research output continues to grow as the number of grants records Crossref members register with us increases.</p>
        <div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/graph-grant-research-output.png"
        alt="Graph of the number of relationships grant-research output" width="75%">
        </figure>
        </div>
        <p><strong>Figure 1:</strong> Cumulative totals of grants, linked grants, research outputs, and grant–research output relationships from 2019 to 2025. Stepwise increases correspond to the addition of major funder datasets, including Wellcome (2020), OSTI (2021), JST (2022), the European Union (2022), the Austrian Science Fund (2023), and the Fonds de recherche du Québec (2025).</p>
        <p>Looking at the numbers broken down by grant registrants we can see that the more grants registered the more relationships can be uncovered. The table below shows funders who have at least 1,000 total grants registered and for whom at least 10% of their registered grants are linked to research outputs, showing the number of relationships, grants, linked grants and linked research outputs (sorted by the percentage of linked grants), and compared with the data from the 2023 analysis (where available) to see how the uptake of open funding metadata is evolving.</p>
        <table style="border-collapse:collapse; width:100%; font-family:system-ui, -apple-system, Segoe UI, Roboto, Arial, sans-serif;">
        <thead>
        <tr style="background-color:#006d87; color:#fff;">
        <th rowspan="2" style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:left;">Funder</th>
        <th colspan="2" style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">Relationships</th>
        <th colspan="2" style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">Linked research outputs</th>
        <th colspan="2" style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">Grants</th>
        <th colspan="2" style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">Number of linked grants</th>
        <th colspan="2" style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">Percentage of linked grants</th>
        </tr>
        <tr style="background-color:#006d87; color:#fff;">
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2023</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2025</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2023</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2025</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2023</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2025</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2023</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2025</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2023</th>
        <th style="border:1px solid #ccc; padding:6px; text-align:center;">2025</th>
        </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
        <tr>
        <th scope="row" style="text-align:left; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">European Union</th>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">86,979</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">128,572</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">78,576</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">114,491</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">39,703</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">53,473</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">14,860</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">21,402</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">37.4%</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">40%</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <th scope="row" style="text-align:left; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">Japan Science and Technology Agency</th>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">19,549</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">30,728</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">16,265</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">25,003</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">9,923</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">11,866</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">2,609</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">3,900</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">26.3%</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">32.9%</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <th scope="row" style="text-align:left; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">Wellcome</th>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">34,254</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">45,596</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">25,720</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">33,783</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">17,547</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">19,929</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">5,238</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">6,206</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">29.9%</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">31.1%</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <th scope="row" style="text-align:left; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">American Cancer Society</th>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">50</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">604</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">49</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">586</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">380</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">1,162</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">34</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">277</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">8.9%</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">23.8%</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <th scope="row" style="text-align:left; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">American Heart Association (AHA)</th>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">40</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">1,040</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">38</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">935</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">598</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">2,764</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">30</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">621</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">5%</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">22.5%</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <th scope="row" style="text-align:left; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">Fundacao para a Ciencia e a Tecnologia</th>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">0</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">27,915</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">0</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">15,681</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">5</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">17,422</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">0</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">3,793</td>
        <td style="text-align:center; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">–</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">21.8%</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <th scope="row" style="text-align:left; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">Austrian Science Fund (FWF)</th>
        <td style="text-align:center; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">–</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">10,387</td>
        <td style="text-align:center; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">–</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">7,459</td>
        <td style="text-align:center; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">–</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">19,576</td>
        <td style="text-align:center; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">–</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">2,712</td>
        <td style="text-align:center; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">–</td>
        <td style="text-align:right; border:1px solid #000; padding:6px;">13.9%</td>
        </tr>
        </tbody>
        </table>
        <p><strong>Table 1:</strong> Comparison between data from 2023-07-31 and 2025-07-31 of a number of Crossref members registering grants. It shows the number of relationships, grants, linked grants and linked research outputs, sorted by the percentage of linked grants.</p>
        <p>We encourage funders to join as members once they have determined the means of effective implementation of the GLS within their processes. By further analysing metadata of matched outputs, funders have the opportunity to monitor compliance with their policies and learn more about the impact of their programs.</p>
        <h3 id="following-through-funders-open-science-commitments">Following through funders’ Open Science commitments</h3>
        <p>The relationships showcased above and in the recent analysis are powered by open funding metadata. Open funding metadata plays a central role in building a transparent, accountable and high integrity research environment by making visible the connections between the funding, grantees, research outputs, and their impact. Funders’ openness mandates and Open Science commitments emphasize the importance of traceability in the research process, so ensuring that the support given-whether financial or otherwise-can be systematically recorded and shared is instrumental. Openness is also part of the strategic plans of institutions such as the International Science Council, who has <a href="https://council.science/blog/fighting-disinformation-with-sunshine-promoting-funding-transparency-in-science/" target="_blank">explicitly called for greater transparency in funding</a> as a way to strengthen trust in science and counter misinformation. At the same time, initiatives such as the <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/" target="_blank">Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information</a> underscores the benefits of open, reusable funding metadata for monitoring, evaluation and assessment of research and researchers.</p>
        <p>Crossref’s Grant Linking System offers funders’ a way to demonstrate a commitment to openness, modeling the standards they expect of the research community they support, while creating a more robust, trustworthy and collaborative research ecosystem.</p>
        <h3 id="economy-of-scale-unlocking-relationships-with-crossref">Economy of scale: unlocking relationships with Crossref</h3>
        <p>Crossref houses millions of records, from the ubiquitous research articles and preprints, to books, peer review records, technical reports, datasets – you name it. Our members not only register, but also regularly update their metadata as new or corrected information becomes available. Our matching workflows allow us to make visible the hidden relationships and complete and improve the metadata records by adding new and reciprocal assertions.</p>
        <p>This analysis shows the unique value of registering funding metadata with Crossref and adding an essential piece to the Research Nexus puzzle. <strong>The relationship metadata allows the funding that underpins the research process to be connected, and contextualise scattered data points, acting as an anchor that links publications, people, and other research outputs.</strong> This is made possible by the impressive number of records continuously being registered by more than 23,000 member organisations, and by the increasing availability of funding information in the system with more research funders joining in and registering their grant metadata with us.</p>
        <h3 id="next-steps">Next steps</h3>
        <p>As we welcome more and more funders to the GLS, we, collectively, continue to complete the Research Nexus, record by record, field by field. The more awards we have in our corpus the more relationships we’ll uncover, so we’ll keep making these analyses periodically to make sure we don’t miss them.</p>
        <p>But it is not all on us. We are working towards a vision where Crossref Grant IDs are business as usual – where funders register their awards, grantees are aware of them and share them with publishers, and those publishers share them back with us when registering their content – closing the loop organically. We continue working on making this easier. In the upcoming works schema update a specific Crossref Grant ID field will be added in the funding information, alongside Award ID (for an internal identifier).</p>
        <p>Crucially, as the momentum of adoption among funders increases, and thousands of Crossref Grant IDs are available in the system, we are working with all members to raise their attention to the importance and desirability of funding metadata, so inclusion of that information in metadata of all works increases and consequently, the percentage of relationships asserted by Crossref members can grow.</p>
        <p>This matching analysis is just one example of what we do to enrich metadata to highlight relationships among works, individuals, institutions, and actions. Earlier this year, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/">we launched the Metadata Matching project</a>, which is a major effort to rebuild our matching workflows using modern software development and data science practices. As part of the project, we plan to expose additional matched relationships between grants and research outputs in our REST API, alongside those deposited by our members. We’ll keep you updated as we go along!</p>
        <p>Read more about metadata matching in the blog series:</p>
        <ul>
        <li><a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/aewi1cai" target="_blank">Metadata matching 101: what is it and why do we need it?</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/zie7reeg" target="_blank">The anatomy of metadata matching</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/pied3tho" target="_blank">The myth of perfect metadata matching</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/ief7aibi" target="_blank">How good is your matching?</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/axeer1ee" target="_blank">Metadata matching: beyond correctness</a></li>
        </ul>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The Crossref [Grant Linking System (GLS)](https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/) has been facilitating the registration, sharing and re-use of open funding metadata for six years now, and we have reached some important milestones recently! What started as an interest in identifying funders through the Open Funder Registry evolved to a more nuanced and comprehensive way to share and re-use open funding data systematically. That’s how, in collaboration with the funding community, the Crossref Grant Linking System was developed. Open funding metadata is fundamental for the transparency and integrity of the research endeavour, so we are happy to see them included in the [Research Nexus](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/).

As emphasised recently by [Hans de Jonge from NWO](https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69), funding metadata’s value is in the transparency of the relationships it enables. The system is powered by the collective action of the research community– including research funders – that registers open metadata with Crossref, making these relationships possible. With close to 180,000 grant records in our corpus we wanted to know how far they reach and what story they tell.

In March 2022, we [developed an approach for linking grants to research outputs](https://doi.org/10.64000/ske16-xve54) and analysed how many such relationships could be established. Now we’re able to present [the latest dataset](https://doi.org/10.13003/aexidu9f) that contains relationships between grants and research outputs, both those deposited by Crossref members and discovered by an automated matching strategy. It includes data deposited up to the end of July 2025.

This work is part of our ongoing [Metadata Matching](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/) project.

## What exactly is in this new open dataset of grant&#60;&#62;output relationships?

- The dataset contains 250,163 total funding relationships between grants and research outputs.
- We welcomed a number of funders, such as the [Dutch Research Council](https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69) and [Fonds de Recherche du Quebec](https://frq.gouv.qc.ca/en/persistent-unique-identifiers-doi/), which together registered almost 27,000 grants in the past year.
- It’s clear that the more grant metadata is registered the more funding relationships we can uncover.
- The percentage of relationships that are registered explicitly by Crossref members providing grants IDs in funding information has grown from less than 0.1% in 2023 to 1% (modest numbers but amazing growth!).

### The methodology

We created [a dataset of relationships between grants and research outputs](https://doi.org/10.13003/aexidu9f) by analysing their metadata in several ways. A relationship is included in the dataset if at least one of the following conditions is met:

- A relationship was explicitly deposited by a Crossref member through a _finances_ or _isFinancedBy_ [relationship](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/relationships/): 488 (0.2%) relationships
- The research output contains the grant DOI within the award number in the funding metadata: 2,003 (0.8%) relationships
- The award numbers in the grant and the research output are similar, and the associated funding organisations are either the same, or one is the sub-organisation of the other: 247,672 (99%) relationships

The dataset includes data deposited until the end of July 2025 and contains 250,163 total relationships.

The code used to generate the dataset is available [in our GitLab repository](https://gitlab.com/crossref/data-science/matching-tools/-/tree/main/grant_matching/offline_dataset?ref_type=heads).

### The results

As you can see in the graph below, the number of relationships grant-research output continues to grow as the number of grants records Crossref members register with us increases.

![Graph of the number of relationships grant-research output](https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2025/graph-grant-research-output.png)

**Figure 1:** Cumulative totals of grants, linked grants, research outputs, and grant–research output relationships from 2019 to 2025. Stepwise increases correspond to the addition of major funder datasets, including Wellcome (2020), OSTI (2021), JST (2022), the European Union (2022), the Austrian Science Fund (2023), and the Fonds de recherche du Québec (2025).

Looking at the numbers broken down by grant registrants we can see that the more grants registered the more relationships can be uncovered. The table below shows funders who have at least 1,000 total grants registered and for whom at least 10% of their registered grants are linked to research outputs, showing the number of relationships, grants, linked grants and linked research outputs (sorted by the percentage of linked grants), and compared with the data from the 2023 analysis (where available) to see how the uptake of open funding metadata is evolving.

FunderRelationshipsLinked research outputsGrantsNumber of linked grantsPercentage of linked grants2023202520232025202320252023202520232025European Union86,979128,57278,576114,49139,70353,47314,86021,40237.4%40%Japan Science and Technology Agency19,54930,72816,26525,0039,92311,8662,6093,90026.3%32.9%Wellcome34,25445,59625,72033,78317,54719,9295,2386,20629.9%31.1%American Cancer Society50604495863801,162342778.9%23.8%American Heart Association (AHA)401,040389355982,764306215%22.5%Fundacao para a Ciencia e a Tecnologia027,915015,681517,42203,793–21.8%Austrian Science Fund (FWF)–10,387–7,459–19,576–2,712–13.9%

**Table 1:** Comparison between data from 2023-07-31 and 2025-07-31 of a number of Crossref members registering grants. It shows the number of relationships, grants, linked grants and linked research outputs, sorted by the percentage of linked grants.

We encourage funders to join as members once they have determined the means of effective implementation of the GLS within their processes. By further analysing metadata of matched outputs, funders have the opportunity to monitor compliance with their policies and learn more about the impact of their programs.

### Following through funders’ Open Science commitments

The relationships showcased above and in the recent analysis are powered by open funding metadata. Open funding metadata plays a central role in building a transparent, accountable and high integrity research environment by making visible the connections between the funding, grantees, research outputs, and their impact. Funders’ openness mandates and Open Science commitments emphasize the importance of traceability in the research process, so ensuring that the support given-whether financial or otherwise-can be systematically recorded and shared is instrumental. Openness is also part of the strategic plans of institutions such as the International Science Council, who has [explicitly called for greater transparency in funding](https://council.science/blog/fighting-disinformation-with-sunshine-promoting-funding-transparency-in-science/) as a way to strengthen trust in science and counter misinformation. At the same time, initiatives such as the [Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information](https://barcelona-declaration.org/) underscores the benefits of open, reusable funding metadata for monitoring, evaluation and assessment of research and researchers.

Crossref’s Grant Linking System offers funders’ a way to demonstrate a commitment to openness, modeling the standards they expect of the research community they support, while creating a more robust, trustworthy and collaborative research ecosystem.

### Economy of scale: unlocking relationships with Crossref

Crossref houses millions of records, from the ubiquitous research articles and preprints, to books, peer review records, technical reports, datasets – you name it. Our members not only register, but also regularly update their metadata as new or corrected information becomes available. Our matching workflows allow us to make visible the hidden relationships and complete and improve the metadata records by adding new and reciprocal assertions.

This analysis shows the unique value of registering funding metadata with Crossref and adding an essential piece to the Research Nexus puzzle. **The relationship metadata allows the funding that underpins the research process to be connected, and contextualise scattered data points, acting as an anchor that links publications, people, and other research outputs.** This is made possible by the impressive number of records continuously being registered by more than 23,000 member organisations, and by the increasing availability of funding information in the system with more research funders joining in and registering their grant metadata with us.

### Next steps

As we welcome more and more funders to the GLS, we, collectively, continue to complete the Research Nexus, record by record, field by field. The more awards we have in our corpus the more relationships we’ll uncover, so we’ll keep making these analyses periodically to make sure we don’t miss them.

But it is not all on us. We are working towards a vision where Crossref Grant IDs are business as usual – where funders register their awards, grantees are aware of them and share them with publishers, and those publishers share them back with us when registering their content – closing the loop organically. We continue working on making this easier. In the upcoming works schema update a specific Crossref Grant ID field will be added in the funding information, alongside Award ID (for an internal identifier).

Crucially, as the momentum of adoption among funders increases, and thousands of Crossref Grant IDs are available in the system, we are working with all members to raise their attention to the importance and desirability of funding metadata, so inclusion of that information in metadata of all works increases and consequently, the percentage of relationships asserted by Crossref members can grow.

This matching analysis is just one example of what we do to enrich metadata to highlight relationships among works, individuals, institutions, and actions. Earlier this year, [we launched the Metadata Matching project](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/), which is a major effort to rebuild our matching workflows using modern software development and data science practices. As part of the project, we plan to expose additional matched relationships between grants and research outputs in our REST API, alongside those deposited by our members. We’ll keep you updated as we go along!

Read more about metadata matching in the blog series:

- [Metadata matching 101: what is it and why do we need it?](https://doi.org/10.13003/aewi1cai)
- [The anatomy of metadata matching](https://doi.org/10.13003/zie7reeg)
- [The myth of perfect metadata matching](https://doi.org/10.13003/pied3tho)
- [How good is your matching?](https://doi.org/10.13003/ief7aibi)
- [Metadata matching: beyond correctness](https://doi.org/10.13003/axeer1ee)</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/piecing-together-the-research-nexus-uncovering-relationships-with-open-funding-metadata/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Institutional Collaborations at the MAP Pilot Workshop</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/new-institutional-collaborations-at-the-map-pilot-workshop/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 30, 2025, 2:34 pm ET Representatives from the Machine Actionable Plans (MAP) pilot institutions and other institutions interested in the implementation of machine-actionable data management plans...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/new-institutional-collaborations-at-the-map-pilot-workshop/">New Institutional Collaborations at the MAP Pilot Workshop</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on September 30, 2025, 2:34 pm ET Representatives from the Machine Actionable Plans (MAP) pilot institutions and other institutions interested in the implementation of machine-actionable data management plans...

The post [New Institutional Collaborations at the MAP Pilot Workshop](https://www.arl.org/blog/new-institutional-collaborations-at-the-map-pilot-workshop/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=46182</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>September 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/our-priorities/advocacy-public-policy/public-policy-briefing/september-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on September 30, 2025, 12:15 pm ET Subscribe to the Public Policy Briefing ARL Public Policy Briefing (September 2025) This issue includes: Copyright and Fair Use/Fair Dealing ARL...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/our-priorities/advocacy-public-policy/public-policy-briefing/september-2025/">September 2025</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on September 30, 2025, 12:15 pm ET Subscribe to the Public Policy Briefing ARL Public Policy Briefing (September 2025) This issue includes: Copyright and Fair Use/Fair Dealing ARL...

The post [September 2025](https://www.arl.org/our-priorities/advocacy-public-policy/public-policy-briefing/september-2025/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=46170</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post – Taxonomy of Delegation: How GAIDeT Reframes AI Transparency in Science, an Interview with Yana Suchikova</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/30/guest-post-taxonomy-of-delegation-how-gaidet-reframes-ai-transparency-in-science-an-interview-with-yana-suchikova/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today, we speak with Prof. Yana Suchikova about GAIDeT, the Generative AI Delegation Taxonomy, which enables researchers to disclose the use of generative AI in an honest and transparent way.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/30/guest-post-taxonomy-of-delegation-how-gaidet-reframes-ai-transparency-in-science-an-interview-with-yana-suchikova/">Guest Post – Taxonomy of Delegation: How GAIDeT Reframes AI Transparency in Science, an Interview with Yana Suchikova</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today, we speak with Prof. Yana Suchikova about GAIDeT, the Generative AI Delegation Taxonomy, which enables researchers to disclose the use of generative AI in an honest and transparent way.

The post [Guest Post – Taxonomy of Delegation: How GAIDeT Reframes AI Transparency in Science, an Interview with Yana Suchikova](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/30/guest-post-taxonomy-of-delegation-how-gaidet-reframes-ai-transparency-in-science-an-interview-with-yana-suchikova/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61040</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Day in Review (September 29–October 2)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-september-29-october-2/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on October 2, 2025, 2:47 pm ET Day in Review highlights news and other stories of interest to the research library community in the US and Canada. Released Monday...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-september-29-october-2/">Day in Review (September 29–October 2)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on October 2, 2025, 2:47 pm ET Day in Review highlights news and other stories of interest to the research library community in the US and Canada. Released Monday...

The post [Day in Review (September 29–October 2)](https://www.arl.org/day-in-review/day-in-review-september-29-october-2/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=46147</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Artificial Intelligence Safety: An Interview with Stanford Research Fellow Duncan Eddy</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2025/09/duncan-eddy-interview/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In this interview, Stanford Research Fellow Dr. Duncan Eddy reflects on his professional background, shifting his focus on artificial intelligence safety standards, and what he is currently working on. He offers insightful observations from his work in AI safety and advice for future professionals. Dr. Eddy shared his experiences with the Library&#8217;s Artificial Intelligence Community &#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In this interview, Stanford Research Fellow Dr. Duncan Eddy reflects on his professional background, shifting his focus on artificial intelligence safety standards, and what he is currently working on. He offers insightful observations from his work in AI safety and advice for future professionals. Dr. Eddy shared his experiences with the Library’s Artificial Intelligence Community …</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/?p=36133</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Octopus, by Frank Norris</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/frank-norris/the-octopus</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Wheat growers in nineteenth-century California resist when a railroad company attempts to take possession of their farms.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Wheat growers in nineteenth-century California resist when a railroad company attempts to take possession of their farms.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/frank-norris/the-octopus/downloads/frank-norris_the-octopus.epub?source=feed" length="1462396" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/frank-norris/the-octopus</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Sir Tim Berners-Lee to Receive the 2025 Internet Archive Hero Award</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2025/09/29/sir-tim-berners-lee-to-receive-the-2025-internet-archive-hero-award/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Celebrating 1 trillion web pages archived, the Internet Archive is proud to honor the visionary who made it all possible. As announced in The New Yorker, this year&#8217;s Internet Archive [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Celebrating 1 trillion web pages archived, the Internet Archive is proud to honor the visionary who made it all possible. As announced in The New Yorker, this year’s Internet Archive \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29383</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Death of the LGBTQ+ Suicide Prevention Line</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/29/the-death-of-the-lgbtq-suicide-prevention-line/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In today’s post, Teodoro (Teo) Pulvirenti and Marianne Calilhanna join Randy Townsend to unpack the disturbing topic of suicide among the LGBTQ+ community.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/29/the-death-of-the-lgbtq-suicide-prevention-line/">The Death of the LGBTQ+ Suicide Prevention Line</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In today’s post, Teodoro (Teo) Pulvirenti and Marianne Calilhanna join Randy Townsend to unpack the disturbing topic of suicide among the LGBTQ+ community.

The post [The Death of the LGBTQ+ Suicide Prevention Line](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/29/the-death-of-the-lgbtq-suicide-prevention-line/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61043</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>When Charles the First Was King, by J. S. Fletcher</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/j-s-fletcher/when-charles-the-first-was-king</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Serving for the Royalist cause affects the domestic life of a young Yorkshire farmer during the English Civil War.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Serving for the Royalist cause affects the domestic life of a young Yorkshire farmer during the English Civil War.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/j-s-fletcher/when-charles-the-first-was-king/downloads/j-s-fletcher_when-charles-the-first-was-king.epub?source=feed" length="776953" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/j-s-fletcher/when-charles-the-first-was-king</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Generative AI on the College Internship</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/the-impact-of-generative-ai-on-the-college-internship/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Beneath the headlines of white collar lay-offs as companies explore the potential of generative AI to do entry-level office work, another change to the workforce is happening that may be of more immediate concern to current students and higher education institutions. The college internship is changing along with the rest of the American employment landscape. Students and administrators alike should prepare for what is happening now and begin thinking about what may happen over the next several years.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/the-impact-of-generative-ai-on-the-college-internship/">The Impact of Generative AI on the College Internship</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Beneath the headlines of white collar lay-offs as companies explore the potential of generative AI to do entry-level office work, another change to the workforce is happening that may be of more immediate concern to current students and higher education institutions. The college internship is changing along with the rest of the American employment landscape. Students and administrators alike should prepare for what is happening now and begin thinking about what may happen over the next several years.

The post [The Impact of Generative AI on the College Internship](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/the-impact-of-generative-ai-on-the-college-internship/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323699</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post – From Publications to Policy: How Research Is Driving Progress on the SDGs</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/26/guest-post-from-publications-to-policy-how-research-is-driving-progress-on-the-sdgs/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest bloggers share analysis on the relationship between impact and policy during Global Goals Week 2025.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/26/guest-post-from-publications-to-policy-how-research-is-driving-progress-on-the-sdgs/">Guest Post – From Publications to Policy: How Research Is Driving Progress on the SDGs</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest bloggers share analysis on the relationship between impact and policy during Global Goals Week 2025.

The post [Guest Post – From Publications to Policy: How Research Is Driving Progress on the SDGs](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/26/guest-post-from-publications-to-policy-how-research-is-driving-progress-on-the-sdgs/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61032</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Old English Baron, by Clara Reeve</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clara-reeve/the-old-english-baron</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An aging knight returns home after years of service only to learn of his friend’s tragic death.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>An aging knight returns home after years of service only to learn of his friend’s tragic death.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clara-reeve/the-old-english-baron/downloads/clara-reeve_the-old-english-baron.epub?source=feed" length="386110" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clara-reeve/the-old-english-baron</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Cherry Orchard, by Anton Chekhov</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/the-cherry-orchard/constance-garnett</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A heavily indebted landowner and her family return to Russia in an attempt to save her estate from being auctioned off.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A heavily indebted landowner and her family return to Russia in an attempt to save her estate from being auctioned off.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/the-cherry-orchard/constance-garnett/downloads/anton-chekhov_the-cherry-orchard_constance-garnett.epub?source=feed" length="681818" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/anton-chekhov/the-cherry-orchard/constance-garnett</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Bound to Browsable: Unlocking the Historical Media Publications Collection</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2025/09/unlocking-historical-media-publications/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This post details the exciting transformation of the Historical Media Publications Collection, a challenging digital collection of historical media industry magazines spanning the late 19th to mid-20th century. Expanding online presentation from dense bound volumes into searchable, issue-level resources, this collaborative project improved discoverability and usability of this collection and set a foundation for working with other serialized content though innovative new workflows and next-generation content management.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>This post details the exciting transformation of the Historical Media Publications Collection, a challenging digital collection of historical media industry magazines spanning the late 19th to mid-20th century. Expanding online presentation from dense bound volumes into searchable, issue-level resources, this collaborative project improved discoverability and usability of this collection and set a foundation for working with other serialized content though innovative new workflows and next-generation content management.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/?p=36095</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>More Than a Major</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/more-than-a-major/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Prior research on the value of a liberal arts and sciences education has traditionally relied on two proxies for whether students receive a liberal education: what they majored in or what type of institution they attended. We contend that this view is limited. Rather than assume that major and institutional type are adequate proxies, our 2020 research led us to develop a clearer, more comprehensive definition and measure of a liberal education. </p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/more-than-a-major/">More Than a Major</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Prior research on the value of a liberal arts and sciences education has traditionally relied on two proxies for whether students receive a liberal education: what they majored in or what type of institution they attended. We contend that this view is limited. Rather than assume that major and institutional type are adequate proxies, our 2020 research led us to develop a clearer, more comprehensive definition and measure of a liberal education.

The post [More Than a Major](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/more-than-a-major/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=323696</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — If a Tree Falls with Nobody Around to Record its Exact Location, Was it Even Compliant?</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/25/guest-post-if-a-tree-falls-with-nobody-around-to-record-its-exact-location-was-it-even-compliant/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The EU Deforestation Regulation (EUDR) could make millions of books illegal in Europe, forcing publishers to pulp stock and raising costs for readers. What changes should publishers be asking the EU to make before the regulation comes in?</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/25/guest-post-if-a-tree-falls-with-nobody-around-to-record-its-exact-location-was-it-even-compliant/">Guest Post — If a Tree Falls with Nobody Around to Record its Exact Location, Was it Even Compliant?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The EU Deforestation Regulation (EUDR) could make millions of books illegal in Europe, forcing publishers to pulp stock and raising costs for readers. What changes should publishers be asking the EU to make before the regulation comes in?

The post [Guest Post — If a Tree Falls with Nobody Around to Record its Exact Location, Was it Even Compliant?](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2025/09/25/guest-post-if-a-tree-falls-with-nobody-around-to-record-its-exact-location-was-it-even-compliant/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=60986</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Short Fiction, by Charles Beaumont</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/charles-beaumont/short-fiction</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of short fiction by Charles Beaumont.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A collection of short fiction by Charles Beaumont.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/charles-beaumont/short-fiction/downloads/charles-beaumont_short-fiction.epub?source=feed" length="523535" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/charles-beaumont/short-fiction</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Innovation in scientific publishing and its implications for Crossref DOI registration practices - Request for input</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/innovation-in-scientific-publishing-and-its-implications-for-crossref-doi-registration-practices-request-for-input/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><em>Lots of exciting innovations are being made in scientific publishing, often raising fundamental questions about established publishing practices. In this guest post, Ludo Waltman and André Brasil discuss the recently launched MetaROR publish-review-curate platform and the questions it raises about good practices for Crossref DOI registration in this emerging landscape.</em></p>
        <p>Digital Object Identifiers (DOIs) are unique identifiers commonly assigned to research outputs such as journal articles, preprints, peer review reports, and datasets. The DOI of a research output allows the output to be identified online in a persistent way, even when the underlying publishing infrastructure changes (e.g., a journal moving from one publisher to another).</p>
        <p>There are several DOI registration agencies. Most of the larger scientific publishers work with Crossref, and so do many preprint servers, and therefore our focus in this post is on Crossref. Crossref also keeps track of <a href="https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5_v2" target="_blank">metadata associated with research outputs</a>, such as the title, authors, and publication date of an output, and it makes this metadata openly available via APIs for all kinds of services to ingest and reuse. Because indexing, discovery, and evaluation tools rely heavily on this metadata, <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/content-registration/">content registration practices</a> and metadata design choices can have major effects on the visibility and findability of research outputs and on analytics used to monitor and assess research outputs and their contributors.</p>
        <p>For the most common types of research outputs, such as journal articles and preprints, a broad consensus has emerged over the past decades on good practices for DOI registration. Such consensus means that articles are assigned the record type ‘article’ in their Crossref metadata. Likewise, many preprint servers register DOIs for preprints at Crossref, with the record type ‘preprint’ in the metadata. (The arXiv preprint server is an exception; it registers DOIs for preprints with DataCite rather than Crossref.)</p>
        <p>For innovative new publication platforms, however, good practices for DOI registration are less clear. The approaches to scientific publishing offered by these platforms often do not fit neatly into established ways of working. For instance, for some of these platforms, the traditional distinction between peer-reviewed articles published in scientific journals and non-peer-reviewed articles posted on preprint servers is no longer applicable. This raises fundamental questions about suitable DOI registration practices for new approaches to scientific publishing.</p>
        <h2 id="metaror">MetaROR</h2>
        <p>The <a href="https://metaror.org/" target="_blank">MetaROR (MetaResearch Open Review) platform</a>, launched in November 2024 by the Research on Research Institute (RoRI) and the Association for Interdisciplinary Meta-Research and Open Science (AIMOS), offers an example of the challenge of developing appropriate DOI registration practices for new publishing models.</p>
        <p>Inspired by similar initiatives such as <a href="https://elifesciences.org/" target="_blank">eLife</a> and others, MetaROR adopts the so-called <a href="https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/h7swt" target="_blank">publish-review-curate model</a>. Authors first publish their article on a preprint server and then submit it to MetaROR. MetaROR then organizes an open peer review process for the article. Review reports are published on the MetaROR platform, along with a copy of the preprinted article and an editorial assessment. Rather than a simple binary decision (accept vs. reject), an editorial assessment is a short one-paragraph statement summarizing the strengths and weaknesses of an article. Each review report and each editorial assessment has its own DOI registered at Crossref. In this way, review reports are treated as first-class research outputs that can, for instance, be indexed in scientific literature databases and can be cited in other research outputs.</p>
        <p>For an article submitted to MetaROR, the publication of the review reports, the editorial assessment, and a copy of the article itself concludes MetaROR’s publish-review-curate process. The authors of the article may revise their work in light of the feedback received, and MetaROR may review the revised article. However, there is no requirement that revisions must be made. The primary aim of the review reports and the editorial assessment published on the MetaROR platform is to offer context for readers of the article, helping readers understand the strengths and weaknesses of the article.</p>
        <h2 id="crossref-doi-registration">Crossref DOI registration</h2>
        <p><a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/peer-reviews/" target="_blank">Registration of DOIs</a> for open peer review reports is <a href="https://www.leidenmadtrics.nl/articles/the-growth-of-open-peer-review" target="_blank">increasingly common</a>. By registering Crossref DOIs for review reports and editorial assessments, MetaROR enables reviewers and editors to be recognized for their contributions. But what about recognition for authors?</p>
        <p>A crucial element in MetaROR’s philosophy is that authors of articles peer-reviewed by MetaROR deserve to be recognized in a similar way as authors of articles published in traditional peer-reviewed journals. One way to promote appropriate recognition for authors of articles peer-reviewed by MetaROR is to ensure that articles on the MetaROR platform, just like articles in peer-reviewed journals, <a href="https://www.openscience.nl/en/cases/the-metaror-publish-review-curate-model-our-experience-as-authors" target="_blank">have their own DOI</a>. While this may seem straightforward to arrange, it actually raises two non-trivial questions about good practices for Crossref DOI registration:</p>
        <ol>
        <li>For each article on the MetaROR platform, there is a corresponding article on a preprint server. Is it acceptable to have two Crossref DOIs, one registered by the preprint server and one registered by the MetaROR platform, for essentially the same article?</li>
        <li>If Crossref DOIs are registered for articles on the MetaROR platform, should the articles be assigned the type ‘article’ or the type ‘preprint’ in their Crossref metadata, or something else entirely?</li>
        </ol>
        <p>On the first question, it could be argued that having <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/xjgnq-a3p05" target="_blank">two Crossref DOIs for the same article</a> is problematic and that MetaROR, therefore, should not register DOIs for articles on its platform. Alternatively, one could argue that an article on the MetaROR platform differs in a meaningful way from the corresponding article on a preprint server, since the article on the MetaROR platform has been enriched with peer review reports and an editorial assessment, similar to the way an article in a peer-reviewed journal may be seen as an enriched version of the corresponding article on a preprint server. This line of reasoning would justify registering DOIs for articles on the MetaROR platform.</p>
        <p>On the second question, the argument could be made that articles on the MetaROR platform should be assigned the type ‘preprint’ in their Crossref metadata, since the type ‘article’ is intended for articles in journals and MetaROR does not consider itself to be a journal (in fact, MetaROR works with <a href="https://cms.metaror.org/partner-journals/" target="_blank">partner journals</a> to enable articles peer-reviewed by MetaROR to be published in journals) and does not certify articles in the way journals do (i.e., MetaROR does not make accept/reject decisions). On the other hand, one could argue that articles on the MetaROR platform should be assigned the type ‘article’, since the peer-reviewed nature of articles in journals is typically seen as the key factor distinguishing these articles from articles on preprint servers. Articles on the MetaROR platform have been peer-reviewed, and in that sense, they resemble articles in journals. A third line of reasoning could be that neither the ‘preprint’ nor the ‘article’ type is fully appropriate for articles on the MetaROR platform and, consequently, that there is a need for a new Crossref record type.</p>
        <h2 id="what-is-your-take">What is your take?</h2>
        <p>The MetaROR team, in consultation with Crossref, will need to decide how to deal with the two questions discussed in this blog post. After some preliminary conversations between the MetaROR team and Crossref, we decided to share these questions more widely to solicit input from the broader community. We invite you to share your thoughts on the two questions, either by posting a comment on this blog post or by reaching out to us on social media or by email. Community perspectives will help shape good practices not only for MetaROR but also for other publish-review-curate initiatives facing similar questions. We look forward to hearing from you!</p>
        <p><em>Ludo Waltman and André Brasil are members of the editorial team of MetaROR. Ludo and André are grateful to Ginny Hendricks at Crossref for valuable discussions about the issues raised in this blog post.</em></p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>_Lots of exciting innovations are being made in scientific publishing, often raising fundamental questions about established publishing practices. In this guest post, Ludo Waltman and André Brasil discuss the recently launched MetaROR publish-review-curate platform and the questions it raises about good practices for Crossref DOI registration in this emerging landscape._

Digital Object Identifiers (DOIs) are unique identifiers commonly assigned to research outputs such as journal articles, preprints, peer review reports, and datasets. The DOI of a research output allows the output to be identified online in a persistent way, even when the underlying publishing infrastructure changes (e.g., a journal moving from one publisher to another).

There are several DOI registration agencies. Most of the larger scientific publishers work with Crossref, and so do many preprint servers, and therefore our focus in this post is on Crossref. Crossref also keeps track of [metadata associated with research outputs](https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5_v2), such as the title, authors, and publication date of an output, and it makes this metadata openly available via APIs for all kinds of services to ingest and reuse. Because indexing, discovery, and evaluation tools rely heavily on this metadata, [content registration practices](https://www.crossref.org/services/content-registration/) and metadata design choices can have major effects on the visibility and findability of research outputs and on analytics used to monitor and assess research outputs and their contributors.

For the most common types of research outputs, such as journal articles and preprints, a broad consensus has emerged over the past decades on good practices for DOI registration. Such consensus means that articles are assigned the record type ‘article’ in their Crossref metadata. Likewise, many preprint servers register DOIs for preprints at Crossref, with the record type ‘preprint’ in the metadata. (The arXiv preprint server is an exception; it registers DOIs for preprints with DataCite rather than Crossref.)

For innovative new publication platforms, however, good practices for DOI registration are less clear. The approaches to scientific publishing offered by these platforms often do not fit neatly into established ways of working. For instance, for some of these platforms, the traditional distinction between peer-reviewed articles published in scientific journals and non-peer-reviewed articles posted on preprint servers is no longer applicable. This raises fundamental questions about suitable DOI registration practices for new approaches to scientific publishing.

## MetaROR

The [MetaROR (MetaResearch Open Review) platform](https://metaror.org/), launched in November 2024 by the Research on Research Institute (RoRI) and the Association for Interdisciplinary Meta-Research and Open Science (AIMOS), offers an example of the challenge of developing appropriate DOI registration practices for new publishing models.

Inspired by similar initiatives such as [eLife](https://elifesciences.org/) and others, MetaROR adopts the so-called [publish-review-curate model](https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/h7swt). Authors first publish their article on a preprint server and then submit it to MetaROR. MetaROR then organizes an open peer review process for the article. Review reports are published on the MetaROR platform, along with a copy of the preprinted article and an editorial assessment. Rather than a simple binary decision (accept vs. reject), an editorial assessment is a short one-paragraph statement summarizing the strengths and weaknesses of an article. Each review report and each editorial assessment has its own DOI registered at Crossref. In this way, review reports are treated as first-class research outputs that can, for instance, be indexed in scientific literature databases and can be cited in other research outputs.

For an article submitted to MetaROR, the publication of the review reports, the editorial assessment, and a copy of the article itself concludes MetaROR’s publish-review-curate process. The authors of the article may revise their work in light of the feedback received, and MetaROR may review the revised article. However, there is no requirement that revisions must be made. The primary aim of the review reports and the editorial assessment published on the MetaROR platform is to offer context for readers of the article, helping readers understand the strengths and weaknesses of the article.

## Crossref DOI registration

[Registration of DOIs](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus/peer-reviews/) for open peer review reports is [increasingly common](https://www.leidenmadtrics.nl/articles/the-growth-of-open-peer-review). By registering Crossref DOIs for review reports and editorial assessments, MetaROR enables reviewers and editors to be recognized for their contributions. But what about recognition for authors?

A crucial element in MetaROR’s philosophy is that authors of articles peer-reviewed by MetaROR deserve to be recognized in a similar way as authors of articles published in traditional peer-reviewed journals. One way to promote appropriate recognition for authors of articles peer-reviewed by MetaROR is to ensure that articles on the MetaROR platform, just like articles in peer-reviewed journals, [have their own DOI](https://www.openscience.nl/en/cases/the-metaror-publish-review-curate-model-our-experience-as-authors). While this may seem straightforward to arrange, it actually raises two non-trivial questions about good practices for Crossref DOI registration:

1. For each article on the MetaROR platform, there is a corresponding article on a preprint server. Is it acceptable to have two Crossref DOIs, one registered by the preprint server and one registered by the MetaROR platform, for essentially the same article?
2. If Crossref DOIs are registered for articles on the MetaROR platform, should the articles be assigned the type ‘article’ or the type ‘preprint’ in their Crossref metadata, or something else entirely?

On the first question, it could be argued that having [two Crossref DOIs for the same article](https://doi.org/10.64000/xjgnq-a3p05) is problematic and that MetaROR, therefore, should not register DOIs for articles on its platform. Alternatively, one could argue that an article on the MetaROR platform differs in a meaningful way from the corresponding article on a preprint server, since the article on the MetaROR platform has been enriched with peer review reports and an editorial assessment, similar to the way an article in a peer-reviewed journal may be seen as an enriched version of the corresponding article on a preprint server. This line of reasoning would justify registering DOIs for articles on the MetaROR platform.

On the second question, the argument could be made that articles on the MetaROR platform should be assigned the type ‘preprint’ in their Crossref metadata, since the type ‘article’ is intended for articles in journals and MetaROR does not consider itself to be a journal (in fact, MetaROR works with [partner journals](https://cms.metaror.org/partner-journals/) to enable articles peer-reviewed by MetaROR to be published in journals) and does not certify articles in the way journals do (i.e., MetaROR does not make accept/reject decisions). On the other hand, one could argue that articles on the MetaROR platform should be assigned the type ‘article’, since the peer-reviewed nature of articles in journals is typically seen as the key factor distinguishing these articles from articles on preprint servers. Articles on the MetaROR platform have been peer-reviewed, and in that sense, they resemble articles in journals. A third line of reasoning could be that neither the ‘preprint’ nor the ‘article’ type is fully appropriate for articles on the MetaROR platform and, consequently, that there is a need for a new Crossref record type.

## What is your take?

The MetaROR team, in consultation with Crossref, will need to decide how to deal with the two questions discussed in this blog post. After some preliminary conversations between the MetaROR team and Crossref, we decided to share these questions more widely to solicit input from the broader community. We invite you to share your thoughts on the two questions, either by posting a comment on this blog post or by reaching out to us on social media or by email. Community perspectives will help shape good practices not only for MetaROR but also for other publish-review-curate initiatives facing similar questions. We look forward to hearing from you!

_Ludo Waltman and André Brasil are members of the editorial team of MetaROR. Ludo and André are grateful to Ginny Hendricks at Crossref for valuable discussions about the issues raised in this blog post._</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/innovation-in-scientific-publishing-and-its-implications-for-crossref-doi-registration-practices-request-for-input/</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
