<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:source="https://source.scripting.com/">
  <atom:link href="https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Library and Archives organizations</title>
    <link>https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/libraries.xml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>25 Jan 26 08:11 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.18</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Jibby Jones, by Ellis Parker Butler</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ellis-parker-butler/jibby-jones</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Five boys who live near the Mississippi River embark on an adventure to find hidden pirate treasure.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Five boys who live near the Mississippi River embark on an adventure to find hidden pirate treasure.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ellis-parker-butler/jibby-jones/downloads/ellis-parker-butler_jibby-jones.epub?source=feed" length="687636" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ellis-parker-butler/jibby-jones</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Recordings From Our Public Domain Day Celebrations are Now Available</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/23/recordings-from-our-public-domain-day-celebrations-are-now-available/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This week, Internet Archive celebrated Public Domain Day with a lively mix of ideas, art, and community. Session recordings are now available to revisit or discover the highlights. In our daytime virtual session, we [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>This week, Internet Archive celebrated Public Domain Day with a lively mix of ideas, art, and community. Session recordings are now available to revisit or discover the highlights. In our daytime virtual session, we \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=30020</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>SPARC and Curationist Join Widening Effort to Protect Our Future Memory</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/23/sparc-and-curationist-join-widening-effort-to-protect-our-future-memory/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Two more organizations—SPARC and Curationist—have decided to sign the Statement on Four Digital Rights for Memory Institutions Online, demonstrating its broad appeal to memory institutions of different stripes. SPARC and [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Two more organizations—SPARC and Curationist—have decided to sign the Statement on Four Digital Rights for Memory Institutions Online, demonstrating its broad appeal to memory institutions of different stripes. SPARC and \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=30011</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The rise of ‘predatory’ publishing</title>
      <link>https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/23/the-rise-of-predatory-publishing/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Over the past two decades, scientific publishing has undergone a technological and economic transformation that has opened the door to more unorthodox models and, unfortunately, predatory practices. Predatory publishing refers to journals and publishers that charge authors (very high fees) to publish, claim peer review and indexing practices that do not exist or are fraudulent, and prioritize quick revenue over scientific quality.  <span class="ellipsis">&#8230;</span> <span class="more-link-wrap"><a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/23/the-rise-of-predatory-publishing/" class="more-link"><span>Read More &#8594;</span></a></span></p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/23/the-rise-of-predatory-publishing/">The rise of ‘predatory’ publishing</a> first appeared on <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en">SciELO in Perspective</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Over the past two decades, scientific publishing has undergone a technological and economic transformation that has opened the door to more unorthodox models and, unfortunately, predatory practices. Predatory publishing refers to journals and publishers that charge authors (very high fees) to publish, claim peer review and indexing practices that do not exist or are fraudulent, and prioritize quick revenue over scientific quality. …[Read More →](https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/23/the-rise-of-predatory-publishing/)

The post [The rise of ‘predatory’ publishing](https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/23/the-rise-of-predatory-publishing/) first appeared on [SciELO in Perspective](https://blog.scielo.org/en).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.scielo.org/en/?p=5825</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Ladies Lindores, by Margaret Oliphant</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/margaret-oliphant/the-ladies-lindores</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The lives of three families of the Scottish gentry intertwine through love and conflict.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The lives of three families of the Scottish gentry intertwine through love and conflict.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/margaret-oliphant/the-ladies-lindores/downloads/margaret-oliphant_the-ladies-lindores.epub?source=feed" length="804433" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/margaret-oliphant/the-ladies-lindores</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Great News From GDELT Project: “A Transformative New Chapter: Translating The Entire Quarter-Century TV News Archive Through Gemini For Just $54K + All Channels Now Translated”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/23/great-news-from-gdelt-project-a-transformative-new-chapter-translating-the-entire-quarter-century-tv-news-archive-through-gemini-for-just-54k-all-channels-now-translated/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From a GDELT Project Post: Today we are announcing a transformative new chapter in planetary-scale translation and towards our vision of making it possible to see the world through others&#8217; eyes. In collaboration with the Internet Archive&#8217;s Television News Archive, we have completed the Gemini-powered machine translation of the Archive&#8217;s entire quarter-century archive of more [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From a GDELT Project Post: Today we are announcing a transformative new chapter in planetary-scale translation and towards our vision of making it possible to see the world through others’ eyes. In collaboration with the Internet Archive’s Television News Archive, we have completed the Gemini-powered machine translation of the Archive’s entire quarter-century archive of more \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167575</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post – The Next Era of Reference Management: An Interview with William Gunn</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/23/guest-post-the-next-era-of-reference-management-an-interview-with-william-gunn/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest post features an interview with William Gunn discussing how AI will (or won't!) change the future of reference management tools.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/23/guest-post-the-next-era-of-reference-management-an-interview-with-william-gunn/">Guest Post – The Next Era of Reference Management: An Interview with William Gunn</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest post features an interview with William Gunn discussing how AI will (or won&#39;t!) change the future of reference management tools.

The post [Guest Post – The Next Era of Reference Management: An Interview with William Gunn](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/23/guest-post-the-next-era-of-reference-management-an-interview-with-william-gunn/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61478</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>siegfried 1.11.4 released</title>
      <link>https://www.itforarchivists.com/post/sf1114/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Version 1.11.4 of siegfried is now available. Get it <a href="https://www.itforarchivists.com/siegfried">here</a>.</p>
        <h3 id="changelog-v1114-2026-01-23">CHANGELOG v1.11.4 (2026-01-23)</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>update go version to 1.24.0</li>
        <li>Roy speed-up by avoiding function calls in loops. Fixes #148. Implemented by Ross Spencer</li>
        <li>update PRONOM to v122</li>
        <li>update LOC to 2025-12-09</li>
        <li>update TIKA to v3.2.3</li>
        </ul>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Version 1.11.4 of siegfried is now available. Get it [here](https://www.itforarchivists.com/siegfried).

### CHANGELOG v1.11.4 (2026-01-23)

- update go version to 1.24.0
- Roy speed-up by avoiding function calls in loops. Fixes #148. Implemented by Ross Spencer
- update PRONOM to v122
- update LOC to 2025-12-09
- update TIKA to v3.2.3</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.itforarchivists.com/post/sf1114/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Atlantic: “Science is Drowning in AI Slop”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/22/the-atlantic-science-is-drowning-in-ai-slop/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From The Atlantic. (via MSN): Scientific publishing has always had its plumbing problems. Even before ChatGPT, journal editors struggled to control the quantity and quality of submitted work. Alex Csiszar, a historian of science at Harvard, told me that he has found letters from editors going all the way back to the early 19th century [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From The Atlantic. (via MSN): Scientific publishing has always had its plumbing problems. Even before ChatGPT, journal editors struggled to control the quantity and quality of submitted work. Alex Csiszar, a historian of science at Harvard, told me that he has found letters from editors going all the way back to the early 19th century \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167573</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — The Ghost in the Machine: Why Generative AI is a Crisis of Authorship, Not Just a Tool</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/22/guest-post-the-ghost-in-the-machine-why-generative-ai-is-a-crisis-of-authorship-not-just-a-tool/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest author raises the question of whether a researcher submitting an article that was significantly drafted by an LLM without clear disclosure is effectively engaging in a contemporary form of ghost authorship.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/22/guest-post-the-ghost-in-the-machine-why-generative-ai-is-a-crisis-of-authorship-not-just-a-tool/">Guest Post &#8212; The Ghost in the Machine: Why Generative AI is a Crisis of Authorship, Not Just a Tool</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest author raises the question of whether a researcher submitting an article that was significantly drafted by an LLM without clear disclosure is effectively engaging in a contemporary form of ghost authorship.

The post [Guest Post — The Ghost in the Machine: Why Generative AI is a Crisis of Authorship, Not Just a Tool](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/22/guest-post-the-ghost-in-the-machine-why-generative-ai-is-a-crisis-of-authorship-not-just-a-tool/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61475</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Insights from a roundtable on author affiliation metadata</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/insights-from-a-roundtable-on-author-affiliation-metadata/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>It’s been said that Americans are unusual in tending to ask “Where do you work?” as an initial question upon introduction to a new acquaintance, indicating a perhaps unhealthy preoccupation with work as identity. But in the context of published research, “What is this author&rsquo;s affiliation?” is a question of global importance that goes beyond just wanting to know the name &ndash; and perhaps prestige level &ndash; of the place a researcher works.</p>
        <p>When collected, used, and analyzed at scale, data about author affiliations can provide intriguing insights about international collaboration trends, signal trust and lack of trust in particular research institutions, generate business intelligence for publishers, help universities track the work their researchers do, help funders demonstrate the impact of their funding, and much more.</p>
        <p>In November we partnered with <a href="https://oaswitchboard.org/" target="_blank">OA Switchboard</a> to organize a roundtable on author affiliation metadata for the Crossref community, service and infrastructure providers, production vendors, data scientists, researchers, and librarians. We aimed to bring together scholarly information professionals with many diverse perspectives; ultimately, participants from more than 40 organizations joined the roundtable to share their experiences and their thoughts.</p>
        <p>In focusing on a single type of metadata, we hoped to focus our discussions, as well. Similarly, in October the Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information organized <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/" target="_blank">a roundtable on &ldquo;Moving Funding Metadata Forward&rdquo;</a> in which it became clear that “improving the quality and coverage of funding metadata was on the agenda of many organisations and there was a strong interest in collaborating on practical next steps.”</p>
        <p>While many of the issues and solutions discussed at both roundtables are similar, in the course of the author affiliation metadata roundtable we identified some unique challenges as well as benefits related to this particular flavor of information. In this blog post, I’ll share these insights.</p>
        <h2 id="insights-from-presenters">Insights from presenters</h2>
        <p>I opened the roundtable with a brief introduction and a working definition of affiliation metadata: names and/or identifiers such as <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/ror/" target="_blank">Research Organization Registry (ROR)</a> IDs for organizations where research was conducted or with which authors and contributors are associated, usually officially, as in their place of employment.</p>
        <p>Next, to create a shared context for discussion, we heard four presentations on the current state of author affiliation metadata, its importance, and Crossref’s ongoing initiative to enhance it automatically.</p>
        <p>Nees Jan van Eck of Leiden University’s <a href="https://www.universiteitleiden.nl/en/social-behavioural-sciences/cwts" target="_blank">Center for Science and Technology Studies (CWTS)</a> shared observations on the state of author affiliations from a preprint titled “<a href="https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5_v2" target="_blank">Crossref as a source of open bibliographic metadata</a>” that presents the findings of an analysis performed annually since 2021. Nees’s key points:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Crossref is a foundational data source for bibliographic metadata.</li>
        <li>Affiliation metadata is available for only 1 out of 3 journal articles in Crossref for the period 2023-2024.</li>
        <li>There is considerable variation in the extent to which Crossref members deposit affiliation metadata.</li>
        <li>Downstream sources try to fill gaps using suboptimal approaches, leading to missing, inaccurate, and inconsistent linking of publications to institutions.</li>
        <li>Publications lacking affiliation metadata in Crossref are less visible in bibliometric applications, analyses, studies, and tools (such as the <a href="https://open.leidenranking.com/" target="_blank">open edition of the Leiden Ranking</a> of over 2800 universities).</li>
        </ul>
        <p><figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-01.png"
        alt="Crossref as a source of open bibliographic metadata.">
        </figure>
        <br /></p>
        <p>Next, Yvonne Campfens of OA Switchboard reiterated the desirability of the Crossref community providing complete and accurate author affiliation metadata at the source. Yvonne called upon publishers to “Integrate metadata creation in your systems and workflows before publication and relay it throughout the editorial, production, and publication processes.”</p>
        <p>Yvonne pointed out that in the context of managing Open Access agreements, publishers ought to keep in mind that providing good affiliation metadata improves customer satisfaction, since institutions and consortia need to have that information in order to connect research to the correct organization. In closing, Yvonne featured best practices from <a href="https://www.oaswitchboard.org/dqc-publisherbestpractices" target="_blank">OA Switchboard’s Data Quality Challenge</a>:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>eLife captures affiliations at submissions with “author select,” ensuring that ROR IDs are introduced early and verified before publication, coupled with a quality assurance process during proofing. (See also our piece on <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/3gcdf-23s29" target="_blank">Metadata Excellence Award winner eLife</a>.)</li>
        <li>EMS Press captures metadata via manuscript extraction as early as at submission, building on globally valid identifiers whenever possible (ROR IDs, DOIs, ORCIDs).</li>
        <li>Pensoft Publishers uses AI-assisted metadata extraction with human review and in-house metadata validation.</li>
        <li>Beilstein-Institut performs post-acceptance metadata quality assurance through automation and expert review.</li>
        <li>The Royal Society embeds metadata in OA payment and agreement workflows.</li>
        <li>American Chemical Society (ACS) has a multi-method persistent identifier matching strategy with near-complete coverage.</li>
        <li>The American Society for Microbiology (ASM) combines AI-powered submission tools with editorial oversight via expert manual checks. (See also our piece on <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/xxwy3-xhf38" target="_blank">Metadata Excellence Award winner ASM</a>.)</li>
        <li>Rockefeller University Press (RUP) maintains ROR IDs across the full publishing workflow with “author select” at submission through metadata deposits upon publication. (See also the <a href="https://doi.org/10.71938/t63t-g186" target="_blank">ROR case study on RUP</a>.)</li>
        </ul>
        <p><figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-02.png"
        alt="Having great metadata improves your operational excellence.">
        </figure>
        <br /></p>
        <p>Adam Day of <a href="https://clear-skies.co.uk/" target="_blank">Clear Skies Ltd</a> began his talk by wryly framing the first and second rules of data science as contradictory: “Never fix data: always use sources that produce high-quality data in the first place,” but also “Get good at fixing data, because you will have to.” Adam went on to demonstrate the central role author affiliation metadata plays in research integrity investigations, displaying anonymized data for institutions with a high number of alerts. In conclusion, Adam reiterated the importance of author affiliation metadata to research integrity efforts:</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Data analysis is critical to research integrity.</li>
        <li>Quality data helps enormously by giving oversight, saving time, and assisting investigations.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-03.png"
        alt="Value comes from data.">
        </figure>
        <br /></p>
        <p>Lastly, our own Director of Technology <a href="https://www.crossref.org/people/dominika-tkaczyk" target="_blank">Dominika Tkaczyk</a> gave an account of our plans to enrich author affiliation metadata by matching organization name text strings to <a href="https://ror.org" target="_blank">ROR IDs</a> as part of our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/" target="_blank">metadata matching</a> initiative. A strategy for performing such matching has already been developed and tested and an <a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993" target="_blank">open dataset of results made available</a>. Tests on a set of 3,000 affiliations sampled from our metadata show that the strategy can be expected to match 95 million ROR IDs to organization names with 97.35% precision, an astronomical increase over the less than 1 million ROR IDs deposited in Crossref records to date.</p>
        <p>Dominika concluded the presentation portion of the session by reiterating that our planned enrichment of author affiliation metadata</p>
        <ul>
        <li>Will use flexible and transparent matching strategies (and <a href="https://gitlab.com/crossref/labs/marple/-/tree/main/strategies_available/affiliation_single_search" target="_blank">open code</a>),</li>
        <li>Will welcome community participation in developing new strategies, and</li>
        <li>Will be available in the REST API.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-04.png"
        alt="Matching affiliation strings to ROR IDs.">
        </figure>
        <br /></p>
        <p>Automatic matching of organization names to ROR IDs in author affiliations cannot solve the problem of missing organization names, of course, but it represents a huge leap forward in addressing metadata quality issues.</p>
        <p>All of our speakers&rsquo; presentations are available on Zenodo at <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw</a>.</p>
        <h2 id="insights-into-challenges">Insights into challenges</h2>
        <p>In the next stage of the event, participants broke into six breakout groups to identify factors contributing to incomplete or inaccurate affiliation metadata. Participants were pre-assigned to groups randomly by role to ensure a variety of perspectives in every discussion.</p>
        <p>At least two participants, it should be noted, pointed out that it would be helpful to agree on a definition of “complete” and “accurate” affiliation metadata, which in itself is a challenge, and one we did not address in this roundtable. For instance, practices most recently have trended away from defining a complete author affiliation in open metadata as including an institutional address, although many internal databases might include such information separately.</p>
        <p>Even without such definitions, however, all six groups were able to identify several general areas for attention, and one participant provided a particularly helpful categorization of these areas that is largely reused here.</p>
        <h3 id="inherent-data-complexity">Inherent data complexity</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Research organizations have names in different languages, abbreviations, and many other name variants.</li>
        <li>Research organizations have frequent name changes, mergers, and rebranding.</li>
        <li>Research organizations have different degrees, levels, and complexity of hierarchical granularity, and authors, publishers, and software systems are often misaligned as to which level in an organization&rsquo;s structure is appropriate to use in a particular instance.</li>
        <li>Research organizations often lack official policies on how affiliations should be written, leading to hundreds of variations for a single institution.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="author-related-issues">Author-related issues</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Corresponding authors often submit information for all co-authors, which can lead to inaccuracies.</li>
        <li>Many authors have multiple profiles across multiple submission systems, which can introduce errors.</li>
        <li>Authors may have “octopus affiliations,” claiming affiliations with many institutions that are difficult to verify.</li>
        <li>Authors may fail to update affiliations when changing institutions between manuscript acceptance and publication.</li>
        <li>Authors may demonstrate &ldquo;apathy&rdquo; when repeatedly filling out submission forms, sometimes providing incomplete, inconsistent, or incorrect information.</li>
        <li>On occasion, authors might even provide false or purchased affiliations, which of course is a significant research integrity concern.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="technical-barriers">Technical barriers</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Many manuscript tracking and peer review systems, especially legacy systems, lack structured fields for affiliations or don&rsquo;t support open organization identifiers like ROR.</li>
        <li>Some systems limit authors to a single affiliation, despite many researchers having multiple institutional connections.</li>
        <li>Some systems only collect affiliation information for the corresponding author.</li>
        <li>Some systems link affiliations to user accounts instead of to publications.</li>
        <li>Different systems use competing identifier registries, including proprietary identifier registries, creating interoperability challenges.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="publisher-practices">Publisher practices</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Even when publishers improve current metadata collection practices, historical data correction is resource-intensive and often not prioritized.</li>
        <li>Publishers collect affiliation information at submission but don’t ensure that it is maintained throughout all stages of the publication process and deposited in metadata.</li>
        <li>Some publishers are unaware of the importance of author affiliation metadata or do not prioritize its improvement.</li>
        <li>Some publishers deliberately choose not to deposit affiliation metadata to Crossref, viewing it as value-added information they&rsquo;ve invested in curating.</li>
        </ul>
        <h2 id="insights-into-solutions">Insights into solutions</h2>
        <p>Naturally, we didn’t rest at identifying challenges: after a break, we gathered in the same groups to brainstorm approaches to improving author affiliation metadata.</p>
        <h3 id="adopt-collective-approaches">Adopt collective approaches</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Collective action, where corrections and improvements made by various stakeholders flow back into shared systems, has historically worked for proprietary systems and could be even more powerful with open infrastructure.</li>
        <li>Since those who do not provide metadata “upstream” will inevitably have it provided for them “downstream” by multiple separate entities using multifarious methods, provenance metadata indicating who asserted author affiliations and how (whether automatically or with the author’s or editor’s input) would help metadata users assess trust levels.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="engage-authors-and-institutions">Engage authors and institutions</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Reach out to authors and institutions to educate them on the need for more consistent affiliation reporting, especially in terms of language, name format, and degree of hierarchical granularity.</li>
        <li>Demonstrate the benefit to institutions of maintaining accurate records in registries like ROR, including abbreviations and name variants.</li>
        <li>Publishers and/or software systems should allow authors to review (though not necessarily edit) affiliation information during the proofing process to verify accuracy. Authors should not, however, need to know, see, or use ROR IDs.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="improve-the-tech">Improve the tech</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Publishers would welcome submission systems that incorporate structured fields for author affiliations with well-designed auto-suggestions linked to ROR or other organization identifiers.</li>
        <li>Making affiliation data mandatory at submission could significantly improve capture rates, although it would be important to ensure that independent researchers can use these systems as well.</li>
        <li>Enable collection of affiliations for all authors, not just the corresponding author.</li>
        <li>Pull in <a href="https://info.orcid.org/trust-markers-in-orcid-records-verified-email-domains/" target="_blank">verified affiliation information from ORCID</a>.</li>
        <li>Increasingly, intelligent matching systems can be implemented to reduce author burden and perhaps also increase accuracy and completeness of metadata.</li>
        <li>Better crosswalks between different organization identifier systems would make it vastly easier for publishers to maintain better metadata. Since open registries cannot include proprietary information, proprietary registries should provide their customers with crosswalks to all standard open identifiers.</li>
        </ul>
        <h3 id="encourage-publisher-best-practices">Encourage publisher best practices</h3>
        <ul>
        <li>Publishers can use already-available tools to help assess and improve the quality of both new and legacy author affiliation metadata.
        <ul>
        <li><a href="https://crossref.org/members/prep/" target="_blank">Crossref’s Participation Reports</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://graph.openaire.eu/docs/10.5.1/graph-production-workflow/enrichment-by-mining/affiliation_matching/" target="_blank">OpenAIRE&rsquo;s affiliation matching methods and validation systems</a></li>
        <li><a href="https://ror.readme.io/docs/api-affiliation" target="_blank">ROR API affiliation matching service</a></li>
        </ul>
        </li>
        <li>Share the benefits of improved author affiliation metadata for internal and external analytics, customer satisfaction, and research integrity.</li>
        <li>Identify best practices in collecting and structuring author affiliation metadata.</li>
        <li>Understand that the entire research ecosystem would benefit from publishers sharing collected affiliation data with Crossref.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>It’s worth mentioning that these solutions are heterogeneous: not all strategies can be implemented by any one actor nor even by any one sector of our profession. Clearly, collaborative action is necessary for substantive change.</p>
        <h2 id="moving-forward">Moving forward</h2>
        <p>The affiliations metadata roundtable represented an important step in addressing affiliation metadata challenges in a productive and collaborative way. If there was a consensus, it was that while perfect completeness and accuracy of author affiliation metadata may not be achievable (or even definable), incremental improvements can substantially enhance the quality and availability of affiliation metadata for the entire scholarly information community.</p>
        <p>Here at Crossref, we intend to use the insights from this roundtable to inform our support of the Crossref community, including publishers, service providers, and metadata users. We welcome your comments, questions, and suggestions on this issue! <strong>Share your thoughts with Amanda French at <a href="mailto:alfrench@crossref.org">alfrench@crossref.org</a>.</strong></p>
        <h3 id="references">References</h3>
        <ol>
        <li>van Eck, N. J., &amp; Waltman, L. (2025). Crossref as a source of open bibliographic metadata (No. smxe5_v2). MetaArXiv. <a href="https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5_v2" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5_v2</a></li>
        <li>Tkaczyk, D. (2025). Crossref relationships involving research organisations [Dataset]. Zenodo. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993</a></li>
        <li>French, A., van Eck, N. J., Campfens, Y., Day, A., &amp; Tkaczyk, D. (2026, January 19). Affiliations Metadata Roundtable 2025—All Presentations. <a href="https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw</a></li>
        </ol>
        <h3 id="participating-organizations">Participating organizations</h3>
        <table>
        <thead>
        <tr>
        <th style="text-align: center"></th>
        <th></th>
        </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Africa PID Alliance / TCC Africa</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Frontiers Media SA</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">American Association of Cancer Research (AACR)</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Iowa State</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">American Chemical Society (ACS)</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Kriyadocs / Exeter Premedia Services</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">American Physical Society (APS)</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">MDPI</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">American Society for Microbiology (ASM)</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Noyam Publishers</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Aptara</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">OpenAIRE / OpenOrgs</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Australian Research Data Commons (ARDC)</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Optica Publishing Group</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Atypon</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">ORCID</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Beilstein-Institut</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Oxford University Press</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">California Digital Library (CDL)</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Public Knowledge Project (PKP)</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Cambridge University Press</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Public Library of Science (PLOS)</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Carnegie Mellon University</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">River Valley Technologies</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">CHORUS</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Rockefeller University Press</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Clarivate / Web of Science </td>
        <td style="text-align: center">SAGE Publications</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Copernicus GmBH</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Curtin University / Curtin Open Knowledge Initiative (COKI)</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Silverchair / ScholarOne</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">De Gruyter Brill</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">Springer Science &amp; Business</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Digital Science / Figshare</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">TNQTech</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Digital Science / Symplectic Elements</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">University of Laval</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">eLife</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">University of Chicago Press</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Elsevier BV</td>
        <td style="text-align: center">University of Split</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">Enago</td>
        <td></td>
        </tr>
        </tbody>
        </table>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>It’s been said that Americans are unusual in tending to ask “Where do you work?” as an initial question upon introduction to a new acquaintance, indicating a perhaps unhealthy preoccupation with work as identity. But in the context of published research, “What is this author’s affiliation?” is a question of global importance that goes beyond just wanting to know the name – and perhaps prestige level – of the place a researcher works.

When collected, used, and analyzed at scale, data about author affiliations can provide intriguing insights about international collaboration trends, signal trust and lack of trust in particular research institutions, generate business intelligence for publishers, help universities track the work their researchers do, help funders demonstrate the impact of their funding, and much more.

In November we partnered with [OA Switchboard](https://oaswitchboard.org/) to organize a roundtable on author affiliation metadata for the Crossref community, service and infrastructure providers, production vendors, data scientists, researchers, and librarians. We aimed to bring together scholarly information professionals with many diverse perspectives; ultimately, participants from more than 40 organizations joined the roundtable to share their experiences and their thoughts.

In focusing on a single type of metadata, we hoped to focus our discussions, as well. Similarly, in October the Barcelona Declaration on Open Research Information organized [a roundtable on “Moving Funding Metadata Forward”](https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/) in which it became clear that “improving the quality and coverage of funding metadata was on the agenda of many organisations and there was a strong interest in collaborating on practical next steps.”

While many of the issues and solutions discussed at both roundtables are similar, in the course of the author affiliation metadata roundtable we identified some unique challenges as well as benefits related to this particular flavor of information. In this blog post, I’ll share these insights.

## Insights from presenters

I opened the roundtable with a brief introduction and a working definition of affiliation metadata: names and/or identifiers such as [Research Organization Registry (ROR)](https://www.crossref.org/community/ror/) IDs for organizations where research was conducted or with which authors and contributors are associated, usually officially, as in their place of employment.

Next, to create a shared context for discussion, we heard four presentations on the current state of author affiliation metadata, its importance, and Crossref’s ongoing initiative to enhance it automatically.

Nees Jan van Eck of Leiden University’s [Center for Science and Technology Studies (CWTS)](https://www.universiteitleiden.nl/en/social-behavioural-sciences/cwts) shared observations on the state of author affiliations from a preprint titled “ [Crossref as a source of open bibliographic metadata](https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5_v2)” that presents the findings of an analysis performed annually since 2021. Nees’s key points:

- Crossref is a foundational data source for bibliographic metadata.
- Affiliation metadata is available for only 1 out of 3 journal articles in Crossref for the period 2023-2024.
- There is considerable variation in the extent to which Crossref members deposit affiliation metadata.
- Downstream sources try to fill gaps using suboptimal approaches, leading to missing, inaccurate, and inconsistent linking of publications to institutions.
- Publications lacking affiliation metadata in Crossref are less visible in bibliometric applications, analyses, studies, and tools (such as the [open edition of the Leiden Ranking](https://open.leidenranking.com/) of over 2800 universities).

![Crossref as a source of open bibliographic metadata.](https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-01.png)

Next, Yvonne Campfens of OA Switchboard reiterated the desirability of the Crossref community providing complete and accurate author affiliation metadata at the source. Yvonne called upon publishers to “Integrate metadata creation in your systems and workflows before publication and relay it throughout the editorial, production, and publication processes.”

Yvonne pointed out that in the context of managing Open Access agreements, publishers ought to keep in mind that providing good affiliation metadata improves customer satisfaction, since institutions and consortia need to have that information in order to connect research to the correct organization. In closing, Yvonne featured best practices from [OA Switchboard’s Data Quality Challenge](https://www.oaswitchboard.org/dqc-publisherbestpractices):

- eLife captures affiliations at submissions with “author select,” ensuring that ROR IDs are introduced early and verified before publication, coupled with a quality assurance process during proofing. (See also our piece on [Metadata Excellence Award winner eLife](https://doi.org/10.64000/3gcdf-23s29).)
- EMS Press captures metadata via manuscript extraction as early as at submission, building on globally valid identifiers whenever possible (ROR IDs, DOIs, ORCIDs).
- Pensoft Publishers uses AI-assisted metadata extraction with human review and in-house metadata validation.
- Beilstein-Institut performs post-acceptance metadata quality assurance through automation and expert review.
- The Royal Society embeds metadata in OA payment and agreement workflows.
- American Chemical Society (ACS) has a multi-method persistent identifier matching strategy with near-complete coverage.
- The American Society for Microbiology (ASM) combines AI-powered submission tools with editorial oversight via expert manual checks. (See also our piece on [Metadata Excellence Award winner ASM](https://doi.org/10.64000/xxwy3-xhf38).)
- Rockefeller University Press (RUP) maintains ROR IDs across the full publishing workflow with “author select” at submission through metadata deposits upon publication. (See also the [ROR case study on RUP](https://doi.org/10.71938/t63t-g186).)

![Having great metadata improves your operational excellence.](https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-02.png)

Adam Day of [Clear Skies Ltd](https://clear-skies.co.uk/) began his talk by wryly framing the first and second rules of data science as contradictory: “Never fix data: always use sources that produce high-quality data in the first place,” but also “Get good at fixing data, because you will have to.” Adam went on to demonstrate the central role author affiliation metadata plays in research integrity investigations, displaying anonymized data for institutions with a high number of alerts. In conclusion, Adam reiterated the importance of author affiliation metadata to research integrity efforts:

- Data analysis is critical to research integrity.
- Quality data helps enormously by giving oversight, saving time, and assisting investigations.

![Value comes from data.](https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-03.png)

Lastly, our own Director of Technology [Dominika Tkaczyk](https://www.crossref.org/people/dominika-tkaczyk) gave an account of our plans to enrich author affiliation metadata by matching organization name text strings to [ROR IDs](https://ror.org) as part of our [metadata matching](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/) initiative. A strategy for performing such matching has already been developed and tested and an [open dataset of results made available](https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993). Tests on a set of 3,000 affiliations sampled from our metadata show that the strategy can be expected to match 95 million ROR IDs to organization names with 97.35% precision, an astronomical increase over the less than 1 million ROR IDs deposited in Crossref records to date.

Dominika concluded the presentation portion of the session by reiterating that our planned enrichment of author affiliation metadata

- Will use flexible and transparent matching strategies (and [open code](https://gitlab.com/crossref/labs/marple/-/tree/main/strategies_available/affiliation_single_search)),
- Will welcome community participation in developing new strategies, and
- Will be available in the REST API.

![Matching affiliation strings to ROR IDs.](https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/aff-roundtable-04.png)

Automatic matching of organization names to ROR IDs in author affiliations cannot solve the problem of missing organization names, of course, but it represents a huge leap forward in addressing metadata quality issues.

All of our speakers’ presentations are available on Zenodo at [https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw](https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw).

## Insights into challenges

In the next stage of the event, participants broke into six breakout groups to identify factors contributing to incomplete or inaccurate affiliation metadata. Participants were pre-assigned to groups randomly by role to ensure a variety of perspectives in every discussion.

At least two participants, it should be noted, pointed out that it would be helpful to agree on a definition of “complete” and “accurate” affiliation metadata, which in itself is a challenge, and one we did not address in this roundtable. For instance, practices most recently have trended away from defining a complete author affiliation in open metadata as including an institutional address, although many internal databases might include such information separately.

Even without such definitions, however, all six groups were able to identify several general areas for attention, and one participant provided a particularly helpful categorization of these areas that is largely reused here.

### Inherent data complexity

- Research organizations have names in different languages, abbreviations, and many other name variants.
- Research organizations have frequent name changes, mergers, and rebranding.
- Research organizations have different degrees, levels, and complexity of hierarchical granularity, and authors, publishers, and software systems are often misaligned as to which level in an organization’s structure is appropriate to use in a particular instance.
- Research organizations often lack official policies on how affiliations should be written, leading to hundreds of variations for a single institution.

### Author-related issues

- Corresponding authors often submit information for all co-authors, which can lead to inaccuracies.
- Many authors have multiple profiles across multiple submission systems, which can introduce errors.
- Authors may have “octopus affiliations,” claiming affiliations with many institutions that are difficult to verify.
- Authors may fail to update affiliations when changing institutions between manuscript acceptance and publication.
- Authors may demonstrate “apathy” when repeatedly filling out submission forms, sometimes providing incomplete, inconsistent, or incorrect information.
- On occasion, authors might even provide false or purchased affiliations, which of course is a significant research integrity concern.

### Technical barriers

- Many manuscript tracking and peer review systems, especially legacy systems, lack structured fields for affiliations or don’t support open organization identifiers like ROR.
- Some systems limit authors to a single affiliation, despite many researchers having multiple institutional connections.
- Some systems only collect affiliation information for the corresponding author.
- Some systems link affiliations to user accounts instead of to publications.
- Different systems use competing identifier registries, including proprietary identifier registries, creating interoperability challenges.

### Publisher practices

- Even when publishers improve current metadata collection practices, historical data correction is resource-intensive and often not prioritized.
- Publishers collect affiliation information at submission but don’t ensure that it is maintained throughout all stages of the publication process and deposited in metadata.
- Some publishers are unaware of the importance of author affiliation metadata or do not prioritize its improvement.
- Some publishers deliberately choose not to deposit affiliation metadata to Crossref, viewing it as value-added information they’ve invested in curating.

## Insights into solutions

Naturally, we didn’t rest at identifying challenges: after a break, we gathered in the same groups to brainstorm approaches to improving author affiliation metadata.

### Adopt collective approaches

- Collective action, where corrections and improvements made by various stakeholders flow back into shared systems, has historically worked for proprietary systems and could be even more powerful with open infrastructure.
- Since those who do not provide metadata “upstream” will inevitably have it provided for them “downstream” by multiple separate entities using multifarious methods, provenance metadata indicating who asserted author affiliations and how (whether automatically or with the author’s or editor’s input) would help metadata users assess trust levels.

### Engage authors and institutions

- Reach out to authors and institutions to educate them on the need for more consistent affiliation reporting, especially in terms of language, name format, and degree of hierarchical granularity.
- Demonstrate the benefit to institutions of maintaining accurate records in registries like ROR, including abbreviations and name variants.
- Publishers and/or software systems should allow authors to review (though not necessarily edit) affiliation information during the proofing process to verify accuracy. Authors should not, however, need to know, see, or use ROR IDs.

### Improve the tech

- Publishers would welcome submission systems that incorporate structured fields for author affiliations with well-designed auto-suggestions linked to ROR or other organization identifiers.
- Making affiliation data mandatory at submission could significantly improve capture rates, although it would be important to ensure that independent researchers can use these systems as well.
- Enable collection of affiliations for all authors, not just the corresponding author.
- Pull in [verified affiliation information from ORCID](https://info.orcid.org/trust-markers-in-orcid-records-verified-email-domains/).
- Increasingly, intelligent matching systems can be implemented to reduce author burden and perhaps also increase accuracy and completeness of metadata.
- Better crosswalks between different organization identifier systems would make it vastly easier for publishers to maintain better metadata. Since open registries cannot include proprietary information, proprietary registries should provide their customers with crosswalks to all standard open identifiers.

### Encourage publisher best practices

- Publishers can use already-available tools to help assess and improve the quality of both new and legacy author affiliation metadata.
  - [Crossref’s Participation Reports](https://crossref.org/members/prep/)
  - [OpenAIRE’s affiliation matching methods and validation systems](https://graph.openaire.eu/docs/10.5.1/graph-production-workflow/enrichment-by-mining/affiliation_matching/)
  - [ROR API affiliation matching service](https://ror.readme.io/docs/api-affiliation)
- Share the benefits of improved author affiliation metadata for internal and external analytics, customer satisfaction, and research integrity.
- Identify best practices in collecting and structuring author affiliation metadata.
- Understand that the entire research ecosystem would benefit from publishers sharing collected affiliation data with Crossref.

It’s worth mentioning that these solutions are heterogeneous: not all strategies can be implemented by any one actor nor even by any one sector of our profession. Clearly, collaborative action is necessary for substantive change.

## Moving forward

The affiliations metadata roundtable represented an important step in addressing affiliation metadata challenges in a productive and collaborative way. If there was a consensus, it was that while perfect completeness and accuracy of author affiliation metadata may not be achievable (or even definable), incremental improvements can substantially enhance the quality and availability of affiliation metadata for the entire scholarly information community.

Here at Crossref, we intend to use the insights from this roundtable to inform our support of the Crossref community, including publishers, service providers, and metadata users. We welcome your comments, questions, and suggestions on this issue! **Share your thoughts with Amanda French at [alfrench@crossref.org](mailto:alfrench@crossref.org).**

### References

1. van Eck, N. J., &#38; Waltman, L. (2025). Crossref as a source of open bibliographic metadata (No. smxe5\_v2). MetaArXiv. [https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5\_v2](https://doi.org/10.31222/osf.io/smxe5_v2)
2. Tkaczyk, D. (2025). Crossref relationships involving research organisations \[Dataset\]. Zenodo. [https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993](https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.15254993)
3. French, A., van Eck, N. J., Campfens, Y., Day, A., &#38; Tkaczyk, D. (2026, January 19). Affiliations Metadata Roundtable 2025—All Presentations. [https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw](https://doi.org/10.13003/661591chqlyw)

### Participating organizations

Africa PID Alliance / TCC AfricaFrontiers Media SAAmerican Association of Cancer Research (AACR)Iowa StateAmerican Chemical Society (ACS)Kriyadocs / Exeter Premedia ServicesAmerican Physical Society (APS)MDPIAmerican Society for Microbiology (ASM)Noyam PublishersAptaraOpenAIRE / OpenOrgsAustralian Research Data Commons (ARDC)Optica Publishing GroupAtyponORCIDBeilstein-InstitutOxford University PressCalifornia Digital Library (CDL)Public Knowledge Project (PKP)Cambridge University PressPublic Library of Science (PLOS)Carnegie Mellon UniversityRiver Valley TechnologiesCHORUSRockefeller University PressClarivate / Web of Science SAGE PublicationsCopernicus GmBHBarcelona Declaration on Open Research Information Curtin University / Curtin Open Knowledge Initiative (COKI)Silverchair / ScholarOneDe Gruyter BrillSpringer Science &#38; BusinessDigital Science / FigshareTNQTechDigital Science / Symplectic ElementsUniversity of LavaleLifeUniversity of Chicago PressElsevier BVUniversity of SplitEnago</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/insights-from-a-roundtable-on-author-affiliation-metadata/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Understanding Postsecondary Students’ Perspectives on Basic Needs Insecurity</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/understanding-postsecondary-students-perspectives-on-basic-needs-insecurity/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Across higher education, there is growing recognition that students’ academic success is deeply connected to whether their basic needs are met. Food, housing, transportation, child care, mental health support, and financial stability all play a critical role in students’ ability to persist and thrive. Yet, despite increased attention to basic needs insecurity, institutions often rely [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/understanding-postsecondary-students-perspectives-on-basic-needs-insecurity/">Understanding Postsecondary Students’ Perspectives on Basic Needs Insecurity</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Across higher education, there is growing recognition that students’ academic success is deeply connected to whether their basic needs are met. Food, housing, transportation, child care, mental health support, and financial stability all play a critical role in students’ ability to persist and thrive. Yet, despite increased attention to basic needs insecurity, institutions often rely \[…\]

The post [Understanding Postsecondary Students’ Perspectives on Basic Needs Insecurity](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/understanding-postsecondary-students-perspectives-on-basic-needs-insecurity/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=324589</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How Congress Can Improve Accessibility and Digital Access</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/accessibility-and-digital-access/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on January 21, 2026, 12:24 pm ET For EFF Copyright Week 2026: Device and Digital Ownership Every three years since 2003, disability rights advocates and library associations have...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/accessibility-and-digital-access/">How Congress Can Improve Accessibility and Digital Access</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on January 21, 2026, 12:24 pm ET For EFF Copyright Week 2026: Device and Digital Ownership Every three years since 2003, disability rights advocates and library associations have...

The post [How Congress Can Improve Accessibility and Digital Access](https://www.arl.org/blog/accessibility-and-digital-access/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=47162</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>At the Villa Rose, by A. E. W. Mason</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/a-e-w-mason/at-the-villa-rose</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A wealthy widow is murdered at her villa in Aix-les-Bains, and her companion is missing.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A wealthy widow is murdered at her villa in Aix-les-Bains, and her companion is missing.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/a-e-w-mason/at-the-villa-rose/downloads/a-e-w-mason_at-the-villa-rose.epub?source=feed" length="466477" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/a-e-w-mason/at-the-villa-rose</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Data From OverDrive: Libraries Break Digital Lending Records in 2025 with Over 820 Million Checkouts and Over 1 Billion Minutes Streamed</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/21/new-data-from-overdrive-libraries-break-digital-lending-records-in-2025-with-over-820-million-checkouts-and-over-1-billion-minutes-streamed/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From OverDrive: In 2025, libraries around the world continued to prove their essential role in connecting communities with stories, information, and entertainment, breaking new digital lending records in the process. As the need for flexible, on-demand access to books and media continued to grow, libraries expanded their digital collections to meet readers where they are, [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From OverDrive: In 2025, libraries around the world continued to prove their essential role in connecting communities with stories, information, and entertainment, breaking new digital lending records in the process. As the need for flexible, on-demand access to books and media continued to grow, libraries expanded their digital collections to meet readers where they are, \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167570</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Announcing the 2026 Public Domain Film Remix Contest Winners, Honorable Mentions &#38; Finalists</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/21/2026-public-domain-film-remix-contest/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[We’re thrilled to unveil the creativity of our top three winners and four honorable mentions in this year’s&#160;Public Domain Day Film Remix Contest. These remarkable films not only reimagined and [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We’re thrilled to unveil the creativity of our top three winners and four honorable mentions in this year’s Public Domain Day Film Remix Contest. These remarkable films not only reimagined and \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://www.instagram.com/avi.mov" length="0" type="video/quicktime" />
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29930</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>National Survey Findings: “The AI Challenge: How College Faculty Assess the Present and Future Of Higher Education in the Age of AI”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/21/findings-from-a-national-survey-the-ai-challenge-how-college-faculty-assess-the-present-and-future-of-higher-education-in-the-age-of-ai/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The survey was conducted by the American Association of Colleges and Universities and Elon University’s Imagining the Digital Future Center. Report Resources Direct to Full Text Report (26 pages; PDF) Charts (23 pages; PDF) Methodology and Topline (21 pages; PDF) News Release: National Survey: 95% of College Faculty Fear Student Overreliance on AI and Diminished Critical Thinking [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The survey was conducted by the American Association of Colleges and Universities and Elon University’s Imagining the Digital Future Center. Report Resources Direct to Full Text Report (26 pages; PDF) Charts (23 pages; PDF) Methodology and Topline (21 pages; PDF) News Release: National Survey: 95% of College Faculty Fear Student Overreliance on AI and Diminished Critical Thinking \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167556</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — AI Isn’t Going to Pay for Content … At Least Not How You’re Hoping It Will</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/21/guest-post-ai-isnt-going-to-pay-for-content-at-least-not-how-youre-hoping-it-will/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest post is the first in a two-part series — we begin by facing up to the fact that AI will not become the content windfall the way many in the publishing industry hope.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/21/guest-post-ai-isnt-going-to-pay-for-content-at-least-not-how-youre-hoping-it-will/">Guest Post — AI Isn’t Going to Pay for Content … At Least Not How You’re Hoping It Will</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest post is the first in a two-part series — we begin by facing up to the fact that AI will not become the content windfall the way many in the publishing industry hope.

The post [Guest Post — AI Isn’t Going to Pay for Content … At Least Not How You’re Hoping It Will](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/21/guest-post-ai-isnt-going-to-pay-for-content-at-least-not-how-youre-hoping-it-will/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61463</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The January 2026 Issue (Vol 87, No 1) of College &#38; Research Libraries (C&#38;RL) is Now Available Online</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/20/the-january-2026-issue-vol-87-no-1-of-college-research-libraries-crl-is-now-available-online/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The January 2026 Issue (Vol 87, No 1) of College &#38; Research Libraries (C&#38;RL) is now available online. Table of Contents Articles Finding Their Own Way: A Phenomenological Study of Academic Librarians&#8217; Experiences with Tenure Jolene Cole Interventions for Reducing, Preventing, or Overcoming Librarian Burnout: A Scoping Review Natalie Logue, Jessica C. Garner, Stephanie Hendren [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The January 2026 Issue (Vol 87, No 1) of College &#38; Research Libraries (C&#38;RL) is now available online. Table of Contents Articles Finding Their Own Way: A Phenomenological Study of Academic Librarians’ Experiences with Tenure Jolene Cole Interventions for Reducing, Preventing, or Overcoming Librarian Burnout: A Scoping Review Natalie Logue, Jessica C. Garner, Stephanie Hendren \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167550</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>In Praise of Pre-Hays: “Morocco” and the Public Domain</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/20/in-praise-of-pre-hays-morocco-and-the-public-domain/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Theo Unkrich (he/him) is a member of Internet Archive’s Patron Services team. His love of media preservation persists outside of Internet Archive in his writing and game design projects, which [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Theo Unkrich (he/him) is a member of Internet Archive’s Patron Services team. His love of media preservation persists outside of Internet Archive in his writing and game design projects, which \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29958</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ARL Daily Intelligence (January 20–22)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/daily-intelligence/arl-daily-intelligence-january-20-22/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on January 22, 2026, 1:13 pm ET The ARL Daily Intelligence is the trusted source of news and analysis for library leaders and advocates. Released Monday through Thursday,...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/daily-intelligence/arl-daily-intelligence-january-20-22/">ARL Daily Intelligence (January 20–22)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on January 22, 2026, 1:13 pm ET The ARL Daily Intelligence is the trusted source of news and analysis for library leaders and advocates. Released Monday through Thursday,...

The post [ARL Daily Intelligence (January 20–22)](https://www.arl.org/daily-intelligence/arl-daily-intelligence-january-20-22/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=47146</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Digital Literacy Strategies to Prepare Incarcerated Students for Education and Work</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/digital-literacy-strategies-to-prepare-incarcerated-students-for-education-and-work/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In today’s technology-driven world, digital literacy isn’t just a skill—it’s a lifeline. For individuals who are incarcerated, the ability to effectively use digital tools can mean the difference between returning to the community prepared or being left even further behind. As research shows, digital skills acquisition is critical for navigating all phases of reentry.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/digital-literacy-strategies-to-prepare-incarcerated-students-for-education-and-work/">Digital Literacy Strategies to Prepare Incarcerated Students for Education and Work</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In today’s technology-driven world, digital literacy isn’t just a skill—it’s a lifeline. For individuals who are incarcerated, the ability to effectively use digital tools can mean the difference between returning to the community prepared or being left even further behind. As research shows, digital skills acquisition is critical for navigating all phases of reentry.

The post [Digital Literacy Strategies to Prepare Incarcerated Students for Education and Work](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/digital-literacy-strategies-to-prepare-incarcerated-students-for-education-and-work/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=324550</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Happy Anniversary! Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL) Celebrates 70 Years of Advancing Research Libraries in the Southeast</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/20/happy-anniversary-association-of-southeastern-research-libraries-aserl-celebrates-70-years-of-advancing-research-libraries-in-the-southeast/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From ASERL: The Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL) proudly celebrates its 70th anniversary in 2026, marking seven decades of leadership, collaboration, and innovation in support of research libraries and higher education across the southeastern United States. Founded in 1956, ASERL has played a pivotal role in shaping regional and national conversations around access to [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From ASERL: The Association of Southeastern Research Libraries (ASERL) proudly celebrates its 70th anniversary in 2026, marking seven decades of leadership, collaboration, and innovation in support of research libraries and higher education across the southeastern United States. Founded in 1956, ASERL has played a pivotal role in shaping regional and national conversations around access to \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167545</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>AI Roundup: De Gruyter Brill, Emerald Publishing, IOP Publishing, Silverchair and Springer Nature Partner With Kudos to Examine Zero-Click and AI Search Risks to the Research Ecosystem &#38; More Headlines</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/20/ai-roundup-de-gruyter-brill-emerald-publishing-iop-publishing-silverchair-and-springer-nature-partner-with-kudos-to-examine-zero-click-and-ai-search-risks-to-the-research-ecosystem-more-head/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Anthropic Anthropic and Teach For AllLaunch Global AI Training Initiative For Educators Conferderation of Open Access Repositories (COAR) Mitigating the Impact of AI Bots;  New Resource: &#8220;Dealing With Bots: A COAR Resource for Repository Managers&#8221; Clarivate Clarivate Announces Launch of Alma Specto (An AI-Powered Digital Collection Platform) Guidelines Guidelines and Best Practices for Making Government [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Anthropic Anthropic and Teach For AllLaunch Global AI Training Initiative For Educators Conferderation of Open Access Repositories (COAR) Mitigating the Impact of AI Bots;  New Resource: “Dealing With Bots: A COAR Resource for Repository Managers” Clarivate Clarivate Announces Launch of Alma Specto (An AI-Powered Digital Collection Platform) Guidelines Guidelines and Best Practices for Making Government \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167541</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Creating a Culture of Diversity and Inclusion Revisited: An Interview with Vicky Williams of Emerald Publishing</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/20/creating-a-culture-of-diversity-and-inclusion-revisited-an-interview-with-vicky-williams-of-emerald-publishing/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In this follow-up to a 2018 interview, Alice Meadows revisits the topic of DEIA with Emerald Publishing's CEO, Vicky Williams to find out what progress has been made and where improvements are still needed -- both at Emerald and within scholarly communications</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/20/creating-a-culture-of-diversity-and-inclusion-revisited-an-interview-with-vicky-williams-of-emerald-publishing/">Creating a Culture of Diversity and Inclusion Revisited: An Interview with Vicky Williams of Emerald Publishing </a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In this follow-up to a 2018 interview, Alice Meadows revisits the topic of DEIA with Emerald Publishing&#39;s CEO, Vicky Williams to find out what progress has been made and where improvements are still needed -- both at Emerald and within scholarly communications

The post [Creating a Culture of Diversity and Inclusion Revisited: An Interview with Vicky Williams of Emerald Publishing](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/20/creating-a-culture-of-diversity-and-inclusion-revisited-an-interview-with-vicky-williams-of-emerald-publishing/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61406</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Breaking of the Storm, by Friedrich Spielhagen</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/friedrich-spielhagen/the-breaking-of-the-storm/s-e-a-h-stephenson</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Two families in north Germany deal with love across rigid class boundaries in turbulent times.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Two families in north Germany deal with love across rigid class boundaries in turbulent times.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/friedrich-spielhagen/the-breaking-of-the-storm/s-e-a-h-stephenson/downloads/friedrich-spielhagen_the-breaking-of-the-storm_s-e-a-h-stephenson.epub?source=feed" length="1044207" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/friedrich-spielhagen/the-breaking-of-the-storm/s-e-a-h-stephenson</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Trail of the Serpent, by M. E. Braddon</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/m-e-braddon/the-trail-of-the-serpent</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In the town of Slopperton-on-the-Sloshy, the fate of Richard Marwood and Jabez North intertwine in a story of crime, intrigue, and redemption.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In the town of Slopperton-on-the-Sloshy, the fate of Richard Marwood and Jabez North intertwine in a story of crime, intrigue, and redemption.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/m-e-braddon/the-trail-of-the-serpent/downloads/m-e-braddon_the-trail-of-the-serpent.epub?source=feed" length="833775" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/m-e-braddon/the-trail-of-the-serpent</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>On the Eve, by Ivan Turgenev</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ivan-turgenev/on-the-eve/constance-garnett</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young Russian woman falls in love with a Bulgarian patriot on the eve of the Crimean War.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young Russian woman falls in love with a Bulgarian patriot on the eve of the Crimean War.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ivan-turgenev/on-the-eve/constance-garnett/downloads/ivan-turgenev_on-the-eve_constance-garnett.epub?source=feed" length="413348" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/ivan-turgenev/on-the-eve/constance-garnett</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>University of Missouri Libraries Adds Collection of World War II Posters to Digital Library</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/19/university-of-missouri-libraries-adds-collection-of-world-war-ii-posters-to-digital-library/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From the University of Missouri Libraries: 25, marked the 80th anniversary of the end of World War II, which took place over six years between 1939 and 1945. In honor of the anniversary, the Digital Initiatives department began digitizing posters from the War Poster Collection housed in our libraries’ Special Collections. This collection offers a [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From the University of Missouri Libraries: 25, marked the 80th anniversary of the end of World War II, which took place over six years between 1939 and 1945. In honor of the anniversary, the Digital Initiatives department began digitizing posters from the War Poster Collection housed in our libraries’ Special Collections. This collection offers a \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167537</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Who is the midwife and who is the parturient? The maieutic perspective for rethinking authorship and epistemic responsibility in the use of AI in scientific output</title>
      <link>https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/19/who-is-the-midwife-and-who-is-the-parturient-the-maieutic-perspective-for-rethinking-authorship-and-epistemic-responsibility-in-the-use-of-ai-in-scientific-output/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The Socratic maieutic perspective offers a philosophical framework for rethinking the use of AI in scientific output. Instead of an oracle that provides answers, AI can be a dialogical partner that helps researchers to make latent knowledge explicit and thus reposition the discussion about authorship: the researcher remains the responsible epistemic agent, while AI acts as an intellectual midwife. <span class="ellipsis">&#8230;</span> <span class="more-link-wrap"><a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/19/who-is-the-midwife-and-who-is-the-parturient-the-maieutic-perspective-for-rethinking-authorship-and-epistemic-responsibility-in-the-use-of-ai-in-scientific-output/" class="more-link"><span>Read More &#8594;</span></a></span></p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/19/who-is-the-midwife-and-who-is-the-parturient-the-maieutic-perspective-for-rethinking-authorship-and-epistemic-responsibility-in-the-use-of-ai-in-scientific-output/">Who is the midwife and who is the parturient? The maieutic perspective for rethinking authorship and epistemic responsibility in the use of AI in scientific output</a> first appeared on <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en">SciELO in Perspective</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The Socratic maieutic perspective offers a philosophical framework for rethinking the use of AI in scientific output. Instead of an oracle that provides answers, AI can be a dialogical partner that helps researchers to make latent knowledge explicit and thus reposition the discussion about authorship: the researcher remains the responsible epistemic agent, while AI acts as an intellectual midwife. …[Read More →](https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/19/who-is-the-midwife-and-who-is-the-parturient-the-maieutic-perspective-for-rethinking-authorship-and-epistemic-responsibility-in-the-use-of-ai-in-scientific-output/)

The post [Who is the midwife and who is the parturient? The maieutic perspective for rethinking authorship and epistemic responsibility in the use of AI in scientific output](https://blog.scielo.org/en/2026/01/19/who-is-the-midwife-and-who-is-the-parturient-the-maieutic-perspective-for-rethinking-authorship-and-epistemic-responsibility-in-the-use-of-ai-in-scientific-output/) first appeared on [SciELO in Perspective](https://blog.scielo.org/en).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.scielo.org/en/?p=5804</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Short Fiction, by Clark Ashton Smith</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clark-ashton-smith/short-fiction</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of short fiction by Clark Ashton Smith, ordered by date of publication.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A collection of short fiction by Clark Ashton Smith, ordered by date of publication.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clark-ashton-smith/short-fiction/downloads/clark-ashton-smith_short-fiction.epub?source=feed" length="680173" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/clark-ashton-smith/short-fiction</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>THIS WEDNESDAY: Three Ways to Celebrate the Public Domain</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/18/this-wednesday-three-ways-to-celebrate-the-public-domain/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Join us THIS WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 21 for three different ways to celebrate the creative works from 1930 and the sounds recordings from 1925 that have entered the public domain in [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Join us THIS WEDNESDAY, JANUARY 21 for three different ways to celebrate the creative works from 1930 and the sounds recordings from 1925 that have entered the public domain in \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29947</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>“We”, by Charles A. Lindbergh</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/charles-a-lindbergh/we</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Legendary aviator Charles Lindbergh gives an account of his early life, how he got into flying, and his famous transatlantic flight.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Legendary aviator Charles Lindbergh gives an account of his early life, how he got into flying, and his famous transatlantic flight.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/charles-a-lindbergh/we/downloads/charles-a-lindbergh_we.epub?source=feed" length="3476432" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/charles-a-lindbergh/we</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Lisa O’Hara: Librarianship Is All About the People</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/blog/lisa-ohara-librarianship-is-all-about-the-people/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on January 16, 2026, 10:49 am ET Before retiring from the University of Manitoba at the end of 2025, Lisa O’Hara chatted with ARL about her career and...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/blog/lisa-ohara-librarianship-is-all-about-the-people/">Lisa O’Hara: Librarianship Is All About the People</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on January 16, 2026, 10:49 am ET Before retiring from the University of Manitoba at the end of 2025, Lisa O’Hara chatted with ARL about her career and...

The post [Lisa O’Hara: Librarianship Is All About the People](https://www.arl.org/blog/lisa-ohara-librarianship-is-all-about-the-people/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=47127</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>2025 Readership Survey</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/16/2025-readership-survey/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The Scholarly Kitchen's 2025 Readership Survey reflects feedback from our community that will shape the future direction of our blog.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/16/2025-readership-survey/">2025 Readership Survey</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The Scholarly Kitchen&#39;s 2025 Readership Survey reflects feedback from our community that will shape the future direction of our blog.

The post [2025 Readership Survey](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/16/2025-readership-survey/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61448</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Reports: Microsoft is Closing Its Employee Library and Cutting Back on Subscriptions</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/15/reports-microsoft-is-closing-its-employee-library-and-cutting-back-on-subscriptions/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From The Verge: Microsoft’s library of books is so heavy that it once caused a campus building to sink, according to an unproven legend among employees. Now those physical books, journals, and reports, and many of Microsoft’s digital subscriptions to leading US newspapers, are disappearing in a shift described inside Microsoft as an “AI-powered learning [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From The Verge: Microsoft’s library of books is so heavy that it once caused a campus building to sink, according to an unproven legend among employees. Now those physical books, journals, and reports, and many of Microsoft’s digital subscriptions to leading US newspapers, are disappearing in a shift described inside Microsoft as an “AI-powered learning \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167532</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Human Values and AI Adoption in the Research Enterprise</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/human-values-and-ai-adoption-in-the-research-enterprise/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Research administrators play an essential role in the research enterprise. Their work managing expenditures and monitoring compliance with rules related to the ethical conduct of research ensure that public money is spent and that research data is collected in ways that protect privacy, minimize risks to participants, and meet the complex legal and contractual obligations [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/human-values-and-ai-adoption-in-the-research-enterprise/">Human Values and AI Adoption in the Research Enterprise</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Research administrators play an essential role in the research enterprise. Their work managing expenditures and monitoring compliance with rules related to the ethical conduct of research ensure that public money is spent and that research data is collected in ways that protect privacy, minimize risks to participants, and meet the complex legal and contractual obligations \[…\]

The post [Human Values and AI Adoption in the Research Enterprise](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/human-values-and-ai-adoption-in-the-research-enterprise/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=324517</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Anywhere Adventures is Hitting the Road!</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2026/01/anywhere-adventures-is-hitting-the-road/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[We’re on the hunt for two U.S. communities to include in Vivian Li’s Innovator in Residence Project, Anywhere Adventures!  Visitors to the mobile experience are currently able to explore three American communities, Seattle, Chicago, and Southeastern Wyoming, through items from the Library’s digital collections and learn about the stories, people, and events that shaped everyday life in these places.     With the site, visitors can do a &#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We’re on the hunt for two U.S. communities to include in Vivian Li’s Innovator in Residence Project, Anywhere Adventures!  Visitors to the mobile experience are currently able to explore three American communities, Seattle, Chicago, and Southeastern Wyoming, through items from the Library’s digital collections and learn about the stories, people, and events that shaped everyday life in these places.     With the site, visitors can do a …</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/?p=36735</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>PALCI and Authors Alliance Announce Consortium-Wide Partnership to Strengthen Scholarly Communication and Information Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/15/palci-and-authors-alliance-announce-consortium-wide-partnership-to-strengthen-scholarly-communication-and-information-policy/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Here&#8217;s the Full Text of Today&#8217;s Announcement (via PALCI): The partnership was made possible through financial commitments from PALCI and 26 of its member libraries, including four Leadership Circle contributors who chose to make a deeper investment in both the partnership and the broader PALCI community. Their combined support advances a new consortium-based model for [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Here’s the Full Text of Today’s Announcement (via PALCI): The partnership was made possible through financial commitments from PALCI and 26 of its member libraries, including four Leadership Circle contributors who chose to make a deeper investment in both the partnership and the broader PALCI community. Their combined support advances a new consortium-based model for \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167528</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — Open Scholarship is Poised to Create More Value than Ever, but Are We Ready?</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/15/guest-post-open-scholarship-is-poised-to-create-more-value-than-ever-but-are-we-ready/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest blogger observes how advances in technology create unprecedented opportunities in open scholarship, and asks: Can incentive structures keep up?</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/15/guest-post-open-scholarship-is-poised-to-create-more-value-than-ever-but-are-we-ready/">Guest Post — Open Scholarship is Poised to Create More Value than Ever, but Are We Ready?</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest blogger observes how advances in technology create unprecedented opportunities in open scholarship, and asks: Can incentive structures keep up?

The post [Guest Post — Open Scholarship is Poised to Create More Value than Ever, but Are We Ready?](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/15/guest-post-open-scholarship-is-poised-to-create-more-value-than-ever-but-are-we-ready/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61389</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Beric the Briton, by G. A. Henty</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-a-henty/beric-the-briton</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A young Briton, learned in Roman ways, becomes their chief adversary.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A young Briton, learned in Roman ways, becomes their chief adversary.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-a-henty/beric-the-briton/downloads/g-a-henty_beric-the-briton.epub?source=feed" length="705710" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-a-henty/beric-the-briton</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Tragedy at Ravensthorpe, by J. J. Connington</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/j-j-connington/tragedy-at-ravensthorpe</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Chief Constable Sir Clinton Driffield investigates the theft of valuables from a country estate after a masquerade ball.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Chief Constable Sir Clinton Driffield investigates the theft of valuables from a country estate after a masquerade ball.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/j-j-connington/tragedy-at-ravensthorpe/downloads/j-j-connington_tragedy-at-ravensthorpe.epub?source=feed" length="338938" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/j-j-connington/tragedy-at-ravensthorpe</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Father Henson’s Story of His Own Life, by Josiah Henson</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/josiah-henson/father-hensons-story-of-his-own-life</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Josiah Henson’s autobiography recounts his life in slavery and his escape to freedom in Canada.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Josiah Henson’s autobiography recounts his life in slavery and his escape to freedom in Canada.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/josiah-henson/father-hensons-story-of-his-own-life/downloads/josiah-henson_father-hensons-story-of-his-own-life.epub?source=feed" length="587613" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/josiah-henson/father-hensons-story-of-his-own-life</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Online Event: University of Kansas Libraries Launches Global Speaker Series on Librarianship</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/14/online-event-university-of-kansas-libraries-launches-global-speaker-series-on-librarianship/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From the University of Kansas Libraries:  The University of Kansas Libraries will launch “Global Conversations in Librarianship,” a new speaker series highlighting international perspectives on libraries and information work, with Ukrainian library leader Tetyana Yaroshenko as its inaugural speaker Feb. 26. Yaroshenko, deputy director for research and international affairs at the State Scientific and Technical [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From the University of Kansas Libraries:  The University of Kansas Libraries will launch “Global Conversations in Librarianship,” a new speaker series highlighting international perspectives on libraries and information work, with Ukrainian library leader Tetyana Yaroshenko as its inaugural speaker Feb. 26. Yaroshenko, deputy director for research and international affairs at the State Scientific and Technical \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167524</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>EveryLibrary Releases 2025 Impact Report</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/14/everylibrary-releases-2025-impact-report/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From EveryLibrary: The threats to libraries, librarians, and readers in 2025 included censorship, funding erosion, and unprecedented political interference. At the federal level, President Trump ordered the closure of the Institute of Museum and Library Services, fired the Librarian of Congress and the Archivist of the United States, and institutionalized censorship at Department of Defense [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From EveryLibrary: The threats to libraries, librarians, and readers in 2025 included censorship, funding erosion, and unprecedented political interference. At the federal level, President Trump ordered the closure of the Institute of Museum and Library Services, fired the Librarian of Congress and the Archivist of the United States, and institutionalized censorship at Department of Defense \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167521</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Improving the Share of Adult Learners at Four-Year Institutions</title>
      <link>https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/improving-the-share-of-adult-learners-at-four-year-institutions/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Higher education institutions will face multiple enrollment challenges in the next decade., including the projected decline in the number of high school graduates after 2025 and more prospective students being open to career options outside of a four-year degree. As they consider how to respond to these challenges, colleges and universities, including those with high-graduation rates, should take a closer look at the population of adult learners, particularly those within their geographic region, to support future enrollment efforts. </p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/improving-the-share-of-adult-learners-at-four-year-institutions/">Improving the Share of Adult Learners at Four-Year Institutions</a> appeared first on <a href="https://sr.ithaka.org">Ithaka S+R</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Higher education institutions will face multiple enrollment challenges in the next decade., including the projected decline in the number of high school graduates after 2025 and more prospective students being open to career options outside of a four-year degree. As they consider how to respond to these challenges, colleges and universities, including those with high-graduation rates, should take a closer look at the population of adult learners, particularly those within their geographic region, to support future enrollment efforts.

The post [Improving the Share of Adult Learners at Four-Year Institutions](https://sr.ithaka.org/blog/improving-the-share-of-adult-learners-at-four-year-institutions/) appeared first on [Ithaka S+R](https://sr.ithaka.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sr.ithaka.org/?p=324495</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How much time does the journal require from you?</title>
      <link>https://blog.scielo.org/blog/2026/01/14/quanto-tempo-a-revista-exige-de-voce/#new_tab</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The editor-in-chief formula presents the parameters for calculating the working hours required for the editor to meet the journal's submission demand. It mainly takes into account the number of articles and the rejection rate, expanding knowledge about scientific editing by quantifying an activity that has historically been invisible. Available in Portuguese only. <span class="ellipsis">&#8230;</span> <span class="more-link-wrap"><a href="https://blog.scielo.org/blog/2026/01/14/quanto-tempo-a-revista-exige-de-voce/#new_tab" class="more-link"><span>Read More &#8594;</span></a></span></p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/blog/2026/01/14/quanto-tempo-a-revista-exige-de-voce/#new_tab">How much time does the journal require from you?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://blog.scielo.org/en">SciELO in Perspective</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The editor-in-chief formula presents the parameters for calculating the working hours required for the editor to meet the journal&#39;s submission demand. It mainly takes into account the number of articles and the rejection rate, expanding knowledge about scientific editing by quantifying an activity that has historically been invisible. Available in Portuguese only. …[Read More →](https://blog.scielo.org/blog/2026/01/14/quanto-tempo-a-revista-exige-de-voce/#new_tab)

The post [How much time does the journal require from you?](https://blog.scielo.org/blog/2026/01/14/quanto-tempo-a-revista-exige-de-voce/#new_tab) first appeared on [SciELO in Perspective](https://blog.scielo.org/en).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.scielo.org/en/?p=5794</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How Librarian Megan Lotts Turned 1 Trillion Web Pages into an 8-Page Zine</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/14/how-librarian-megan-lotts-turned-1-trillion-web-pages-into-an-8-page-zine/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[How do you commemorate the preservation of 1 trillion web pages in a zine? That was Megan Lotts’ challenge when she was contacted by the Internet Archive last summer. Lotts [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>How do you commemorate the preservation of 1 trillion web pages in a zine? That was Megan Lotts’ challenge when she was contacted by the Internet Archive last summer. Lotts \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29921</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Open Access Policies – The Devil’s in the Details</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/14/open-access-policies-the-devils-in-the-details/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In today's post Alice Meadows shares some of the feedback gathered by MoreBrains and UKRI about the technical requirements of its OA policy, including thoughts from three speakers at a UKRI webinar on the topic.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/14/open-access-policies-the-devils-in-the-details/">Open Access Policies – The Devil’s in the Details</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In today&#39;s post Alice Meadows shares some of the feedback gathered by MoreBrains and UKRI about the technical requirements of its OA policy, including thoughts from three speakers at a UKRI webinar on the topic.

The post [Open Access Policies – The Devil’s in the Details](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/14/open-access-policies-the-devils-in-the-details/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61361</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The GEM program - Year Three and program expansion for 2026</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/the-gem-program-year-three-and-program-expansion-for-2026/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>As Crossref membership continues to grow, finding ways to help organisations participate is an important part of our mission. Although Crossref membership is open to all organisations that produce scholarly and professional materials, cost and technical challenges can be barriers to joining for many.</p>
        <p>Our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/gem/">Global Equitable Membership (GEM) Program</a> aims to provide greater membership equity and accessibility to organisations in the world&rsquo;s least economically advantaged countries. Eligible members pay no membership or record registration fees. Eligibility for the program is based on a member&rsquo;s country. Seeing its effectiveness in increasing participation in the research nexus from previously underrepresented regions, this year we are expanding the GEM program to include 18 new countries.</p>
        <h3 id="overview-of-the-first-3-years-of-gem">Overview of the first 3 years of GEM</h3>
        <p>The program began in January 2023 with 214 existing members. By the end of 2025, we had 628 organisations under the GEM program. Of these, 535 are independent members, and 89 members work through one of our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/membership/about-sponsors">sponsors</a>. To date, GEM program members have contributed approximately 334,000 works to the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus">Research Nexus</a>.</p>
        <center>
        <table>
        <thead>
        <tr>
        <th>Global equitable membership</th>
        <th>2023</th>
        <th>2024</th>
        <th>2025</th>
        </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
        <tr>
        <td>New members joining</td>
        <td>129</td>
        <td>127</td>
        <td>151</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Total member count</td>
        <td>327</td>
        <td>458</td>
        <td>628</td>
        </tr>
        </tbody>
        </table>
        </center>
        <p>Total number of Crossref GEM members by country until the end of 2025:</p>
        <center>
        <table>
        <thead>
        <tr>
        <th>GEM country – alphabetically</th>
        <th>Total no. of members</th>
        <th>GEM country – alphabetically</th>
        <th>Total no. of members</th>
        </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
        <tr>
        <td>Afghanistan</td>
        <td>29</td>
        <td>Malawi</td>
        <td>2</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Bangladesh</td>
        <td>167</td>
        <td>Maldives</td>
        <td>4</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Benin</td>
        <td>6</td>
        <td>Mali</td>
        <td>4</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Bhutan</td>
        <td>6</td>
        <td>Marshall Islands</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Burkina Faso</td>
        <td>7</td>
        <td>Mauritania</td>
        <td>1</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Burundi</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>Micronesia</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Cambodia</td>
        <td>14</td>
        <td>Mozambique</td>
        <td>2</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Central African Republic</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>Myanmar</td>
        <td>3</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Chad</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>Nepal</td>
        <td>60</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Comoros</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>Nicaragua</td>
        <td>2</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Congo, Democratic Republic</td>
        <td>24</td>
        <td>Niger</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Côte d&rsquo;Ivoire</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>Rwanda</td>
        <td>9</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Djibouti</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>Samoa</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Eritrea</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>São Tomé and Principe</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Ethiopia</td>
        <td>17</td>
        <td>Senegal</td>
        <td>7</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Gambia</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>Sierra Leone</td>
        <td>2</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Ghana</td>
        <td>38</td>
        <td>Solomon Islands</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Guinea</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>Somalia</td>
        <td>10</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Guinea-Bissau</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>South Sudan</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Guyana</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>Sri Lanka</td>
        <td>31</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Haiti</td>
        <td>2</td>
        <td>Sudan</td>
        <td>14</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Honduras</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>Tajikistan</td>
        <td>8</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Kiribati</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>Tanzania, United Republic of</td>
        <td>28</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Kosovo</td>
        <td>9</td>
        <td>Togo</td>
        <td>1</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Kyrgyz Republic</td>
        <td>27</td>
        <td>Tonga</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Lao, People&rsquo;s Democratic Rep.</td>
        <td>5</td>
        <td>Tuvalu</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Lesotho</td>
        <td>0</td>
        <td>Uganda</td>
        <td>23</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Liberia</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>Vanuatu</td>
        <td>0</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td>Madagascar</td>
        <td>5</td>
        <td>Yemen</td>
        <td>37</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
        <td></td>
        <td></td>
        <td>Zambia</td>
        <td>8</td>
        </tr>
        </tbody>
        </table>
        </center>
        <div style="text-align:center;margin:10px">
        <figure><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/gem-expansion-map.png"
        alt="world map with GEM countries highlighted in red" width="75%"><figcaption>
        <p>Membership Density in GEM Program Countries until the end of 2025</p>
        </figcaption>
        </figure>
        </div>
        <h3 id="program-expansion-in-2026">Program expansion in 2026</h3>
        <p>Starting on 1st of January 2026, we’re excited to invite organisations from Angola, Belize, Cabo Verde, Cameroon, Republic of Congo, Dominica, Eswatini, Fiji, Grenada, Kenya, Nigeria, Pakistan, Papua New Guinea, Saint Lucia, Saint Vincent and the Grenadines, Suriname, Timor Leste, and Uzbekistan to join Crossref and register their content and metadata with us without membership or record registration fees. There are 711 existing Crossref members based in these countries who are now eligible for the program, bringing the overall number of GEM members to 1339 across 77 countries (that’s close to 5% of all Crossref members).</p>
        <p>In creating our eligibility list, we refer to existing sources. For the first three years of the program, our list was predominantly based on the World Bank’s <a href="https://datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/906519-world-bank-country-and-lending-groups" target="_blank">International Development Association (IDA)</a> classification. In 2026, we leveraged additional sources to curate our list, resulting in the inclusion of 18 new countries in the program. Following community feedback, we now refer to the IDA, the <a href="https://datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/906519-world-bank-country-and-lending-groups" target="_blank">IDA Blend List</a>, and the <a href="https://www.un.org/ohrlls/content/list-ldcs" target="_blank">United Nations Least Developed Countries</a> list. In our choices, we also keep abreast of the global situation and conversations about supporting equitability in scholarly publishing and in the future, we may consider other factors too.</p>
        <p>We will review our lists and the eligibility criteria annually and note any changes on our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/gem/">website</a>. Members whose country moves on or off the GEM Program will be notified of any upcoming fees (or the removal of fees) with adequate time to plan and budget accordingly.
        Although the GEM program reduces financial barriers, many small organisations may still need administrative, technical, and language support provided by our Sponsors, and we will continue working with suitable organisations to make participation in Crossref easier.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>As Crossref membership continues to grow, finding ways to help organisations participate is an important part of our mission. Although Crossref membership is open to all organisations that produce scholarly and professional materials, cost and technical challenges can be barriers to joining for many.

Our [Global Equitable Membership (GEM) Program](https://www.crossref.org/gem/) aims to provide greater membership equity and accessibility to organisations in the world’s least economically advantaged countries. Eligible members pay no membership or record registration fees. Eligibility for the program is based on a member’s country. Seeing its effectiveness in increasing participation in the research nexus from previously underrepresented regions, this year we are expanding the GEM program to include 18 new countries.

### Overview of the first 3 years of GEM

The program began in January 2023 with 214 existing members. By the end of 2025, we had 628 organisations under the GEM program. Of these, 535 are independent members, and 89 members work through one of our [sponsors](https://www.crossref.org/membership/about-sponsors). To date, GEM program members have contributed approximately 334,000 works to the [Research Nexus](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/research-nexus).

Global equitable membership202320242025New members joining129127151Total member count327458628

Total number of Crossref GEM members by country until the end of 2025:

GEM country – alphabeticallyTotal no. of membersGEM country – alphabeticallyTotal no. of membersAfghanistan29Malawi2Bangladesh167Maldives4Benin6Mali4Bhutan6Marshall Islands0Burkina Faso7Mauritania1Burundi3Micronesia0Cambodia14Mozambique2Central African Republic1Myanmar3Chad0Nepal60Comoros1Nicaragua2Congo, Democratic Republic24Niger0Côte d’Ivoire3Rwanda9Djibouti0Samoa0Eritrea0São Tomé and Principe0Ethiopia17Senegal7Gambia0Sierra Leone2Ghana38Solomon Islands0Guinea0Somalia10Guinea-Bissau0South Sudan0Guyana3Sri Lanka31Haiti2Sudan14Honduras3Tajikistan8Kiribati0Tanzania, United Republic of28Kosovo9Togo1Kyrgyz Republic27Tonga0Lao, People’s Democratic Rep.5Tuvalu0Lesotho0Uganda23Liberia1Vanuatu0Madagascar5Yemen37Zambia8

![world map with GEM countries highlighted in red](https://www.crossref.org/images/blog/2026/gem-expansion-map.png)

Membership Density in GEM Program Countries until the end of 2025

### Program expansion in 2026

Starting on 1st of January 2026, we’re excited to invite organisations from Angola, Belize, Cabo Verde, Cameroon, Republic of Congo, Dominica, Eswatini, Fiji, Grenada, Kenya, Nigeria, Pakistan, Papua New Guinea, Saint Lucia, Saint Vincent and the Grenadines, Suriname, Timor Leste, and Uzbekistan to join Crossref and register their content and metadata with us without membership or record registration fees. There are 711 existing Crossref members based in these countries who are now eligible for the program, bringing the overall number of GEM members to 1339 across 77 countries (that’s close to 5% of all Crossref members).

In creating our eligibility list, we refer to existing sources. For the first three years of the program, our list was predominantly based on the World Bank’s [International Development Association (IDA)](https://datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/906519-world-bank-country-and-lending-groups) classification. In 2026, we leveraged additional sources to curate our list, resulting in the inclusion of 18 new countries in the program. Following community feedback, we now refer to the IDA, the [IDA Blend List](https://datahelpdesk.worldbank.org/knowledgebase/articles/906519-world-bank-country-and-lending-groups), and the [United Nations Least Developed Countries](https://www.un.org/ohrlls/content/list-ldcs) list. In our choices, we also keep abreast of the global situation and conversations about supporting equitability in scholarly publishing and in the future, we may consider other factors too.

We will review our lists and the eligibility criteria annually and note any changes on our [website](https://www.crossref.org/gem/). Members whose country moves on or off the GEM Program will be notified of any upcoming fees (or the removal of fees) with adequate time to plan and budget accordingly.
Although the GEM program reduces financial barriers, many small organisations may still need administrative, technical, and language support provided by our Sponsors, and we will continue working with suitable organisations to make participation in Crossref easier.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/the-gem-program-year-three-and-program-expansion-for-2026/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Journal Article: “Ten Years of a  ‘Quiet Culture War’: Where Does It Stand Now?”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/13/journal-article-ten-years-of-a-quiet-culture-war-where-does-it-stand-now/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The article linked below was published today by Insights, a UKSG publication. Title Ten Years of a ‘Quiet Culture War’: Where Does It Stand Now Author Rick Anderson University Librarian, Brigham Young University Source Insights DOI: 10.1629/uksg.712 Abstract In 2014, I wrote ‘A quiet culture war in research libraries – and what it means for [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The article linked below was published today by Insights, a UKSG publication. Title Ten Years of a ‘Quiet Culture War’: Where Does It Stand Now Author Rick Anderson University Librarian, Brigham Young University Source Insights DOI: 10.1629/uksg.712 Abstract In 2014, I wrote ‘A quiet culture war in research libraries – and what it means for \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167519</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — AI Use: From Policies to Reality</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/13/guest-post-ai-use-from-policies-to-reality/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest blogger reflect on their panel discussion about policies and realities of AI in scholarly communications at COPE's Publication Integrity Week event last month.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/13/guest-post-ai-use-from-policies-to-reality/">Guest Post — AI Use: From Policies to Reality</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest blogger reflect on their panel discussion about policies and realities of AI in scholarly communications at COPE&#39;s Publication Integrity Week event last month.

The post [Guest Post — AI Use: From Policies to Reality](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/13/guest-post-ai-use-from-policies-to-reality/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61434</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Reads: Exploring recent additions to the University Library collection</title>
      <link>https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/2026/01/13/new-year-new-reads-exploring-recently-additions-to-the-university-library-collection/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="200" src="https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-300x200.png" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" srcset="https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-300x200.png 300w, https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-768x512.png 768w, https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>With the new year upon us, you might be looking for new books to start out 2026. This blog post contains recently published books that&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>![](https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-300x200.png)

With the new year upon us, you might be looking for new books to start out 2026. This blog post contains recently published books that…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/?p=7514</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Reads: Exploring recent additions to the University Library collection</title>
      <link>https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/2026/01/13/new-year-new-reads-exploring-recent-additions-to-the-university-library-collection/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div><img width="300" height="200" src="https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-300x200.png" class="attachment-medium size-medium wp-post-image" alt="" style="margin-bottom: 15px;" decoding="async" fetchpriority="high" srcset="https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-300x200.png 300w, https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-768x512.png 768w, https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11.png 900w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></div>With the new year upon us, you might be looking for new books to start out 2026. This blog post contains recently published books that&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>![](https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/wp-content/uploads/sites/4/2026/01/Untitled-design11-300x200.png)

With the new year upon us, you might be looking for new books to start out 2026. This blog post contains recently published books that…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://library.csun.edu/blogs/cited/?p=7514</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>EveryLibrary Institute Joins the Our Future Memory Coalition</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/12/everylibrary-institute-joins-the-our-future-memory-coalition/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Our Future Memory movement continues to grow, with the EveryLibrary Institute (ELI) formally joining the global coalition and endorsing the Statement on Digital Rights for Protecting Memory Institutions Online. [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The Our Future Memory movement continues to grow, with the EveryLibrary Institute (ELI) formally joining the global coalition and endorsing the Statement on Digital Rights for Protecting Memory Institutions Online. \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29915</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ARL Daily Intelligence (January 12–15)</title>
      <link>https://www.arl.org/daily-intelligence/arl-daily-intelligence-january-12-15/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Last Updated on January 20, 2026, 3:12 pm ET ARL’s former Day in Review is starting 2026 with a new name: ARL Daily Intelligence. Our aim remains the same—curating and sharing the top...</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://www.arl.org/daily-intelligence/arl-daily-intelligence-january-12-15/">ARL Daily Intelligence (January 12–15)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.arl.org">Association of Research Libraries</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Last Updated on January 20, 2026, 3:12 pm ET ARL’s former Day in Review is starting 2026 with a new name: ARL Daily Intelligence. Our aim remains the same—curating and sharing the top...

The post [ARL Daily Intelligence (January 12–15)](https://www.arl.org/daily-intelligence/arl-daily-intelligence-january-12-15/) appeared first on [Association of Research Libraries](https://www.arl.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.arl.org/?p=47079</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>National Library of Korea Opens 30 Million National Bibliography Records to the Public</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/12/national-library-of-korea-opens-30-million-national-bibliography-records-to-the-public/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Note: Blurbs below were translated into English with the use of Google Translate. From The Asia Business Daily (via Google Translate): The National Library of Korea announced on the 12th that it will develop an OpenAPI service based on the National Bibliographic Linked Open Data (LOD) through the &#8216;2025 National Key Data Open Support Project&#8217; [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Note: Blurbs below were translated into English with the use of Google Translate. From The Asia Business Daily (via Google Translate): The National Library of Korea announced on the 12th that it will develop an OpenAPI service based on the National Bibliographic Linked Open Data (LOD) through the ‘2025 National Key Data Open Support Project’ \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167517</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Web Archiving at the Library After 25 Years</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2026/01/web-archiving-at-the-library-after-25-years/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This post is co-written by Abbie Grotke, Amanda Lehman, and Melissa Wertheimer of the Web Archiving Section to close our 25th-anniversary celebration year with some highlights of the program.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>This post is co-written by Abbie Grotke, Amanda Lehman, and Melissa Wertheimer of the Web Archiving Section to close our 25th-anniversary celebration year with some highlights of the program.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/?p=36653</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guest Post — What is The ‘Right’ Way to Make Tea? Why International Marketing Needs a Local Touch</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/12/guest-post-what-is-the-right-way-to-make-tea-why-international-marketing-needs-a-local-touch/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Today's guest bloggers advocate for marketing strategy using localization, which brings cultural fluency, awareness, and authenticity to our communication with partners around the world.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/12/guest-post-what-is-the-right-way-to-make-tea-why-international-marketing-needs-a-local-touch/">Guest Post — What is The ‘Right’ Way to Make Tea? Why International Marketing Needs a Local Touch</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today&#39;s guest bloggers advocate for marketing strategy using localization, which brings cultural fluency, awareness, and authenticity to our communication with partners around the world.

The post [Guest Post — What is The ‘Right’ Way to Make Tea? Why International Marketing Needs a Local Touch](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/12/guest-post-what-is-the-right-way-to-make-tea-why-international-marketing-needs-a-local-touch/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/wp-content/uploads/2026/01/Localization-SK-Article-Lou-Peck-audio.mp3" length="6337951" type="audio/mpeg" />
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61427</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Chronicles of Cheifet</title>
      <link>https://blog.archive.org/2026/01/11/the-chronicles-of-cheifet/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The end of 2025 brought news of the passing of Stewart Cheifet, creator of Computer Chronicles, and Net Cafe, two shows about electronics and computers that are, depending on your [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The end of 2025 brought news of the passing of Stewart Cheifet, creator of Computer Chronicles, and Net Cafe, two shows about electronics and computers that are, depending on your \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.archive.org/?p=29893</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Conan Stories, by Robert E. Howard</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/robert-e-howard/conan-stories</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A collection of Robert E. Howard’s short stories featuring Conan the Barbarian.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A collection of Robert E. Howard’s short stories featuring Conan the Barbarian.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/robert-e-howard/conan-stories/downloads/robert-e-howard_conan-stories.epub?source=feed" length="894771" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/robert-e-howard/conan-stories</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Story of Doctor Dolittle, by Hugh Lofting</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/hugh-lofting/the-story-of-doctor-dolittle</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A kindhearted doctor who can speak the language of animals embarks on a whimsical adventure to Africa.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A kindhearted doctor who can speak the language of animals embarks on a whimsical adventure to Africa.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/hugh-lofting/the-story-of-doctor-dolittle/downloads/hugh-lofting_the-story-of-doctor-dolittle.epub?source=feed" length="483275" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/hugh-lofting/the-story-of-doctor-dolittle</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Journal Article: Generative AI in Higher Education: A Bibliometric Review of Emerging Trends, Power Dynamics, and Global Research Landscapes</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/10/new-journal-article-generative-ai-in-higher-education-a-bibliometric-review-of-emerging-trends-power-dynamics-and-global-research-landscapes/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The article linked below was recently published by Computers and Education: Artificial Intelligence. Title Generative AI in Higher Education: A Bibliometric Review of Emerging Trends, Power Dynamics, and Global Research Landscapes Authors Kun Dai The Chinese University of Hong Kong Yabing Liu The Education University of Hong Kong Xiaofan Zhang The Chinese University of Hong [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The article linked below was recently published by Computers and Education: Artificial Intelligence. Title Generative AI in Higher Education: A Bibliometric Review of Emerging Trends, Power Dynamics, and Global Research Landscapes Authors Kun Dai The Chinese University of Hong Kong Yabing Liu The Education University of Hong Kong Xiaofan Zhang The Chinese University of Hong \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167512</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>University of Washington Researchers Analyzed Which Anthologized Writers and Books Get Checked Out the Most From Seattle Public Library</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/09/university-of-washington-researchers-analyzed-which-anthologized-writers-and-books-get-checked-out-the-most-from-seattle-public-library/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From UW: Seattle Public Library, or SPL, is the only U.S. library system that makes its anonymized, granular checkout data public. Want to find out how many times people borrowed the e-book version of Toni Morrison’s “Beloved” in May 2018? That data is available. The hitch is that the library’s data set contains nearly 50 [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From UW: Seattle Public Library, or SPL, is the only U.S. library system that makes its anonymized, granular checkout data public. Want to find out how many times people borrowed the e-book version of Toni Morrison’s “Beloved” in May 2018? That data is available. The hitch is that the library’s data set contains nearly 50 \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167502</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>What’s New Online at the Library of Congress: January 2026</title>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2026/01/new-loc-jan-2026/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In our first edition of "What’s New Online at the Library of Congress" of 2026, we share updates to the Library's digital collections, web archives, crowdsourced transcriptions, and historical newspapers from Washington, D.C. Click through to learn more!]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In our first edition of &#34;What’s New Online at the Library of Congress&#34; of 2026, we share updates to the Library&#39;s digital collections, web archives, crowdsourced transcriptions, and historical newspapers from Washington, D.C. Click through to learn more!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/?p=36635</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>AI in Scholarly Publishing — SSP Pulse Check Report</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/09/ai-in-scholarly-publishing-ssp-pulse-check-report/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The first of SSP’s new polling initiative, Pulse Check, explores AI in scholarly publishing and set out to understand how our communities are navigating this monumental shift. </p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/09/ai-in-scholarly-publishing-ssp-pulse-check-report/">AI in Scholarly Publishing — SSP Pulse Check Report</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The first of SSP’s new polling initiative, Pulse Check, explores AI in scholarly publishing and set out to understand how our communities are navigating this monumental shift.

The post [AI in Scholarly Publishing — SSP Pulse Check Report](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/09/ai-in-scholarly-publishing-ssp-pulse-check-report/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61409</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Digital Collections: Now Available Online via the KC Library: Over 500,000 Photos From the Kansas City Star’s Historical Photo Archives</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/08/digital-collections-now-available-online-via-the-kc-library-over-500000-photos-from-the-kansas-city-stars-historical-photo-archives/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[\From the  Kansas City Star (via the Kansas City Public Library): Today, I’m excited to announce the launch of KCStarPhotos.org, a new project from the Kansas City Public Library and The Kansas City Star. It’s a free website with a database of hundreds of thousands of images from The Star’s archives of the pre-digital era of photography. It’s [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>\\From the  Kansas City Star (via the Kansas City Public Library): Today, I’m excited to announce the launch of KCStarPhotos.org, a new project from the Kansas City Public Library and The Kansas City Star. It’s a free website with a database of hundreds of thousands of images from The Star’s archives of the pre-digital era of photography. It’s \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167488</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New From Research Data Alliance (RDA): Glọbal Community Priorities for Agentic Al in Research Community Consultation Results</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/08/new-from-research-data-alliance-rda-global-community-priorities-for-agentic-al-in-research-community-consultation-sresults/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From the Research Data Alliance (RDA): The results from the global community consultation on agentic AI in research are now available. The consultation explored current use of agentic AI in research and gathered perspectives on its value throughout the research lifecycle. Launched in November 2025, the consultation defined agentic AI as ‘artificial intelligence systems capable [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From the Research Data Alliance (RDA): The results from the global community consultation on agentic AI in research are now available. The consultation explored current use of agentic AI in research and gathered perspectives on its value throughout the research lifecycle. Launched in November 2025, the consultation defined agentic AI as ‘artificial intelligence systems capable \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167483</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Announcing APTrust’s New Preservation Storage Criteria</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/08/announcing-aptrusts-new-preservation-storage-criteria/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From APTrust: APTrust is pleased to announce the publication of our new Preservation Storage Criteria, now available on the APTrust website. These criteria provide a clear, community-informed framework for evaluating current and future preservation storage providers in support of APTrust’s long-term stewardship mission. [Clip] As APTrust continues to diversify and evolve its preservation storage options, it [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From APTrust: APTrust is pleased to announce the publication of our new Preservation Storage Criteria, now available on the APTrust website. These criteria provide a clear, community-informed framework for evaluating current and future preservation storage providers in support of APTrust’s long-term stewardship mission. \[Clip\] As APTrust continues to diversify and evolve its preservation storage options, it \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167480</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Hot Takes on the First Quarter of 21st Century Scholarly Publishing</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/08/hot-takes-on-first-quarter-century-scholarly-publishing/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Todd Carpenter looks back on the past quarter century of a digital revolution in scholarly publishing.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/08/hot-takes-on-first-quarter-century-scholarly-publishing/">Hot Takes on the First Quarter of 21st Century Scholarly Publishing</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Todd Carpenter looks back on the past quarter century of a digital revolution in scholarly publishing.

The post [Hot Takes on the First Quarter of 21st Century Scholarly Publishing](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/08/hot-takes-on-first-quarter-century-scholarly-publishing/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61403</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Reduction of Grant DOI registration fees: a boost for the Research Nexus</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/reduction-of-grant-doi-registration-fees-a-boost-for-the-research-nexus/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that&mdash;effective 1st January 2026&mdash;we have made two changes to grant record registration fees that aim to accelerate adoption of Crossref&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/">Grant Linking System (GLS)</a> and provide a two-year window of opportunity to increase the number and availability of open persistent grant identifiers and boost the matching of relationships with research objects.</p>
        <div class="shortcode-divwrap align-right">
        <span><figure class="img-responsive"><img src="https://www.crossref.org/images/community-images/gls/gls-benefits.png"
        alt="High-level benefits of the Crossref Grant Linking System (GLS)" width="100%">
        </figure>
        </span>
        </div>
        Launched in 2019 with close input from several funders and other infrastructure organisations, the GLS primarily offers the ability to create and steward Crossref Grant DOIs, along with several benefits such as dedicated grant/award metadata like funding type, value, contributors, and projects, as well as hosted landing pages, tools to create and update metadata, and of course both member-asserted and Crossref-automatic matching of relationships within the global corpus of 180 million other research objects. Essentially, we need to identify what research objects are produced as a result of the award, and these objects could be articles, preprints, data, code, blogs, posters, and more.
        <p>This connected network is what we call the Research Nexus, essential for exploring research activity in general, as well as evaluating reach and return on funding and other support like use of facilities/equipment.</p>
        <h3 id="a-fee-reduction-and-a-two-year-fee-waiver-pilot">A fee reduction and a two-year fee waiver pilot</h3>
        <p>Following a review by our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/committees/membership-and-fees/">Membership &amp; Fees Committee</a>, the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#board-members">Board</a> met in December and passed two related motions:</p>
        <ol>
        <li><strong>Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee has been cut in half to match other record types</strong>: The board approved the adjustment of the Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee down from $2.00 to $1.00 USD, effective 1st January 2026.</li>
        <li><strong>Back-Year (BY) grant registration fee is waived through 2027</strong>: The board approved a time-limited fee waiver as a pilot for Back-Year (BY) grant registration fees, bringing that per-record fee down from $0.30 to $0.00 for 2026 and 2027.</li>
        </ol>
        <p>We aim to boost registration of Back-Year (BY) records and accelerate the growth of the Research Nexus with millions more grant&lt;-&gt;output matches. During the course of the two-year pilot, the Membership &amp; Fees Committee and our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/">fee project work</a> that started in 2023 and also <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10" target="_blank">brought in other fee reductions</a>, will consider more adjustments across BY registration fees for the benefit of members beyond just funders and beyond just grants.</p>
        <p>All <a href="https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#motions">Board motions are publicly available</a> and we encourage questions from the community about our governance processes and the decisions on our members&rsquo; behalf; <a href="mailto:feedback@crossref.org">email us via feedback@crossref.org</a> anytime, or <a href="https://community.crossref.org/c/strategy/" target="_blank">post on the forum</a>.</p>
        <h3 id="supercharging-the-grant-linking-system">Supercharging the Grant Linking System</h3>
        <p>Leading up to the <a href="https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/">GLS</a> launch in 2019, we worked with a group of funders and metadata experts to inform the design and implementation of the new service, including a funder governance and fees working group. That was seven years ago, and our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/working-groups/funders/">Funder Advisory Group</a> now includes nearly 100 funding community representatives the GLS has grown to almost 50 funder members that have registered more than 185,000 open grant metadata records. But they are mostly research councils and agencies or charities from Europe and North America, and we know that for a truly comprehensive and interconnected Research Nexus, more needs to be done to include organisations from all parts of the world. The other key driver is simply to boost more metadata connections; the more grant metadata we gather, the better we can match it to all kinds of research outputs, and <a href="">this metadata directly feeds thousands of services</a> available in our community, from Dimensions and Scopus, to OA.Report and OpenAlex, as well as funders&rsquo; own analytics tools. See our <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09" target="_blank">recent report about the latest dataset</a> and of course use <a href="htps://api.crossref.org">api.crossref.org</a> directly.</p>
        <p>Relatedly, we just added a <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/x7d4h-x3r11" target="_blank">new Grant DOI field</a> to our schema for all record types, to give our members a precise and accurate way of capturing funding metadata for all research outputs. With the new lower CY registration fee and a pilot waiver of BY fees for grant records, we hope to boost the creation of more Grant DOIs by more funders from more parts of the world&mdash;so that others also see and can build on the momentum and reuse the data in their own tools and services. <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/" target="_blank">All actors need to play their role</a>, and Crossref’s part is in running the global linking infrastructure at scale, connecting research objects and making them openly available while ensuring that the barriers for the registration, use and reuse of metadata remain as low as possible.</p>
        <p>We feel we&rsquo;re at a tipping point that only needs a small nudge to truly scale the Grant Linking System.</p>
        <p>By waiving BY fees entirely for two years, we&rsquo;re hoping to see members fill in historical data and create more comprehensive grant&lt;-&gt;outcome connections. There is often a long period of time between funding being awarded, and the resulting research objects being generated and communicated. That is why historical grant metadata is so important; we think that there will be many funding outcome relationships and insights just waiting to be uncovered!</p>
        <h3 id="why-give-funders-a-fee-break-and-not-others">Why give funders a fee break and not others?</h3>
        <p>We&rsquo;re not ruling out this kind of fee incentive in future for other members and other object types, but that needs more analysis (which we plan to do) and right now, the relatively small number of grant records, combined with a growing need for this kind of metadata, means the changes are small enough to have almost no impact on Crossref&rsquo;s healthy financial position.</p>
        <p>This decision is consistent with the goals of our <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/">Resourcing Crossref for Future Sustainability (RCFS)</a> to review our fees to make sure they are equitable and clear, while ensuring Crossref retains a sustainable business model. Our fees can encourage or discourage the community to participate in Crossref. The RCFS project has also resulted in the creation of a <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/j2bgz-v7h50/" target="_blank">lower membership fee tier</a> for the very lowest-resourced members, and the tidying up of <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10" target="_blank">things like outlier volume discounts</a>.</p>
        <p>The BY fee waiver is positioned as a pilot to allow us to measure its impact over the next two years and feed into the Membership &amp; Fees Committee and RCFS project. We will evaluate the pilot results (i.e. does it indeed supercharge funding metadata connections and adoption?) and consider additional adjustments to other BY registration fees and whether such fee incentives might be extended to other members.</p>
        <p>We encourage all funders to take advantage of these reduced rates to contribute to the Research Nexus and help us build a more complete picture of the relationship between research funding and outcomes.</p>
        <p>Take a look at the recent case studies from early GLS adopters <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/n9n69-y5b75" target="_blank">FWF</a> (Austria), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69" target="_blank">NWO</a> (The Netherlands), <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/9gjfp-5p698" target="_blank">FCCN|FCT</a> (Portugal), and <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/c1dh8-qn968" target="_blank">Wellcome/EuropePMC</a>, reach out to them or us with any questions, or peruse the <a href="https://community.crossref.org/c/crossref-services/grant-linking-system/" target="_blank">GLS community forum</a>!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We are pleased to announce that—effective 1st January 2026—we have made two changes to grant record registration fees that aim to accelerate adoption of Crossref’s [Grant Linking System (GLS)](https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/) and provide a two-year window of opportunity to increase the number and availability of open persistent grant identifiers and boost the matching of relationships with research objects.

![High-level benefits of the Crossref Grant Linking System (GLS)](https://www.crossref.org/images/community-images/gls/gls-benefits.png)

Launched in 2019 with close input from several funders and other infrastructure organisations, the GLS primarily offers the ability to create and steward Crossref Grant DOIs, along with several benefits such as dedicated grant/award metadata like funding type, value, contributors, and projects, as well as hosted landing pages, tools to create and update metadata, and of course both member-asserted and Crossref-automatic matching of relationships within the global corpus of 180 million other research objects. Essentially, we need to identify what research objects are produced as a result of the award, and these objects could be articles, preprints, data, code, blogs, posters, and more.

This connected network is what we call the Research Nexus, essential for exploring research activity in general, as well as evaluating reach and return on funding and other support like use of facilities/equipment.

### A fee reduction and a two-year fee waiver pilot

Following a review by our [Membership &#38; Fees Committee](https://www.crossref.org/committees/membership-and-fees/), the [Board](https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#board-members) met in December and passed two related motions:

1. **Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee has been cut in half to match other record types**: The board approved the adjustment of the Current-Year (CY) grant registration fee down from $2.00 to $1.00 USD, effective 1st January 2026.
2. **Back-Year (BY) grant registration fee is waived through 2027**: The board approved a time-limited fee waiver as a pilot for Back-Year (BY) grant registration fees, bringing that per-record fee down from $0.30 to $0.00 for 2026 and 2027.

We aim to boost registration of Back-Year (BY) records and accelerate the growth of the Research Nexus with millions more grant&#60;-&#62;output matches. During the course of the two-year pilot, the Membership &#38; Fees Committee and our [fee project work](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/) that started in 2023 and also [brought in other fee reductions](https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10), will consider more adjustments across BY registration fees for the benefit of members beyond just funders and beyond just grants.

All [Board motions are publicly available](https://www.crossref.org/board-and-governance/#motions) and we encourage questions from the community about our governance processes and the decisions on our members’ behalf; [email us via feedback@crossref.org](mailto:feedback@crossref.org) anytime, or [post on the forum](https://community.crossref.org/c/strategy/).

### Supercharging the Grant Linking System

Leading up to the [GLS](https://www.crossref.org/services/grant-linking-system/) launch in 2019, we worked with a group of funders and metadata experts to inform the design and implementation of the new service, including a funder governance and fees working group. That was seven years ago, and our [Funder Advisory Group](https://www.crossref.org/working-groups/funders/) now includes nearly 100 funding community representatives the GLS has grown to almost 50 funder members that have registered more than 185,000 open grant metadata records. But they are mostly research councils and agencies or charities from Europe and North America, and we know that for a truly comprehensive and interconnected Research Nexus, more needs to be done to include organisations from all parts of the world. The other key driver is simply to boost more metadata connections; the more grant metadata we gather, the better we can match it to all kinds of research outputs, and this metadata directly feeds thousands of services available in our community, from Dimensions and Scopus, to OA.Report and OpenAlex, as well as funders’ own analytics tools. See our [recent report about the latest dataset](https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09) and of course use [api.crossref.org](htps://api.crossref.org) directly.

Relatedly, we just added a [new Grant DOI field](https://doi.org/10.64000/x7d4h-x3r11) to our schema for all record types, to give our members a precise and accurate way of capturing funding metadata for all research outputs. With the new lower CY registration fee and a pilot waiver of BY fees for grant records, we hope to boost the creation of more Grant DOIs by more funders from more parts of the world—so that others also see and can build on the momentum and reuse the data in their own tools and services. [All actors need to play their role](https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/), and Crossref’s part is in running the global linking infrastructure at scale, connecting research objects and making them openly available while ensuring that the barriers for the registration, use and reuse of metadata remain as low as possible.

We feel we’re at a tipping point that only needs a small nudge to truly scale the Grant Linking System.

By waiving BY fees entirely for two years, we’re hoping to see members fill in historical data and create more comprehensive grant&#60;-&#62;outcome connections. There is often a long period of time between funding being awarded, and the resulting research objects being generated and communicated. That is why historical grant metadata is so important; we think that there will be many funding outcome relationships and insights just waiting to be uncovered!

### Why give funders a fee break and not others?

We’re not ruling out this kind of fee incentive in future for other members and other object types, but that needs more analysis (which we plan to do) and right now, the relatively small number of grant records, combined with a growing need for this kind of metadata, means the changes are small enough to have almost no impact on Crossref’s healthy financial position.

This decision is consistent with the goals of our [Resourcing Crossref for Future Sustainability (RCFS)](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/resourcing-crossref/) to review our fees to make sure they are equitable and clear, while ensuring Crossref retains a sustainable business model. Our fees can encourage or discourage the community to participate in Crossref. The RCFS project has also resulted in the creation of a [lower membership fee tier](https://doi.org/10.64000/j2bgz-v7h50/) for the very lowest-resourced members, and the tidying up of [things like outlier volume discounts](https://doi.org/10.64000/cvvj8-tax10).

The BY fee waiver is positioned as a pilot to allow us to measure its impact over the next two years and feed into the Membership &#38; Fees Committee and RCFS project. We will evaluate the pilot results (i.e. does it indeed supercharge funding metadata connections and adoption?) and consider additional adjustments to other BY registration fees and whether such fee incentives might be extended to other members.

We encourage all funders to take advantage of these reduced rates to contribute to the Research Nexus and help us build a more complete picture of the relationship between research funding and outcomes.

Take a look at the recent case studies from early GLS adopters [FWF](https://doi.org/10.64000/n9n69-y5b75) (Austria), [NWO](https://doi.org/10.64000/dvqke-j4v69) (The Netherlands), [FCCN\|FCT](https://doi.org/10.64000/9gjfp-5p698) (Portugal), and [Wellcome/EuropePMC](https://doi.org/10.64000/c1dh8-qn968), reach out to them or us with any questions, or peruse the [GLS community forum](https://community.crossref.org/c/crossref-services/grant-linking-system/)!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/reduction-of-grant-doi-registration-fees-a-boost-for-the-research-nexus/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Publication Alert: Inaugural Issue of International Journal of Disability Policy &#38; Advocacy (IJDPA)</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/07/publication-alert-inaugural-issue-of-international-journal-of-disability-policy-advocacy-ijdpa/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The inaugural issue of the International Journal of Disability Policy and Advocacy  is now available. Issue 1 includes the article &#8220;Bridging the Gap: How Congress Can Codify the Rights ofPeople with Disabilities to Access Digital Works&#8221; by Katherine Klosek, Director of Information Policy and Federal Relations at the Association of Research Libraries (ARL). About IJDPA [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The inaugural issue of the International Journal of Disability Policy and Advocacy  is now available. Issue 1 includes the article “Bridging the Gap: How Congress Can Codify the Rights ofPeople with Disabilities to Access Digital Works” by Katherine Klosek, Director of Information Policy and Federal Relations at the Association of Research Libraries (ARL). About IJDPA \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167506</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The World Below, by S. Fowler Wright</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/s-fowler-wright/the-world-below</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A time traveler travels to Earth’s distant future in search of two predecessors lost in the same era.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A time traveler travels to Earth’s distant future in search of two predecessors lost in the same era.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/s-fowler-wright/the-world-below/downloads/s-fowler-wright_the-world-below.epub?source=feed" length="465253" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/s-fowler-wright/the-world-below</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>New Journal Article: “Chatbots for Reference Services in Academic Libraries: Applications and Trends”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/07/new-journal-article-chatbots-for-reference-services-in-academic-libraries-applications-and-trends/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The article linked below was recently published by The Journal of Academic Librarianship. Title Chatbots for Reference Services in Academic Libraries: Applications and Trends Authors Guoying Liu University of Windsor Leddy Library, Canada Shu Liu Peking University Library, China Source The Journal of Academic Librarianship Volume 52, Issue 1, January 2026 First Online: Jan. 5, [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The article linked below was recently published by The Journal of Academic Librarianship. Title Chatbots for Reference Services in Academic Libraries: Applications and Trends Authors Guoying Liu University of Windsor Leddy Library, Canada Shu Liu Peking University Library, China Source The Journal of Academic Librarianship Volume 52, Issue 1, January 2026 First Online: Jan. 5, \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167477</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Kitchen Essentials: An Interview with Tanja Niemann of Érudit / Une Entrevue  avec Tanja Niemann d’Érudit</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/07/kitchen-essentials-an-interview-with-tanja-niemann-of-erudit-une-entrevue-avec-tanja-niemann-derudit/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>For today's Kitchen Essentials post, Alice Meadows interviews Tanja Niemann, Executive Director of Érudit, a Quebec-based non-profit open access publishing platform.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/07/kitchen-essentials-an-interview-with-tanja-niemann-of-erudit-une-entrevue-avec-tanja-niemann-derudit/">Kitchen Essentials: An Interview with Tanja Niemann of Érudit / Une Entrevue  avec Tanja Niemann d’Érudit</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>For today&#39;s Kitchen Essentials post, Alice Meadows interviews Tanja Niemann, Executive Director of Érudit, a Quebec-based non-profit open access publishing platform.

The post [Kitchen Essentials: An Interview with Tanja Niemann of Érudit / Une Entrevue avec Tanja Niemann d’Érudit](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/07/kitchen-essentials-an-interview-with-tanja-niemann-of-erudit-une-entrevue-avec-tanja-niemann-derudit/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61400</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rare Photos of Rosa Parks Discovered in the Archives of Stanford University Libraries</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/06/rare-photos-of-rosa-parks-discovered-in-the-archives-of-stanford-university-libraries/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From Stanford Report: Photographs of civil rights activist Rosa Parks were recently made public after they were discovered in the archives of Stanford University Libraries. Taken during the 1965 march from Selma to Montgomery, Alabama, the images reveal a side of Parks rarely shown to the public. After taking the photos, late photographer Matt Herron [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From Stanford Report: Photographs of civil rights activist Rosa Parks were recently made public after they were discovered in the archives of Stanford University Libraries. Taken during the 1965 march from Selma to Montgomery, Alabama, the images reveal a side of Parks rarely shown to the public. After taking the photos, late photographer Matt Herron \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167468</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Haunted Hotel, by Wilkie Collins</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-haunted-hotel</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The death in Venice of a wealthy man under very mysterious circumstances leads to suspicions of a supernatural cause.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The death in Venice of a wealthy man under very mysterious circumstances leads to suspicions of a supernatural cause.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-haunted-hotel/downloads/wilkie-collins_the-haunted-hotel.epub?source=feed" length="724085" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/wilkie-collins/the-haunted-hotel</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Brooklyn Murders, by G. D. H. Cole</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-d-h-cole/the-brooklyn-murders</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Scotland Yard and a pair of amateur sleuths investigate the case of two heirs to a fortune who apparently murdered each other.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Scotland Yard and a pair of amateur sleuths investigate the case of two heirs to a fortune who apparently murdered each other.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-d-h-cole/the-brooklyn-murders/downloads/g-d-h-cole_the-brooklyn-murders.epub?source=feed" length="532876" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/g-d-h-cole/the-brooklyn-murders</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ORCID Releases New Strategic Plan: “ORCID 2030: Advancing the Future of Research”</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/06/orcid-releases-new-strategic-plan-orcid-2030-advancing-the-future-of-research/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From an ORCID Blog Post: Our new strategic plan, ORCID 2030: Advancing the Future of Research, outlines our commitment to meeting the challenges and opportunities presented by this dynamic future and underscores a significant evolution in our focus, moving from a foundation of establishing trust and value to a more active, expansive role in empowering the [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From an ORCID Blog Post: Our new strategic plan, ORCID 2030: Advancing the Future of Research, outlines our commitment to meeting the challenges and opportunities presented by this dynamic future and underscores a significant evolution in our focus, moving from a foundation of establishing trust and value to a more active, expansive role in empowering the \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167466</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Keywords Are Not Dead — But Discovery Is No Longer Just Search</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/06/keywords-are-not-dead-but-discovery-is-no-longer-just-search/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>As with previous shifts in content discovery, today's winners will be those who understand the strengths and limits of AI search, and design systems that let researchers move fluidly between precision and synthesis.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/06/keywords-are-not-dead-but-discovery-is-no-longer-just-search/">Keywords Are Not Dead — But Discovery Is No Longer Just Search</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>As with previous shifts in content discovery, today&#39;s winners will be those who understand the strengths and limits of AI search, and design systems that let researchers move fluidly between precision and synthesis.

The post [Keywords Are Not Dead — But Discovery Is No Longer Just Search](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/06/keywords-are-not-dead-but-discovery-is-no-longer-just-search/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61396</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The best way of acknowledging research funding in the metadata: Crossref Grant ID</title>
      <link>https://www.crossref.org/blog/the-best-way-of-acknowledging-research-funding-in-the-metadata-crossref-grant-id/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>We are very pleased to kick off the New Year with another important schema update and the news that a Grant DOI field is now supported for all record types. This means that Crossref members can explicitly include the Crossref Grant IDs as part of their DOI metadata records for publications and any other output type, accurately linking research outputs to the funding that made it possible, all through metadata. We hope that our members will leverage this to respond to recent calls for <a href="https://council.science/statements/isc-position-on-research-funding-transparency/" target="_blank">stronger funding transparency</a> and best practices for <a href="https://publicationethics.org/guidance/discussion-document/declaring-funding-sources-research" target="_blank">reporting funding sources in research outputs</a>. </p>
        <p>Funding information is very important for the research community. As explored by <a href="https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2025/12/11/open-funder-metadata-is-essential-for-true-research-transparency/" target="_blank">some key European funder representatives</a>, providing mechanisms to clearly link funding with its outputs is essential for the community to have a full picture of the research endeavour.</p>
        <div class="quotecite">
        <blockquote>
        <p>When funders systematically register grants with persistent identifiers and make this information openly available, they create a foundation that publishers and infrastructure providers such as repositories can reliably build upon when depositing output metadata.”</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p><cite>&ndash; Hans de Jonge, Katharina Rieck and Zoé Ancion</cite></p>
        </div>
        <p>Up until now, if a Crossref member wanted to include a Crossref Grant ID to unambiguously identify the output funding source, they would need to use other available fields, such as for an award number. While it was an important step towards increasing transparency and is heavily used for reporting and impact assessment, being an unstructured field, it was prone to errors, and of course, funders’ internal award identifiers are not unique, persistent, or necessarily open. This limited our ability to create unambiguous relationships with the Crossref Grant DOIs registered by our now ~50 funder members. As the new field becomes increasingly populated by our members, this rich metadata will pave the way for capturing and representing the funding relationships in a more accurate and complete way and fulfilling one of our commitments at the <a href="https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/" target="_blank">recent funding metadata workshop with the Barcelona Declaration.</a> </p>
        <p><strong>The Crossref Grant ID field in the schema is a clear signal of the growing demand for these persistent Grant IDs (Crossref DOIs), and the relationships these help us create.</strong> Those connections can in turn enable streamlined reporting for the grantees, as well as compliance tracking and programme evaluation for funders. </p>
        <p>As part of our work to enable the research nexus, Crossref has been proactively identifying funding information and prototyping metadata enrichment processes <a href="https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/">through matching projects</a>, ensuring that as many <a href="https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09" target="_blank">relationships as possible are established and made discoverable</a>. With this schema update, we aim to lower barriers and encourage more members to register output-funding relationships at source. This will facilitate the links that make the research nexus a connected, interoperable, and an important source of information that ensures a transparent and trustworthy research process. </p>
        <p><strong>We encourage all Crossref members to start incorporating Grant DOIs when available into your metadata submissions.</strong> By taking advantage of this new field, you&rsquo;ll help build a more complete and transparent record of research funding, making it easier for the community to understand and trace the impact of funded research. </p>
        <p>When collecting funding information for your publication, please consider asking the authors for the Grant DOI (Crossref Grant ID) as well as the funder’s details (such as their name and identifier). Here’s how the U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Scientific and Technical Information&rsquo;s (OSTI-DOE) grant <a href="https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611</a> can be included in the metadata for related works, from datasets, to preprints, conference proceedings, journal articles, and more:</p>
        <div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-JS" data-lang="JS"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;fundgroup&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;ror&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="nx">https</span><span class="o">:</span><span class="c1">//ror.org/04qxsr837&lt;/assertion&gt;
        </span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="c1"></span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;grant_doi&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mf">10.46936</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="nx">aps</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">182101</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="mi">60010611</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span></code></pre></div><p>Similarly, a grant <a href="https://doi.org/10.3030/732489" target="_blank">https://doi.org/10.3030/732489</a> from European Union H2020-EU.2.1.1. - INDUSTRIAL LEADERSHIP, would be represented in related work’s metadata as follows:</p>
        <div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"><code class="language-JS" data-lang="JS"><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;fundgroup&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;funder_name”&gt;H2020 LEIT Information and Communication Technologies
        </span></span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="s2"> &lt;assertion name=&#34;</span><span class="nx">funder_identifier</span><span class="err">”</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mf">10.13039</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="mi">100010669</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">assertion</span> <span class="nx">name</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s2">&#34;grant_doi&#34;</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="mf">10.3030</span><span class="o">/</span><span class="mi">732489</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span><span class="line"><span class="cl"><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="err">/assertion&gt;</span>
        </span></span></code></pre></div><p>For more technical documentation and implementation guidance, please visit <a href="https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/funding-information/">our funding data documentation</a>. If you have questions or need support integrating Grant IDs into your workflow, our support team is here to help!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>We are very pleased to kick off the New Year with another important schema update and the news that a Grant DOI field is now supported for all record types. This means that Crossref members can explicitly include the Crossref Grant IDs as part of their DOI metadata records for publications and any other output type, accurately linking research outputs to the funding that made it possible, all through metadata. We hope that our members will leverage this to respond to recent calls for [stronger funding transparency](https://council.science/statements/isc-position-on-research-funding-transparency/) and best practices for [reporting funding sources in research outputs](https://publicationethics.org/guidance/discussion-document/declaring-funding-sources-research).

Funding information is very important for the research community. As explored by [some key European funder representatives](https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/impactofsocialsciences/2025/12/11/open-funder-metadata-is-essential-for-true-research-transparency/), providing mechanisms to clearly link funding with its outputs is essential for the community to have a full picture of the research endeavour.

&#62; When funders systematically register grants with persistent identifiers and make this information openly available, they create a foundation that publishers and infrastructure providers such as repositories can reliably build upon when depositing output metadata.”

– Hans de Jonge, Katharina Rieck and Zoé Ancion

Up until now, if a Crossref member wanted to include a Crossref Grant ID to unambiguously identify the output funding source, they would need to use other available fields, such as for an award number. While it was an important step towards increasing transparency and is heavily used for reporting and impact assessment, being an unstructured field, it was prone to errors, and of course, funders’ internal award identifiers are not unique, persistent, or necessarily open. This limited our ability to create unambiguous relationships with the Crossref Grant DOIs registered by our now ~50 funder members. As the new field becomes increasingly populated by our members, this rich metadata will pave the way for capturing and representing the funding relationships in a more accurate and complete way and fulfilling one of our commitments at the [recent funding metadata workshop with the Barcelona Declaration.](https://barcelona-declaration.org/news/20251023_community_roundtable/)

**The Crossref Grant ID field in the schema is a clear signal of the growing demand for these persistent Grant IDs (Crossref DOIs), and the relationships these help us create.** Those connections can in turn enable streamlined reporting for the grantees, as well as compliance tracking and programme evaluation for funders.

As part of our work to enable the research nexus, Crossref has been proactively identifying funding information and prototyping metadata enrichment processes [through matching projects](https://www.crossref.org/community/special-programs/metadata-matching/), ensuring that as many [relationships as possible are established and made discoverable](https://doi.org/10.64000/607z6-1nh09). With this schema update, we aim to lower barriers and encourage more members to register output-funding relationships at source. This will facilitate the links that make the research nexus a connected, interoperable, and an important source of information that ensures a transparent and trustworthy research process.

**We encourage all Crossref members to start incorporating Grant DOIs when available into your metadata submissions.** By taking advantage of this new field, you’ll help build a more complete and transparent record of research funding, making it easier for the community to understand and trace the impact of funded research.

When collecting funding information for your publication, please consider asking the authors for the Grant DOI (Crossref Grant ID) as well as the funder’s details (such as their name and identifier). Here’s how the U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Scientific and Technical Information’s (OSTI-DOE) grant [https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611](https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-182101/60010611) can be included in the metadata for related works, from datasets, to preprints, conference proceedings, journal articles, and more:

```JS
&#60;assertion name=&#34;fundgroup&#34;&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;ror&#34;&#62;https://ror.org/04qxsr837&#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;grant_doi&#34;&#62;10.46936/aps-182101/60010611&#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;/assertion&#62;

```

Similarly, a grant [https://doi.org/10.3030/732489](https://doi.org/10.3030/732489) from European Union H2020-EU.2.1.1. - INDUSTRIAL LEADERSHIP, would be represented in related work’s metadata as follows:

```JS
&#60;assertion name=&#34;fundgroup&#34;&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;funder_name”&#62;H2020 LEIT Information and Communication Technologies
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;funder_identifier”&#62;10.13039/100010669&#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;/assertion&#62;
 &#60;assertion name=&#34;grant_doi&#34;&#62;10.3030/732489&#60;/assertion&#62;
&#60;/assertion&#62;

```

For more technical documentation and implementation guidance, please visit [our funding data documentation](https://www.crossref.org/documentation/schema-library/markup-guide-metadata-segments/funding-information/). If you have questions or need support integrating Grant IDs into your workflow, our support team is here to help!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.crossref.org/blog/the-best-way-of-acknowledging-research-funding-in-the-metadata-crossref-grant-id/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Apple Cart, by George Bernard Shaw</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/the-apple-cart</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An English king challenges his popular prime minister and cabinet.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>An English king challenges his popular prime minister and cabinet.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/the-apple-cart/downloads/george-bernard-shaw_the-apple-cart.epub?source=feed" length="535483" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/george-bernard-shaw/the-apple-cart</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Planet of the Damned, by Harry Harrison</title>
      <link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/harry-harrison/planet-of-the-damned</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A planetary champion finds himself employed to solve another planet’s pressing problem.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A planetary champion finds himself employed to solve another planet’s pressing problem.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/harry-harrison/planet-of-the-damned/downloads/harry-harrison_planet-of-the-damned.epub?source=feed" length="798945" type="application/epub+zip" />
      <guid>cid://https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/harry-harrison/planet-of-the-damned</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Tennessee: Here’s Which Libraries Have Been Ordered to Review Book Collections</title>
      <link>https://www.infodocket.com/2026/01/05/tennessee-heres-which-libraries-have-been-ordered-to-review-book-collections/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[From The Tennessean:  &#124;&#124;&#124; Archived Version Some 181 libraries in the Tennessee Regional Library System, in 91 of the state&#8217;s 95 counties, received letters from the secretary of state in October calling for a full audit of the libraries&#8217; juvenile books to better align them with Trump administration standards on gender topics. The directive has caused [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>From The Tennessean:  \|\|\| Archived Version Some 181 libraries in the Tennessee Regional Library System, in 91 of the state’s 95 counties, received letters from the secretary of state in October calling for a full audit of the libraries’ juvenile books to better align them with Trump administration standards on gender topics. The directive has caused \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.infodocket.com/?p=167465</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Year in Review: 2025 in The Scholarly Kitchen</title>
      <link>https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/05/the-year-in-review-2025-in-the-scholarly-kitchen/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Before we plunge into 2026, a look back at 2025, a difficult year for many in the scholarly community.</p>
        <p>The post <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/05/the-year-in-review-2025-in-the-scholarly-kitchen/">The Year in Review: 2025 in The Scholarly Kitchen</a> appeared first on <a href="https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org">The Scholarly Kitchen</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Before we plunge into 2026, a look back at 2025, a difficult year for many in the scholarly community.

The post [The Year in Review: 2025 in The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/2026/01/05/the-year-in-review-2025-in-the-scholarly-kitchen/) appeared first on [The Scholarly Kitchen](https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://scholarlykitchen.sspnet.org/?p=61392</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
