<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:source="https://source.scripting.com/">
  <atom:link href="https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/retro_computing.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Retro Computing News</title>
    <link>https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/retro_computing.xml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>22 Nov 25 14:38 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.15</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/11/22 - Yikes!, Getting that Lidl pocket printer working with Linux, Befuddlement, The day the United States capitulated, Mental hiccup, Translating Mamie.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251122</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Yikes!, Getting that Lidl pocket printer working with Linux, Befuddlement, The day the United States capitulated, Mental hiccup, Translating Mamie.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Yikes!, Getting that Lidl pocket printer working with Linux, Befuddlement, The day the United States capitulated, Mental hiccup, Translating Mamie.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251122</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Live Coding with Gerph on Sunday</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2266.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[If you were intrigued by Gerph's Monday ROUGOL presentation, or just want to improve your coding skills, then you are in luck!]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>If you were intrigued by Gerph&#39;s Monday ROUGOL presentation, or just want to improve your coding skills, then you are in luck!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2266.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Debian Unleashes Debian Libre Live</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Debian-Unleashes-Debian-Libre-Live</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Debian Libre Live keeps your machine free of proprietary software.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Debian Libre Live keeps your machine free of proprietary software.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://393098dd4d7fb82e095f56e000b5f59d</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Mr Roberts Goes to Hollywood, Part 1: A Digital Anvil</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/11/mr-roberts-goes-to-hollywood-part-1-a-digital-anvil/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This article tells part of the story of Chris Roberts. What I&#8217;d really like to do is a game where you could travel from planet to planet &#8212; and there would be hundreds of planets &#8212; with full 3D action. You could go down and explore each planet in detail and interact with all sorts [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>This article tells part of the story of Chris Roberts. What I’d really like to do is a game where you could travel from planet to planet — and there would be hundreds of planets — with full 3D action. You could go down and explore each planet in detail and interact with all sorts \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.filfre.net/?p=6546</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Fireside developer chat on saturday night</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2265.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[It definitely feels like the bleak mid-winter. So why not have a cosy saturday night in. Throw another log on the file and join some very informal and friendly chat with other RISC OS developers online.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>It definitely feels like the bleak mid-winter. So why not have a cosy saturday night in. Throw another log on the file and join some very informal and friendly chat with other RISC OS developers online.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2265.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Episode IV - A New Hope</title>
      <link>https://www.riscosopen.org/news/articles/2025/11/20/episode-iv-a-new-hope</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Not only did 1977 see the release of space opera <a href="https://www.disneyplus.com/en-gb/welcome/star-wars">Star Wars &#8211; A New Hope</a>, but it was also a year famous for the release of Fortran 77, the follow up to Fortran IV and &#8217;66.</p>
        <h3>Your compliance is imperative</h3>
        <p>Fortran is one of a family of <em>imperative</em> programming languages, and was originally short for <b>For</b>mula <b>Tran</b>slation. Finding applications in scientific fields such as modelling of weather systems, molecular structure, and of course calculating star ship propulsion vectors.</p>
        <p><img src="/images/risc_os_open/xwing.jpg" title="Wireframe X-Wing" alt="Wireframe X-Wing" /><br />
        <small>Image available as wallpaper from <a href="https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1941346742">r33v01v3</a> via Steam</small></p>
        <p>As described in our <a href="/content/documents/dde-faq"><span class="caps">FAQ</span></a> the imperative languages are in the class of languages that the Norcroft compiler supports, and we&#8217;ve long known from odd scraps of evidence such as the <a href="http://www.computinghistory.org.uk/det/34486/Acorn-RISC-iX-User-Guide/"><span class="caps">RISC</span> iX User Guide</a> that there was a Fortran version at one time which went alongside the C language we&#8217;re so much more familiar with.</p>
        <p>With help from Codemist a search of their archives managed to locate a partial copy last worked on in the 1990s on a backup tape stowed inside an old R2-unit.</p>
        <p>Joining the Fortran front end &#8211; the part of the compiler which deals with language specifics &#8211; with the rest of the contemporary tools creates the <code>f77</code> compiler. In addition, a brand new 200+ page manual describes its use in detail, along with <span class="caps">ANSI</span> runtime library.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Not only did 1977 see the release of space opera [Star Wars – A New Hope](https://www.disneyplus.com/en-gb/welcome/star-wars), but it was also a year famous for the release of Fortran 77, the follow up to Fortran IV and ’66.

### Your compliance is imperative

Fortran is one of a family of _imperative_ programming languages, and was originally short for **For** mula **Tran** slation. Finding applications in scientific fields such as modelling of weather systems, molecular structure, and of course calculating star ship propulsion vectors.

![Wireframe X-Wing](/images/risc_os_open/xwing.jpg)

Image available as wallpaper from [r33v01v3](https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1941346742) via Steam

As described in our [FAQ](/content/documents/dde-faq) the imperative languages are in the class of languages that the Norcroft compiler supports, and we’ve long known from odd scraps of evidence such as the [RISC iX User Guide](http://www.computinghistory.org.uk/det/34486/Acorn-RISC-iX-User-Guide/) that there was a Fortran version at one time which went alongside the C language we’re so much more familiar with.

With help from Codemist a search of their archives managed to locate a partial copy last worked on in the 1990s on a backup tape stowed inside an old R2-unit.

Joining the Fortran front end – the part of the compiler which deals with language specifics – with the rest of the contemporary tools creates the `f77` compiler. In addition, a brand new 200+ page manual describes its use in detail, along with ANSI runtime library.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://urn:uuid:ae0fa91d-adb3-4c3e-a87d-f38464b3f4fd</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Announcing the TIB 2025 Advent Calendar</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2259.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[For the last 2 years, TIB has run an advent calender over the festive season. And we are looking to our readers to contribute again to make it 3 in a row....]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>For the last 2 years, TIB has run an advent calender over the festive season. And we are looking to our readers to contribute again to make it 3 in a row....</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2259.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/11/19 - Presentations of The London Show, Sheiny Spammy.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251119</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Presentations of The London Show, Sheiny Spammy.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Presentations of The London Show, Sheiny Spammy.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251119</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Valve Announces Pending Release of Steam Machine</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Valve-Announces-Pending-Release-of-Steam-Machine</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Shout it to the heavens: Steam Machine, powered by Linux, is set to arrive in 2026.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Shout it to the heavens: Steam Machine, powered by Linux, is set to arrive in 2026.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://d2ec275891364e48dbe7c96955583d02</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>November 2025 Rougol report - Gerph is back</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2262.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[It's been five years since Gerph last talked to ROUGOL so he was back with an update. And he's been busy&mdash;his presentation included 51 information-packed slides!]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>It&#39;s been five years since Gerph last talked to ROUGOL so he was back with an update. And he&#39;s been busy—his presentation included 51 information-packed slides!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2262.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rebecca Heineman has died</title>
      <link>https://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2025/11/rebecca-heineman-has-died.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA["Burger Becky" did a lot of great games, first at Interplay (Bard's Tale, Wasteland), then later at Logicware, where she and others did some great Mac ports including Jazz Jackrabbit and their Half-Life MacOS port which never actually saw the light of day, the infamous <a href="https://doomwiki.org/wiki/Doom_(3DO)">3DO port of Doom</a>, and of course the initial work on the <a href="/2021/02/the-quest-for-wolfenstein-3d-music-on.html">IIgs version of Wolfenstein 3D</a>. Naturally these are just the highlights that come to mind of <a href="https://www.mobygames.com/person/343/rebecca-ann-heineman/credits/">a very long tenure</a> in the computer gaming world. She was very complimentary of TenFourFox back in the day when I was still developing that, and I'd long hoped she would release Mac Half-Life <a href="https://github.com/Olde-Skuul/doom3do">like she did 3DO Doom</a> for the archivists to pick over. Sadly, word has come out that <a href="https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/legendary-game-designer-programmer-space-invaders-champion-and-lgbtq-trailblazer-rebecca-heineman-has-died/">she has finally succumbed</a> to some sort of aggressive form of pulmonary adenocarcinoma. It's not a good way to go, and I hope her last moments were at peace.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>&#34;Burger Becky&#34; did a lot of great games, first at Interplay (Bard&#39;s Tale, Wasteland), then later at Logicware, where she and others did some great Mac ports including Jazz Jackrabbit and their Half-Life MacOS port which never actually saw the light of day, the infamous [3DO port of Doom](https://doomwiki.org/wiki/Doom_(3DO)), and of course the initial work on the [IIgs version of Wolfenstein 3D](/2021/02/the-quest-for-wolfenstein-3d-music-on.html). Naturally these are just the highlights that come to mind of [a very long tenure](https://www.mobygames.com/person/343/rebecca-ann-heineman/credits/) in the computer gaming world. She was very complimentary of TenFourFox back in the day when I was still developing that, and I&#39;d long hoped she would release Mac Half-Life [like she did 3DO Doom](https://github.com/Olde-Skuul/doom3do) for the archivists to pick over. Sadly, word has come out that [she has finally succumbed](https://www.pcgamer.com/gaming-industry/legendary-game-designer-programmer-space-invaders-champion-and-lgbtq-trailblazer-rebecca-heineman-has-died/) to some sort of aggressive form of pulmonary adenocarcinoma. It&#39;s not a good way to go, and I hope her last moments were at peace.</source:markdown>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (ClassicHasClass)</author>
      <guid>cid://tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8349470052336612452.post-7874555800080284490</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday, ADMIN Magazine!</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Happy-Birthday-ADMIN-Magazine</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>ADMIN is celebrating its 15th anniversary with issue #90.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>ADMIN is celebrating its 15th anniversary with issue #90.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://25745f80bfae82f9ec734210e281038f</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Developers’ fireside chat – 22nd November</title>
      <link>https://www.riscository.com/2025/developers-fireside-chat-22nd-november/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The next friendly fireside chat for people interested in RISC OS software development will take place at 7:30pm on Saturday, 22nd November. Taking place online via the Zoom video conferencing service, these meetings are intended as an informal way of allowing RISC OS programmers, and anyone interested in the subject, to get together online to discuss relevant matters. There is no set agenda for these online meetings, and instead the discussion is steered by what people want to talk about. People are free to ask questions or bring up (and&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The next friendly fireside chat for people interested in RISC OS software development will take place at 7:30pm on Saturday, 22nd November. Taking place online via the Zoom video conferencing service, these meetings are intended as an informal way of allowing RISC OS programmers, and anyone interested in the subject, to get together online to discuss relevant matters. There is no set agenda for these online meetings, and instead the discussion is steered by what people want to talk about. People are free to ask questions or bring up (and…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.riscository.com/?p=10802</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Alternative Junior Monitor</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/alternative-junior-monitor/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Udo Juerss minimized the original monitor written by Alois Nachtmann by removing the socalled &#8220;assembler&#8221;. And added Intel Hex and MOS Technology papertape upload.. Furthermore some routines can be use in own programs like: TTY_INIT, TTY_PUTC, TTY_PUTS. Here an archive with the source, binary and documentation. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Udo Juerss minimized the original monitor written by Alois Nachtmann by removing the socalled “assembler”. And added Intel Hex and MOS Technology papertape upload.. Furthermore some routines can be use in own programs like: TTY\_INIT, TTY\_PUTC, TTY\_PUTS. Here an archive with the source, binary and documentation. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=19305</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>London Show 2025 talks are now online to watch</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2260.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The recordings of the talks at the recent London SHow are now available on youtube.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The recordings of the talks at the recent London SHow are now available on youtube.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2260.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>When UPS charged me a $684 tariff on $355 of vintage computer parts</title>
      <link>https://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2025/11/when-ups-charged-me-684-tariff-on-355.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjwphOIBJNMT4yciT93GgS2WSQvAfFKHKCLVbloburRMuqZzuT5jH02Xa28qTZ2TjrBs6LJP0Fi4WHx1sqRcyd3hmSt_x6a69UKFtYoMs4OGtOJ7r3nlOwiMFQLCqMFi_Rr_ObTgp3xcdzuX59DPWlD3ygjvaqkB3qykcX0Er3kIPh2nwp1X0j0K7jaUt4/s2912/upyourps.png" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" width="320" data-original-height="1586" data-original-width="2912" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjwphOIBJNMT4yciT93GgS2WSQvAfFKHKCLVbloburRMuqZzuT5jH02Xa28qTZ2TjrBs6LJP0Fi4WHx1sqRcyd3hmSt_x6a69UKFtYoMs4OGtOJ7r3nlOwiMFQLCqMFi_Rr_ObTgp3xcdzuX59DPWlD3ygjvaqkB3qykcX0Er3kIPh2nwp1X0j0K7jaUt4/s320/upyourps.png"/></a></div>
        
        I try not to write anything even vaguely political on this blog because we have a variety of views on a variety of subjects and no one is here for that. We can all enjoy our geriatric little silicon artifacts together regardless of your electoral persuasion. But I was hopping mad this week, and the reason is actually on-topic, because I got hit with US Customs tariffs close to double the cost of the vintage items I was ordering and more than the items were worth. This eventually got straightened out, but it wouldn't have happened without my complaint and some time on the phone.
        <p>
        <a name='more'></a>
        <p>
        Although we make regular trips down under, your humble author is based in California and so is the Floodgap computer lab. For newly manufactured items and parts it has generally been my policy to buy parts from United States sellers even prior to the tariffs, mostly because that gets around various irregularities and it arrives more quickly. If they're going to drop-ship then it's their problem, not mine, because they advertised it was already here. Since such items are typically newly produced, the current tariffs would logically apply and this policy thus has the additional benefit of me not having to deal with that directly: any tariff should already have been paid to get them States-side.
        <p>
        But for NOS and used parts, especially if you are a collector like I am for certain systems, you buy where you can find them. Coincidentally I wanted to buy a second Apple Network Server logic board since my ANS 700 is acting a little weird (don't say caps) and I still want a good spare for the ANS 500. These don't exactly grow on trees but, as it turns out, the seller I bought my current spare logic board from (pre-tariffs) had another in stock. The logic board doesn't come with the regular ANS AIX ROM SIMM nor cache, so we'll want one each of those just in case, and he also had an Apple BTO Twin Turbo video card (I believe originally for the Power Macintosh 9500) which might also be nice for one of the other beige PCI Macs. These are all new old stock items in their Apple Service packaging because obviously Apple hasn't made nor sold any of these parts in decades. Per the seller, they came from the teardown of new machines which Apple was unable to sell and got turned into official surplus new stock. The seller is in an European Union country, so we're not talking some shady Shenzhen shop operating off an alley liftgate. (I'm not naming the seller because none of this is his fault and I'm sure he'd not like to be contacted about this.)
        <p>
        The items came to &euro;296.00, about US$355 at the spot exchange rate, plus &euro;48.10 for UPS shipping. This would have been well-under the prior <i>de minimis</i> exemption even with the shipping rolled in. We had to do UPS because his particular country's postal service limits shipment value to the United States to US$100 due to the tariffs, causing him to spend a substantial amount of time at the UPS drop-off depot and on the paperwork, which was way more than he was required to do and I very much appreciate. For any import you need to come up with a Harmonized System code for what you're shipping, which then maps to a Harmonized Tariff Schedule code specific to the United States. These parts are all populated PCBs and most populated boards are, by prior rulings, classified with <a href="https://rulings.cbp.gov/search?term=8473.30">an HTS code of 8473.30</a>, which is what the seller tagged all four items with. This code is for "Parts and accessories of the machines of heading 8471 [Automatic data processing machines and units thereof]." If you look under the Harmonized Tariff Schedule search engine for this code, you <a href="https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=847330">find a duty rate</a> for certain subheadings that at <em>most</em> would be 35 percent, or even if these were products of the People's Republic of China (they're old enough that I don't know their exact provenance, but I have no evidence to believe these were originally), then maybe, maybe, <em>maybe</em> <a href="https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=99038803">an additional 25 percent</a>. The declared value was the purchase price in euros and he even picked up the insurance. The package left the depot uneventfully and worked its way across the continent.
        <p>
        The first sign of trouble was over the weekend when I got an unexpected message.
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiRO6uX353u4XAiNm_52JHxvDYCsY9pjQuaDpUZLmoEEOD_y5WuSK4DiZlsnwZsktqT8Uh51jWcycpNaTbVTsK0651qPy26Lyal3BEx0Se0cVXkcq8c24iOTAev5yUCP0DgCIUVhyG_DY2f5Yv5b_BgxJhmLfNO9rOzkbS568n6LDX6TmC2Y6TZLaiL5z8/s1702/upyourups-2.png" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" height="320" data-original-height="1702" data-original-width="1668" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiRO6uX353u4XAiNm_52JHxvDYCsY9pjQuaDpUZLmoEEOD_y5WuSK4DiZlsnwZsktqT8Uh51jWcycpNaTbVTsK0651qPy26Lyal3BEx0Se0cVXkcq8c24iOTAev5yUCP0DgCIUVhyG_DY2f5Yv5b_BgxJhmLfNO9rOzkbS568n6LDX6TmC2Y6TZLaiL5z8/s320/upyourups-2.png"/></a></div>
        
        The UPS shipping agent had indicated the parcel was subject to <a href="https://www.cbp.gov/trade/programs-administration/entry-summary/232-tariffs-aluminum-and-steel-faqs">Section 232 tariffs</a> on steel and aluminum, which required me to fill out a UPS-specific form attesting to the steel and aluminum content of the package. (This is an important distinction because Section 232 is not currently part of <a href="https://www.supremecourt.gov/oral_arguments/argument_transcripts/2025/24-1287_097c.pdf">the present matter before the U.S. Supreme Court</a> (PDF), only <a href="https://www.swlaw.com/publication/what-if-the-supreme-court-overrules-the-reciprocal-tariffs-plan-now-for-refunds-protests-and-contract-reconciliation/">reciprocal tariffs under the IEEPA</a>.) There should be little or no aluminum in these because the board and traces would be copper. However, a PCI card is probably going to have a steel bracket, so I looked at the typical mass for those and picked a sufficiently high number of 149g, almost certainly an overestimate but that's always safest with this stuff, then looked at the spot price of stainless steel and based on that weight computed a steel content value of $0.48. I marked "not applicable" for everything else and sent it back. They accepted that.
        <p>
        In the background, all this goes into a U.S. Customs and Border Protection Form 7501, also known as an Entry Summary. It is important to realize that in this circumstance, with UPS as the broker, you are <em>not</em> actually the importer of record &mdash; they are. You are the "ultimate consignee." Based on the information provided and the judgement of the broker's agent, then a tariff is assigned and added to the paperwork, which is "assessed" by CBP but in practice is being assessed by the broker based on what they expect CBP would charge under current regulation. Ordinarily you don't see this form. CBP does spot-check these but the majority just go through. Since UPS is the importer in this situation, they also pay the tariff they computed "in advance" to clear customs, and then they charge you for that plus their broker fee.
        <p>
        It took several more days for the actual tariff bill to arrive, which was early Monday morning. Now, the initial E-mail said this:
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhz3mJRRRVpyOUdo0bPPC4ZPIgHYDTaBL9yvPapat_CUPHIHJL1DjG1nbiLWRsu3tnHK6Ar3gLDc5u0AIHjyaPcDk5epS-Ojwmlnft8i2A5SXZDuZ5cIA0VRt-kQy4-YsGqMJDFxpYdXDUVXTW-OIxp2Mx0UTt10ynbVgt0cwPXPuauiIWx2Cez8mQLt4c/s1804/upyourups-3.png" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" height="320" data-original-height="1804" data-original-width="1668" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhz3mJRRRVpyOUdo0bPPC4ZPIgHYDTaBL9yvPapat_CUPHIHJL1DjG1nbiLWRsu3tnHK6Ar3gLDc5u0AIHjyaPcDk5epS-Ojwmlnft8i2A5SXZDuZ5cIA0VRt-kQy4-YsGqMJDFxpYdXDUVXTW-OIxp2Mx0UTt10ynbVgt0cwPXPuauiIWx2Cez8mQLt4c/s320/upyourups-3.png"/></a></div>
        
        Yes, the initial bill was for US$711. When I logged in, however, it gave me a total of $698 because it hadn't yet been delivered, which included a $14 brokerage fee.
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh4IQTh6fo1ImSoo2TL8H7pDwB4OtcnDAwlo4mlZwBVkjlYai32RuU-nF6cDioi_kuIsbFLZSeM9cyvJKPHZREcvfp3WsXhIbVMx5xqS80DvjPCibAViqcq635sv_Eh-CkzLulfQXRCnfMCCZnuxkAuM87tumEaJMoREgPPokLnzoZIB8GqTOKM98yCTU0/s2906/upyourups-4.png" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" width="320" data-original-height="1201" data-original-width="2906" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh4IQTh6fo1ImSoo2TL8H7pDwB4OtcnDAwlo4mlZwBVkjlYai32RuU-nF6cDioi_kuIsbFLZSeM9cyvJKPHZREcvfp3WsXhIbVMx5xqS80DvjPCibAViqcq635sv_Eh-CkzLulfQXRCnfMCCZnuxkAuM87tumEaJMoREgPPokLnzoZIB8GqTOKM98yCTU0/s320/upyourups-4.png"/></a></div>
        
        Time was of the essence, however, because it was arriving <em>that day</em>. I was absolutely incandescent to have to do it, but I paid the entire charge in full on the spot, and this is <em>the correct thing to do.</em> The last thing you want is for your package to get redirected to a warehouse pending your payment, because any shipper will start tacking on storage fees and they have no incentive to get it out of storage quickly. For UPS, a direct quote from their own agents, "Warehouse charges will be added on shipments that are held in our warehouse over two business days at a rate of $20.00 per day and $0.04 per pound. ... On the 15th day, all shipments will be eligible for General Order warehousing by U.S. Customs. Any shipment moved to a G.O. warehouse will be assigned additional warehouse fees over and above any UPS warehouse fees. If imposed, these fees must be paid in full before the shipment can be removed." Obviously I wanted no part of that.
        <p>
        After I had been advised by the system the package would be delivered as scheduled, I then relentlessly abused the AI chatbot on UPS' home page until it asked for my phone number and I got a callback into their phone support line. The first person on the line advised me they didn't handle tariffs and transferred me to another department, after which I spent (not an exaggeration) 45 minutes on hold until it was answered. This new agent said that this was dealt with through a specific subgroup on the UPS post entry team that didn't do anything by phone. (These brokerage teams generally operate out of the Kentucky UPS Worldport hub at Louisville Muhammad Ali International Airport, formerly Standiford Field, hence its IATA code of SDF that also turns up in UPS documentation.) He gave me an E-mail address that looked like line noise but I confirmed it twice with him and also that I had to put the tracking number into the subject line with the magic words "Disputing Duties and Custom Charges." I indicated in the message the fees were paid but that I believed they were unreasonable and incorrect, and also pointed out I submitted the Section 232 paperwork when requested.
        <p>
        It took a day to get a reply, then came the United States Veterans' Day holiday, and finally I heard back yesterday from a second agent that they had "corrected this shipment." What they had done was file an amended Form 7501 and this 7501 they actually sent me so I could see the results. The declared value was changed to US$342 (I presume a difference in the spot exchange rate at the time of filing) and now it had two HTSUS numbers. The entire $342 was attributed to <a href="https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=8473.30.2000">8473.30.2000</a>, a slightly different code for "Parts and accessories, including face plates and lock latches, of printed circuit assemblies" which might be referring to the bracket I declared in the Section 232 form. There was no tariff on this ("FREE"). However, a second code <a href="https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=99030220">9903.02.20</a> was added, a long-winded way of saying a tariff (in this case 15%) on "articles the product of the European Union." This was $51.30 and the final tariff.
        <p>
        Everything arrived safely, by the way, and in excellent condition (though I cracked open the antistatic bag on the ANS board to take off the Maxell battery which Apple always shipped logic boards with back then). However, I would like to point out for the sake of accuracy that the ANS logic board, ROM SIMM and cache DIMM have no country of origin printed on them. Only the Twin Turbo card does, and it says ...
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh7B2-6rjm9Xk610XOOuYNQb9w-E7i8E4IEyDwbzjj5hEdHvioIl9jot8cL6rwI-f8H8h4XsBrBUOoT5LGbSTuNMpZ8WdX2H7MIsrRxAID_aZD-Rf2ohHp3R5o7vbP0rxGVV28zWsAJHZqs23TkukVgNY7GwM18cdqAnEFIjp_8K86vCQ2KxcdHhFiX-TY/s4080/PXL_20251115_231859295~2.jpg" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" width="320" data-original-height="3072" data-original-width="4080" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh7B2-6rjm9Xk610XOOuYNQb9w-E7i8E4IEyDwbzjj5hEdHvioIl9jot8cL6rwI-f8H8h4XsBrBUOoT5LGbSTuNMpZ8WdX2H7MIsrRxAID_aZD-Rf2ohHp3R5o7vbP0rxGVV28zWsAJHZqs23TkukVgNY7GwM18cdqAnEFIjp_8K86vCQ2KxcdHhFiX-TY/s320/PXL_20251115_231859295~2.jpg"/></a></div>
        
        .. but since it wasn't the major part of the order it seemed like I'd be wasting even more time over ten or fifteen bucks to appeal this too. Your mileage and motivation may vary.
        <p>
        Now that UPS was into me for $632.70, the revising agent said, "Any difference between the amount paid and the amount now reflected will be auto-refunded to you. Most of the time, this is done by check sent to the billing address, you can expect this between 2-6 weeks." They didn't say when they don't use a check (I paid with a credit card), but they did give me a phone number for accounting, which I'll call if UPS fails to pay back this particular interest-free loan.
        <p>
        So that's the sordid tale. Even though UPS (mostly) made this right, I'm still unhappy with them for screwing up so badly in the first place because I'm out the money until they get around to reimbursing me. You'd think someone would have noticed that a thumping big duty like that seemed a little weird for a transaction of this size and maybe called a supervisor or something. The fact it could be so promptly appealed &mdash; and reversed in a few days, something that hardly ever happens with the federal government &mdash; pretty much demonstrates it was their call to ding it for that much in duty in the first place. I'm also unhappy with them for only alerting me to the final cost of the tariff when the shipment was inbound and due for delivery instead of earlier when it was assessed, because they have you over a barrel at that point unless you want to take your chances with their brokerage warehouse. This obviously nets them more money with the people who won't pay up immediately, but it's undeniably pretty bad customer service. Unfortunately, my unscientific survey of reports in the UPS Reddit indicate I am far from the only person to get a disproportionate assessment of this type.
        <p>
        Regardless, if this happens to you &mdash; whether it's FedEx or DHL or UPS or whatever &mdash; <em>pay it</em> and <em>then</em> appeal it. Don't let your shipment go to a warehouse and don't bounce it back to the sender; since odds are the shipper (because they are likely the importer of record) has already paid the duty, they're going to want their money back and you'll be out the money <em>and</em> the items. But, by golly, appeal it: just because you might agree with it politically doesn't mean they did it right.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjwphOIBJNMT4yciT93GgS2WSQvAfFKHKCLVbloburRMuqZzuT5jH02Xa28qTZ2TjrBs6LJP0Fi4WHx1sqRcyd3hmSt_x6a69UKFtYoMs4OGtOJ7r3nlOwiMFQLCqMFi_Rr_ObTgp3xcdzuX59DPWlD3ygjvaqkB3qykcX0Er3kIPh2nwp1X0j0K7jaUt4/s320/upyourps.png)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEjwphOIBJNMT4yciT93GgS2WSQvAfFKHKCLVbloburRMuqZzuT5jH02Xa28qTZ2TjrBs6LJP0Fi4WHx1sqRcyd3hmSt_x6a69UKFtYoMs4OGtOJ7r3nlOwiMFQLCqMFi_Rr_ObTgp3xcdzuX59DPWlD3ygjvaqkB3qykcX0Er3kIPh2nwp1X0j0K7jaUt4/s2912/upyourps.png)

I try not to write anything even vaguely political on this blog because we have a variety of views on a variety of subjects and no one is here for that. We can all enjoy our geriatric little silicon artifacts together regardless of your electoral persuasion. But I was hopping mad this week, and the reason is actually on-topic, because I got hit with US Customs tariffs close to double the cost of the vintage items I was ordering and more than the items were worth. This eventually got straightened out, but it wouldn&#39;t have happened without my complaint and some time on the phone.

Although we make regular trips down under, your humble author is based in California and so is the Floodgap computer lab. For newly manufactured items and parts it has generally been my policy to buy parts from United States sellers even prior to the tariffs, mostly because that gets around various irregularities and it arrives more quickly. If they&#39;re going to drop-ship then it&#39;s their problem, not mine, because they advertised it was already here. Since such items are typically newly produced, the current tariffs would logically apply and this policy thus has the additional benefit of me not having to deal with that directly: any tariff should already have been paid to get them States-side.

But for NOS and used parts, especially if you are a collector like I am for certain systems, you buy where you can find them. Coincidentally I wanted to buy a second Apple Network Server logic board since my ANS 700 is acting a little weird (don&#39;t say caps) and I still want a good spare for the ANS 500. These don&#39;t exactly grow on trees but, as it turns out, the seller I bought my current spare logic board from (pre-tariffs) had another in stock. The logic board doesn&#39;t come with the regular ANS AIX ROM SIMM nor cache, so we&#39;ll want one each of those just in case, and he also had an Apple BTO Twin Turbo video card (I believe originally for the Power Macintosh 9500) which might also be nice for one of the other beige PCI Macs. These are all new old stock items in their Apple Service packaging because obviously Apple hasn&#39;t made nor sold any of these parts in decades. Per the seller, they came from the teardown of new machines which Apple was unable to sell and got turned into official surplus new stock. The seller is in an European Union country, so we&#39;re not talking some shady Shenzhen shop operating off an alley liftgate. (I&#39;m not naming the seller because none of this is his fault and I&#39;m sure he&#39;d not like to be contacted about this.)

The items came to €296.00, about US$355 at the spot exchange rate, plus €48.10 for UPS shipping. This would have been well-under the prior _de minimis_ exemption even with the shipping rolled in. We had to do UPS because his particular country&#39;s postal service limits shipment value to the United States to US$100 due to the tariffs, causing him to spend a substantial amount of time at the UPS drop-off depot and on the paperwork, which was way more than he was required to do and I very much appreciate. For any import you need to come up with a Harmonized System code for what you&#39;re shipping, which then maps to a Harmonized Tariff Schedule code specific to the United States. These parts are all populated PCBs and most populated boards are, by prior rulings, classified with [an HTS code of 8473.30](https://rulings.cbp.gov/search?term=8473.30), which is what the seller tagged all four items with. This code is for &#34;Parts and accessories of the machines of heading 8471 \[Automatic data processing machines and units thereof\].&#34; If you look under the Harmonized Tariff Schedule search engine for this code, you [find a duty rate](https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=847330) for certain subheadings that at _most_ would be 35 percent, or even if these were products of the People&#39;s Republic of China (they&#39;re old enough that I don&#39;t know their exact provenance, but I have no evidence to believe these were originally), then maybe, maybe, _maybe_ [an additional 25 percent](https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=99038803). The declared value was the purchase price in euros and he even picked up the insurance. The package left the depot uneventfully and worked its way across the continent.

The first sign of trouble was over the weekend when I got an unexpected message.

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiRO6uX353u4XAiNm_52JHxvDYCsY9pjQuaDpUZLmoEEOD_y5WuSK4DiZlsnwZsktqT8Uh51jWcycpNaTbVTsK0651qPy26Lyal3BEx0Se0cVXkcq8c24iOTAev5yUCP0DgCIUVhyG_DY2f5Yv5b_BgxJhmLfNO9rOzkbS568n6LDX6TmC2Y6TZLaiL5z8/s320/upyourups-2.png)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiRO6uX353u4XAiNm_52JHxvDYCsY9pjQuaDpUZLmoEEOD_y5WuSK4DiZlsnwZsktqT8Uh51jWcycpNaTbVTsK0651qPy26Lyal3BEx0Se0cVXkcq8c24iOTAev5yUCP0DgCIUVhyG_DY2f5Yv5b_BgxJhmLfNO9rOzkbS568n6LDX6TmC2Y6TZLaiL5z8/s1702/upyourups-2.png)

The UPS shipping agent had indicated the parcel was subject to [Section 232 tariffs](https://www.cbp.gov/trade/programs-administration/entry-summary/232-tariffs-aluminum-and-steel-faqs) on steel and aluminum, which required me to fill out a UPS-specific form attesting to the steel and aluminum content of the package. (This is an important distinction because Section 232 is not currently part of [the present matter before the U.S. Supreme Court](https://www.supremecourt.gov/oral_arguments/argument_transcripts/2025/24-1287_097c.pdf) (PDF), only [reciprocal tariffs under the IEEPA](https://www.swlaw.com/publication/what-if-the-supreme-court-overrules-the-reciprocal-tariffs-plan-now-for-refunds-protests-and-contract-reconciliation/).) There should be little or no aluminum in these because the board and traces would be copper. However, a PCI card is probably going to have a steel bracket, so I looked at the typical mass for those and picked a sufficiently high number of 149g, almost certainly an overestimate but that&#39;s always safest with this stuff, then looked at the spot price of stainless steel and based on that weight computed a steel content value of $0.48. I marked &#34;not applicable&#34; for everything else and sent it back. They accepted that.

In the background, all this goes into a U.S. Customs and Border Protection Form 7501, also known as an Entry Summary. It is important to realize that in this circumstance, with UPS as the broker, you are _not_ actually the importer of record — they are. You are the &#34;ultimate consignee.&#34; Based on the information provided and the judgement of the broker&#39;s agent, then a tariff is assigned and added to the paperwork, which is &#34;assessed&#34; by CBP but in practice is being assessed by the broker based on what they expect CBP would charge under current regulation. Ordinarily you don&#39;t see this form. CBP does spot-check these but the majority just go through. Since UPS is the importer in this situation, they also pay the tariff they computed &#34;in advance&#34; to clear customs, and then they charge you for that plus their broker fee.

It took several more days for the actual tariff bill to arrive, which was early Monday morning. Now, the initial E-mail said this:

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhz3mJRRRVpyOUdo0bPPC4ZPIgHYDTaBL9yvPapat_CUPHIHJL1DjG1nbiLWRsu3tnHK6Ar3gLDc5u0AIHjyaPcDk5epS-Ojwmlnft8i2A5SXZDuZ5cIA0VRt-kQy4-YsGqMJDFxpYdXDUVXTW-OIxp2Mx0UTt10ynbVgt0cwPXPuauiIWx2Cez8mQLt4c/s320/upyourups-3.png)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhz3mJRRRVpyOUdo0bPPC4ZPIgHYDTaBL9yvPapat_CUPHIHJL1DjG1nbiLWRsu3tnHK6Ar3gLDc5u0AIHjyaPcDk5epS-Ojwmlnft8i2A5SXZDuZ5cIA0VRt-kQy4-YsGqMJDFxpYdXDUVXTW-OIxp2Mx0UTt10ynbVgt0cwPXPuauiIWx2Cez8mQLt4c/s1804/upyourups-3.png)

Yes, the initial bill was for US$711. When I logged in, however, it gave me a total of $698 because it hadn&#39;t yet been delivered, which included a $14 brokerage fee.

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh4IQTh6fo1ImSoo2TL8H7pDwB4OtcnDAwlo4mlZwBVkjlYai32RuU-nF6cDioi_kuIsbFLZSeM9cyvJKPHZREcvfp3WsXhIbVMx5xqS80DvjPCibAViqcq635sv_Eh-CkzLulfQXRCnfMCCZnuxkAuM87tumEaJMoREgPPokLnzoZIB8GqTOKM98yCTU0/s320/upyourups-4.png)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh4IQTh6fo1ImSoo2TL8H7pDwB4OtcnDAwlo4mlZwBVkjlYai32RuU-nF6cDioi_kuIsbFLZSeM9cyvJKPHZREcvfp3WsXhIbVMx5xqS80DvjPCibAViqcq635sv_Eh-CkzLulfQXRCnfMCCZnuxkAuM87tumEaJMoREgPPokLnzoZIB8GqTOKM98yCTU0/s2906/upyourups-4.png)

Time was of the essence, however, because it was arriving _that day_. I was absolutely incandescent to have to do it, but I paid the entire charge in full on the spot, and this is _the correct thing to do._ The last thing you want is for your package to get redirected to a warehouse pending your payment, because any shipper will start tacking on storage fees and they have no incentive to get it out of storage quickly. For UPS, a direct quote from their own agents, &#34;Warehouse charges will be added on shipments that are held in our warehouse over two business days at a rate of $20.00 per day and $0.04 per pound. ... On the 15th day, all shipments will be eligible for General Order warehousing by U.S. Customs. Any shipment moved to a G.O. warehouse will be assigned additional warehouse fees over and above any UPS warehouse fees. If imposed, these fees must be paid in full before the shipment can be removed.&#34; Obviously I wanted no part of that.

After I had been advised by the system the package would be delivered as scheduled, I then relentlessly abused the AI chatbot on UPS&#39; home page until it asked for my phone number and I got a callback into their phone support line. The first person on the line advised me they didn&#39;t handle tariffs and transferred me to another department, after which I spent (not an exaggeration) 45 minutes on hold until it was answered. This new agent said that this was dealt with through a specific subgroup on the UPS post entry team that didn&#39;t do anything by phone. (These brokerage teams generally operate out of the Kentucky UPS Worldport hub at Louisville Muhammad Ali International Airport, formerly Standiford Field, hence its IATA code of SDF that also turns up in UPS documentation.) He gave me an E-mail address that looked like line noise but I confirmed it twice with him and also that I had to put the tracking number into the subject line with the magic words &#34;Disputing Duties and Custom Charges.&#34; I indicated in the message the fees were paid but that I believed they were unreasonable and incorrect, and also pointed out I submitted the Section 232 paperwork when requested.

It took a day to get a reply, then came the United States Veterans&#39; Day holiday, and finally I heard back yesterday from a second agent that they had &#34;corrected this shipment.&#34; What they had done was file an amended Form 7501 and this 7501 they actually sent me so I could see the results. The declared value was changed to US$342 (I presume a difference in the spot exchange rate at the time of filing) and now it had two HTSUS numbers. The entire $342 was attributed to [8473.30.2000](https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=8473.30.2000), a slightly different code for &#34;Parts and accessories, including face plates and lock latches, of printed circuit assemblies&#34; which might be referring to the bracket I declared in the Section 232 form. There was no tariff on this (&#34;FREE&#34;). However, a second code [9903.02.20](https://hts.usitc.gov/search?query=99030220) was added, a long-winded way of saying a tariff (in this case 15%) on &#34;articles the product of the European Union.&#34; This was $51.30 and the final tariff.

Everything arrived safely, by the way, and in excellent condition (though I cracked open the antistatic bag on the ANS board to take off the Maxell battery which Apple always shipped logic boards with back then). However, I would like to point out for the sake of accuracy that the ANS logic board, ROM SIMM and cache DIMM have no country of origin printed on them. Only the Twin Turbo card does, and it says ...

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh7B2-6rjm9Xk610XOOuYNQb9w-E7i8E4IEyDwbzjj5hEdHvioIl9jot8cL6rwI-f8H8h4XsBrBUOoT5LGbSTuNMpZ8WdX2H7MIsrRxAID_aZD-Rf2ohHp3R5o7vbP0rxGVV28zWsAJHZqs23TkukVgNY7GwM18cdqAnEFIjp_8K86vCQ2KxcdHhFiX-TY/s320/PXL_20251115_231859295~2.jpg)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEh7B2-6rjm9Xk610XOOuYNQb9w-E7i8E4IEyDwbzjj5hEdHvioIl9jot8cL6rwI-f8H8h4XsBrBUOoT5LGbSTuNMpZ8WdX2H7MIsrRxAID_aZD-Rf2ohHp3R5o7vbP0rxGVV28zWsAJHZqs23TkukVgNY7GwM18cdqAnEFIjp_8K86vCQ2KxcdHhFiX-TY/s4080/PXL_20251115_231859295~2.jpg)

.. but since it wasn&#39;t the major part of the order it seemed like I&#39;d be wasting even more time over ten or fifteen bucks to appeal this too. Your mileage and motivation may vary.

Now that UPS was into me for $632.70, the revising agent said, &#34;Any difference between the amount paid and the amount now reflected will be auto-refunded to you. Most of the time, this is done by check sent to the billing address, you can expect this between 2-6 weeks.&#34; They didn&#39;t say when they don&#39;t use a check (I paid with a credit card), but they did give me a phone number for accounting, which I&#39;ll call if UPS fails to pay back this particular interest-free loan.

So that&#39;s the sordid tale. Even though UPS (mostly) made this right, I&#39;m still unhappy with them for screwing up so badly in the first place because I&#39;m out the money until they get around to reimbursing me. You&#39;d think someone would have noticed that a thumping big duty like that seemed a little weird for a transaction of this size and maybe called a supervisor or something. The fact it could be so promptly appealed — and reversed in a few days, something that hardly ever happens with the federal government — pretty much demonstrates it was their call to ding it for that much in duty in the first place. I&#39;m also unhappy with them for only alerting me to the final cost of the tariff when the shipment was inbound and due for delivery instead of earlier when it was assessed, because they have you over a barrel at that point unless you want to take your chances with their brokerage warehouse. This obviously nets them more money with the people who won&#39;t pay up immediately, but it&#39;s undeniably pretty bad customer service. Unfortunately, my unscientific survey of reports in the UPS Reddit indicate I am far from the only person to get a disproportionate assessment of this type.

Regardless, if this happens to you — whether it&#39;s FedEx or DHL or UPS or whatever — _pay it_ and _then_ appeal it. Don&#39;t let your shipment go to a warehouse and don&#39;t bounce it back to the sender; since odds are the shipper (because they are likely the importer of record) has already paid the duty, they&#39;re going to want their money back and you&#39;ll be out the money _and_ the items. But, by golly, appeal it: just because you might agree with it politically doesn&#39;t mean they did it right.</source:markdown>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (ClassicHasClass)</author>
      <guid>cid://tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8349470052336612452.post-5082726271334179629</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Pyromaniac Evolution at ROUGOL – 17th November</title>
      <link>https://www.riscository.com/2025/pyromaniac-evolution-rougol-17th-november/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Your next opportunity to attend a RISC OS User Group of London (ROUGOL) meeting is Monday, 17th November, where Gerph will be discussing the evolution of RISC OS Pyromaniac. If you don&#8217;t already know, RISC OS Pyromaniac is an online resource developed by Gerph that provides a semi-hosted re-implementation of RISC OS, capable of running 32-bit programs with a focus on testing software. Gerph first talked about the system to ROUGOL five years ago this month, with the last follow-up talk four years ago &#8211; and if you want to&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Your next opportunity to attend a RISC OS User Group of London (ROUGOL) meeting is Monday, 17th November, where Gerph will be discussing the evolution of RISC OS Pyromaniac. If you don’t already know, RISC OS Pyromaniac is an online resource developed by Gerph that provides a semi-hosted re-implementation of RISC OS, capable of running 32-bit programs with a focus on testing software. Gerph first talked about the system to ROUGOL five years ago this month, with the last follow-up talk four years ago – and if you want to…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.riscository.com/?p=10798</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Theatre talks from the London Show now on YouTube</title>
      <link>https://www.riscository.com/2025/london-2025-theatre-talks/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The RISC OS London Show, which took place a few short weeks ago, maintained the usual format &#8211; a main hall where the exhibitors had their stands, and a show theatre for a selection of exhibitors to deliver short talks. If you couldn&#8217;t attend the talks on the day &#8211; or the show itself (shame on you, unless you have a good excuse) &#8211; you can now watch them online thanks to the recording and editing efforts of Leo White. If you want to watch them all in one long&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The RISC OS London Show, which took place a few short weeks ago, maintained the usual format – a main hall where the exhibitors had their stands, and a show theatre for a selection of exhibitors to deliver short talks. If you couldn’t attend the talks on the day – or the show itself (shame on you, unless you have a good excuse) – you can now watch them online thanks to the recording and editing efforts of Leo White. If you want to watch them all in one long…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.riscository.com/?p=10796</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rockwell AIM 65 additions</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/rockwell-aim-65-additions/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Rockwell pages on AIM 65 have had some updates. There is a new page on AIM 65 hardware produced by others, like video cards, dataloggers and more. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 needs 2 edge connectors. The specifications are: card edge; PIN: 44; 3.96mm When you search for those, ...Magazines: [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The Rockwell pages on AIM 65 have had some updates. There is a new page on AIM 65 hardware produced by others, like video cards, dataloggers and more. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 needs 2 edge connectors. The specifications are: card edge; PIN: 44; 3.96mm When you search for those, ...Magazines: \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=19276</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This Week on The Analog Antiquarian</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/11/this-week-on-the-analog-antiquarian/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Chapter 7: The Changing of the Guard]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Chapter 7: The Changing of the Guard</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.filfre.net/?p=6566</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rougol November 2025 meeting on monday - Pyromaniac update</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2256.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The November 2025 Rougol meeting is on Monday and features Gerph.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The November 2025 Rougol meeting is on Monday and features Gerph.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2256.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Another Linux Malware Discovered</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Another-Linux-Malware-Discovered</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Russian hackers use Hyper-V to hide malware within Linux virtual machines.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Russian hackers use Hyper-V to hide malware within Linux virtual machines.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://4c3f260aa524e48feae1a56184244391</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>KIM-1 Simulator 1.5.4 published</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/kim-1-simulator-1-5-4-published/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A fresh version of the simulator. New functionality 1. The audio tape routines interception can be switched off and on in settings. So no more popups if browsing in the -003 ROM 2. The console window stays open untouched when the LED display is chosen. When switched back to the LED display, the LED lights [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>A fresh version of the simulator. New functionality 1. The audio tape routines interception can be switched off and on in settings. So no more popups if browsing in the -003 ROM 2. The console window stays open untouched when the LED display is chosen. When switched back to the LED display, the LED lights \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=19183</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Moving back to Linux RPCEmu on my Mac</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2244.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I am a big fan of RPCEmu which provides an excellent RISC OS environment on my Mac when I am travelling. In this post I am going to explore why I have switched back to the Linux version and cover some of the issues I encountered.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>I am a big fan of RPCEmu which provides an excellent RISC OS environment on my Mac when I am travelling. In this post I am going to explore why I have switched back to the Linux version and cover some of the issues I encountered.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2244.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>TUXEDO Computers Announces a New InfinityBook</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/TUXEDO-Computers-Announces-a-New-InfinityBook</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>TUXEDO Computers is at it again with a new InfinityBook that will meet your professional and gaming needs.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>TUXEDO Computers is at it again with a new InfinityBook that will meet your professional and gaming needs.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://a1083e23bf144d54e63b8fcc5187afcc</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/11/10 - It works!</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251110</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[It works!]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>It works!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251110</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/11/09 - What a difference a day can make!, More bad English, Time changes everything.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251109</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[What a difference a day can make!, More bad English, Time changes everything.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>What a difference a day can make!, More bad English, Time changes everything.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251109</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>UltimaVM: Update 2025-11-08 – More features added to Ultima – Function pointers, Code sections and more</title>
      <link>https://paolozaino.wordpress.com/2025/11/09/ultimavm-update-2025-11-08-more-features-added-to-ultima-function-pointers-code-sections-and-more/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Given the interest Ultima has been receiving from enthusiasts and engineers, both online and at the few computer shows where I’ve demonstrated it, I think some will appreciate a more detailed look at its ongoing progress. So here’s the first of these updates. Intro If you’re new to Ultima or UltimaVM, you can find an [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Given the interest Ultima has been receiving from enthusiasts and engineers, both online and at the few computer shows where I’ve demonstrated it, I think some will appreciate a more detailed look at its ongoing progress. So here’s the first of these updates. Intro If you’re new to Ultima or UltimaVM, you can find an \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://paolozaino.wordpress.com/?p=9756</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How to Brew Solar Powered Coffee</title>
      <link>https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/solar-powered-coffee-maker-intro-image_dithered.png" alt='Image: The solar powered coffee maker that we build in this manual. Photo by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: The solar powered coffee maker that we build in this manual. Photo by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>There are many different methods for making coffee, some more energy-efficient than others. However, there are no coffee makers that you can power with a small solar PV panel. For example, a commercially available 12V DC drip coffee maker requires a solar panel of 300 watts to brew coffee and keep it warm.</p>
        <p>The key to making a more energy-efficient coffee maker is insulation. Regardless of which conventional coffee maker you purchase, it will typically have little to no heat insulation, and most of the heat generated by the energy source will be wasted into the environment. Therefore, we made an insulated solar electric coffee maker ourselves.</p>
        <p>Our coffee maker operates on the same principles as our <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-a-solar-powered-electric-oven/">solar-powered oven</a> and runs on a 100W solar panel. We embedded an Italian coffee maker—a moka pot—in a mortar slab, surrounded by cork insulation and a layer of ceramic tiles.</p>
        <blockquote>
        <p>We embedded an Italian coffee maker—a moka pot—in a mortar slab, surrounded by cork insulation and a layer of ceramic tiles.</p>
        </blockquote>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_0104_dithered.png" alt='Image: Connecting the coffee maker to a solar panel. Photo by Hugo Lopez.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Connecting the coffee maker to a solar panel. Photo by Hugo Lopez. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <div class="article-img  vertical">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/coffee-pot-inside_dithered.png" alt='Image: Cross-section of the coffee maker. 1. Tiles, 2. Cork, 3. Mortar. Illustration by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Cross-section of the coffee maker. 1. Tiles, 2. Cork, 3. Mortar. Illustration by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>The cooker has an <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-an-electric-heating-element-from-scratch/">electric resistance heating element</a> integrated inside, which is directly connected to the solar panel without a battery, solar charge controller, or voltage regulator in between. Although it&rsquo;s solar-powered, the coffee maker can be located inside your kitchen or next to your bed—only the solar panel needs to be outside.</p>
        <blockquote>
        <p>Although it’s solar-powered, the coffee maker can be located inside your kitchen or next to your bed—only the solar panel needs to be outside.</p>
        </blockquote>
        <p>The moka pot was invented in 1933 and uses pressure rather than gravity or a pump to brew coffee. It consists of a bottom chamber (a boiler that acts as a base), a funnel filter with a plate and a rubber joint, and an upper chamber where the coffee is collected. Just before the water boils, the steam increases the pressure inside the heating vessel, pushing the water through the filter and the ground coffee. The moka pot is an energy-efficient appliance, comparable to a pressure cooker for food.</p>
        <h2 id="how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee">How to brew solar-powered coffee</h2>
        <p>Once the solar panel receives sunlight in the morning, the coffee maker will start heating up. Consequently, if you put water and coffee in the machine in the evening, the sun will brew your coffee in the morning. Coffee is often a collective beverage and our coffee maker is most practical when several people use it. The first coffee takes roughly one and a quarter hours to make. However, once the mortar slab is warm, subsequent brews take only 20-25 minutes.</p>
        <p>Preparing the coffee works similarly to a regular moka pot. You unscrew the top part and remove the funnel, fill the bottom part with water until the valve, place the funnel back, fill it with ground coffee, and then screw the top part back on. To serve the coffee, you unscrew the top part using the longer handle we attached to the moka pot. The handle was inspired by the Arabic raqweh.</p>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_0163_dithered.png" alt='Image: Unscrewing the top part of the moka pot. Photo by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Unscrewing the top part of the moka pot. Photo by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/coffee-making-steps_dithered.png" alt='Image: Preparing coffee. Photos by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Preparing coffee. Photos by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <div class="article-img  vertical">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_9940_dithered.png" alt='Image: Serving solar-powered coffee. Photo by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Serving solar-powered coffee. Photo by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>Our coffee maker is the first insulated cooking device we built, and there is room for improvement. It doesn&rsquo;t produce the characteristic gurgling noise when the coffee is ready, probably because the temperature isn&rsquo;t high enough.</p>
        <p>Also, not all water evaporates. Therefore, cleaning involves placing the base under the tap, letting water run in, shaking, and then turning the coffee maker upside down to empty the base. That&rsquo;s a bit impractical, because the appliance weighs 10 kg.</p>
        <p>Because the coffee collects in the upper chamber, it is not kept warm by the mortar slab and the cork insulation. We solve this by wrapping one or more towels around the top part to keep it warm. Alternatively, you could incorporate heat insulation into the design, for example, with a tea cozy.</p>
        <h2 id="what-you-need">What you need</h2>
        <div class="article-img  vertical">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/moka-pot_dithered.png" alt='Image: The moka pot that we started with. Photo by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: The moka pot that we started with. Photo by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <ul>
        <li>
        <p><em>Moka pot</em>. Choose the size you need. If you get a second-hand device, make sure that the rubber seal is still in good condition. Also, ensure you can easily take off the handle to replace it with a longer, straight handle.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><em>Mortar</em>. Any construction mortar will work. Make sure it&rsquo;s not too coarse. Read more about mortar in our <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-a-solar-powered-electric-oven/">solar oven manual</a>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><em>Metal reinforcement</em>. We pour quite a big chunk of mortar, so we reinforce it with a metal mesh to prevent it from breaking. We use a frying sieve. Chicken wire mesh shaped in a cylinder will work as well.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><em>Cork</em>. For thermal insulation, we use cork sheets available at home decor shops.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><em>Tiles</em>. Read more about tiles and tiling in our <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-a-solar-powered-electric-oven/">solar oven manual</a>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><em>Chimney</em>. Because the water chamber of the coffee pot is sunk in mortar, you need a way to maintain an opening around the valve to release pressure if the coffee maker overheats. We use a metal pastry bag tip, but any metal tube will work. You can also cut a piece out of an aluminum can and roll it up.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><em>Nichrome wire, heat-resistant electric cable</em>. These are the components for building an electric resistance heater (see our <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-an-electric-heating-element-from-scratch/">separate manual</a>).</p>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <h2 id="step-1-thermal-mass-and-electric-resistance-heating">Step 1: Thermal mass and electric resistance heating</h2>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/step-by-step-cooker-step1-4by5_dithered.png" alt='Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 1 to 9). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 1 to 9). Illustration by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <ul>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 1 —</strong> Start by making a mold for the mortar base. Since the moka pot is circular, we decided to shape our cooker’s heating element into a larger cylinder. Get a wooden board. Use a plastic sheet to form a cylinder and tape it to the board with duct tape. We use an old plastic office folder and shape it around a round cork pad that we place on the wooden board.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 2 —</strong> Prepare some mortar and pour a layer of about 2 cm at the bottom of the mold. Let it cure for a couple of hours.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p>In the meantime, prepare your electric resistance circuit <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-an-electric-heating-element-from-scratch/">based on the instructions in our manual</a>. We made a circuit with two nichrome wires in parallel (2 x 64 cm) for a resistance of 3.2 Ohms at 18V. It draws around 5.5 Amps.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 3 —</strong> Make two holes in the plastic mold to weave the heat-resistant electric cables through. Distribute the resistance wires evenly on the surface of the mortar layer. Make sure they do not touch each other.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 4 —</strong> Prepare some more mortar and pour it on top of the first layer so that the electric heating circuit is completely submerged.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p>Add the metal mesh. Gently press it into the mortar. Ensure it doesn’t touch the nichrome wire and that there is sufficient space in the center for the pot to fit. Add a bit more mortar if necessary so that the mesh is trapped at the bottom. Wait for a couple of hours for it to set.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 5 —</strong> Cut the chimney tube at an angle to fit snugly around the coffee pot valve while pointing up. Attach it to the moka pot body with hot glue or clay to ensure it stays in place while pouring mortar. It will later be submerged in mortar.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 6 —</strong> Place the coffee pot on top of the mortar layer, in the center. Remove the handle; otherwise, its tip would get stuck in the next mortar layer. We&rsquo;ll replace it with another handle later in the building process.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 7 —</strong> Prepare more mortar and pour it into the mold, around the coffee maker. Fill the mold up to the screw rim of the coffee pot. Let the mortar cure for at least 24 hours.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 8 —</strong> Once hardened, remove the plastic mold sheet.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 9 —</strong> Let the base dry for an additional 48 hours. Position the base on top of a grid to allow the bottom to dry as well. The mortar should feel completely dry to the touch.</p>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/pouring-mortar_dithered.png" alt='Image on the left: The mold for the mortar slab. Image on the right: The electric resistance heating next to the mold in which the mortar is cast. A metal mesh sieve acts as a reinforcement inside. Photos by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image on the left: The mold for the mortar slab. Image on the right: The electric resistance heating next to the mold in which the mortar is cast. A metal mesh sieve acts as a reinforcement inside. Photos by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/pouring-mortar2_dithered.png" alt='Image on the left: The electric resistance is embedded in the mortar. Image on the right: The moka pot, with the original handle removed, in the mortar slab. The chimney is glued to the base. Photos by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image on the left: The electric resistance is embedded in the mortar. Image on the right: The moka pot, with the original handle removed, in the mortar slab. The chimney is glued to the base. Photos by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <h2 id="step-2-insulation">Step 2: Insulation</h2>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/step-by-step-cooker-step2-4by5_dithered.png" alt='Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 10 to 15). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 10 to 15). Illustration by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>We insulate the mortar slab with a 2 cm thick cork layer on all sides (including the top and bottom). We use rectangular and circular cork sheets, 4 mm thick, which means we use five layers.</p>
        <ul>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 10 —</strong> Layer 5 circular cork pads for the bottom part. Use wood glue to secure them together.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 11 —</strong> Use another five cork pads for the top. Cut out a circle in the middle, about 2 cm wider than the coffee pot, so that there is room to add a plaster protection to the cork. Glue them together.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 12 —</strong> Start cutting and layering cork sheets around the cylinder, using painter&rsquo;s tape to keep them in place. In each layer, make two holes to weave the electric wires through.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 13-15 —</strong> Before adding the last sheet, decide where you want to route the cables from the electric heating resistance. You can cut away a path into the last but one layer of cork to allow the wires to pass. We let them out at the bottom. Add the last sheet of cork (fig 15.). Use some tape to secure it.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p>At this stage, you can run a test. We used water only, in order not to stain the cork with coffee. Test how long it takes for the water to reach the top chamber.</p>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/adding-cork_dithered.png" alt='Image on the left: Cork sheets on top of the finished mortar slab. Image on the right: The device is covered in cork and ready to test with a wattmeter. Photos by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image on the left: Cork sheets on top of the finished mortar slab. Image on the right: The device is covered in cork and ready to test with a wattmeter. Photos by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <h2 id="step-3-tiling">Step 3: Tiling</h2>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/step-by-step-cooker-step3-4by5_dithered.png" alt='Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 16 to 21). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 16 to 21). Illustration by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <p>We chose to cover our coffee maker in glazed tiles. They are waterproof, easy to clean, and commonly used in kitchen furniture, walls and counter tops. Tiles are easy to adapt to various shapes and are aesthetically pleasing. Furthermore, they are easy to obtain and tiling doesn&rsquo;t require expensive tools.</p>
        <ul>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 16 —</strong> First, prepare the surface for tiling. Adhesive mortar doesn&rsquo;t stick well on cork, so start by covering the cork with plaster. We used plaster bands, similar to those used for medical casts. The bands also help to keep the cork sheets together and fill the air gaps. At this stage, protect the coffee maker with painter&rsquo;s tape to prevent it from getting plastered.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p>Leave the plaster to dry for 24 hours.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 17 —</strong> Once the plaster has dried, you can tile the surface. We found vintage glazed tiles on the street that we cut into strips and sanded off their sharp edges. For the top part, we use tile fragments from tiles that shattered during the cutting process. Mix approximately a cup of adhesive mortar for walls (which is stronger than adhesive mortar for floors). Using a spatula, spread some mortar at the back of each tile before pressing it against the cylinder. Leave a gap of a few millimeters between each tile for grouting. Repeat this process for the top, and ensure the chimney entrance remains clear. Leave everything to dry as indicated on the mortar packaging.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 18 —</strong> Now it&rsquo;s time to grout the tiles. The aim of grouting is to seal the joints between the tiles to avoid moisture and dirt getting in. Mix the grout with water following the instructions on the package. With a scraper, or an old plastic card, press the paste in between the tiles. After about 20 minutes, clean up the excess grout with a damp sponge. Smooth out each grout line with a wet finger or sponge. Leave everything until it&rsquo;s dry.</p>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/tiling-coffee-brewer_dithered.png" alt='Image: Tiling the plastered surface. Photos by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Tiling the plastered surface. Photos by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <h2 id="step-4-finishing-touches">Step 4: Finishing touches</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 19 —</strong> Add a handle. Remove the original handle of the moka pot, as it has a vertical design that would get stuck in the mortar. Replace it with a horizontal handle, which gives leverage to screw and unscrew the top chamber and helps to serve the coffee. We made a handle out of wood and attached it with a bolt and nut to the coffee pot using the metal attachment welded on the cylinder. A length of about 20 cm is ideal. Use strong wood because the handle needs to withstand significant stress.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 20 —</strong> Wiring. Extend the short heat-resistant cable with a longer 1.5 mm² regular electric cable. Use shrink tape to prevent water or coffee from coming in.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p>Base. Add a 20 mm thick wood base and cork layer to the underside of the structure. It creates room to lift the coffee maker more easily, and protects the tiles from damaging the countertop surface.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><strong>fig. 21 —</strong> Done! Brew your first solar-powered coffee.</p>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <div class="article-img  vertical">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_9899_dithered.png" alt='Image: The coffee maker is finished. Photo by Marie Verdeil.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: The coffee maker is finished. Photo by Marie Verdeil. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <h2 id="other-ideas">Other ideas</h2>
        <p>You could also fit the coffee pot in mortar in an existing box, like an old wooden crate or a scavenged metal drum. Instead of tiles, you could use other kinds of coating with a cement, lime or plaster base. You could also decide to integrate the pot in the kitchen furniture counter.</p>
        <h2 id="credits">Credits</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>Concept: Kris De Decker, Marie Verdeil.</li>
        <li>Design: Marie Verdeil, with input from Anna Mareschal de Charentenay.</li>
        <li>Construction &amp; documentation: Marie Verdeil, with assistance from Hugo Lopez.</li>
        <li>Thanks to AkashaHub Barcelona for the workspace. Living Energy Farm &amp; Cal Poly for their pioneering work on insulated solar electric cookers.</li>
        </ul>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>![Image: The solar powered coffee maker that we build in this manual. Photo by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/solar-powered-coffee-maker-intro-image_dithered.png)
Image: The solar powered coffee maker that we build in this manual. Photo by Marie Verdeil.

There are many different methods for making coffee, some more energy-efficient than others. However, there are no coffee makers that you can power with a small solar PV panel. For example, a commercially available 12V DC drip coffee maker requires a solar panel of 300 watts to brew coffee and keep it warm.

The key to making a more energy-efficient coffee maker is insulation. Regardless of which conventional coffee maker you purchase, it will typically have little to no heat insulation, and most of the heat generated by the energy source will be wasted into the environment. Therefore, we made an insulated solar electric coffee maker ourselves.

Our coffee maker operates on the same principles as our [solar-powered oven](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-a-solar-powered-electric-oven/) and runs on a 100W solar panel. We embedded an Italian coffee maker—a moka pot—in a mortar slab, surrounded by cork insulation and a layer of ceramic tiles.

&#62; We embedded an Italian coffee maker—a moka pot—in a mortar slab, surrounded by cork insulation and a layer of ceramic tiles.

![Image: Connecting the coffee maker to a solar panel. Photo by Hugo Lopez.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_0104_dithered.png)
Image: Connecting the coffee maker to a solar panel. Photo by Hugo Lopez.

![Image: Cross-section of the coffee maker. 1. Tiles, 2. Cork, 3. Mortar. Illustration by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/coffee-pot-inside_dithered.png)
Image: Cross-section of the coffee maker. 1. Tiles, 2. Cork, 3. Mortar. Illustration by Marie Verdeil.

The cooker has an [electric resistance heating element](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-an-electric-heating-element-from-scratch/) integrated inside, which is directly connected to the solar panel without a battery, solar charge controller, or voltage regulator in between. Although it’s solar-powered, the coffee maker can be located inside your kitchen or next to your bed—only the solar panel needs to be outside.

&#62; Although it’s solar-powered, the coffee maker can be located inside your kitchen or next to your bed—only the solar panel needs to be outside.

The moka pot was invented in 1933 and uses pressure rather than gravity or a pump to brew coffee. It consists of a bottom chamber (a boiler that acts as a base), a funnel filter with a plate and a rubber joint, and an upper chamber where the coffee is collected. Just before the water boils, the steam increases the pressure inside the heating vessel, pushing the water through the filter and the ground coffee. The moka pot is an energy-efficient appliance, comparable to a pressure cooker for food.

## How to brew solar-powered coffee

Once the solar panel receives sunlight in the morning, the coffee maker will start heating up. Consequently, if you put water and coffee in the machine in the evening, the sun will brew your coffee in the morning. Coffee is often a collective beverage and our coffee maker is most practical when several people use it. The first coffee takes roughly one and a quarter hours to make. However, once the mortar slab is warm, subsequent brews take only 20-25 minutes.

Preparing the coffee works similarly to a regular moka pot. You unscrew the top part and remove the funnel, fill the bottom part with water until the valve, place the funnel back, fill it with ground coffee, and then screw the top part back on. To serve the coffee, you unscrew the top part using the longer handle we attached to the moka pot. The handle was inspired by the Arabic raqweh.

![Image: Unscrewing the top part of the moka pot. Photo by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_0163_dithered.png)
Image: Unscrewing the top part of the moka pot. Photo by Marie Verdeil.

![Image: Preparing coffee. Photos by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/coffee-making-steps_dithered.png)
Image: Preparing coffee. Photos by Marie Verdeil.

![Image: Serving solar-powered coffee. Photo by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_9940_dithered.png)
Image: Serving solar-powered coffee. Photo by Marie Verdeil.

Our coffee maker is the first insulated cooking device we built, and there is room for improvement. It doesn’t produce the characteristic gurgling noise when the coffee is ready, probably because the temperature isn’t high enough.

Also, not all water evaporates. Therefore, cleaning involves placing the base under the tap, letting water run in, shaking, and then turning the coffee maker upside down to empty the base. That’s a bit impractical, because the appliance weighs 10 kg.

Because the coffee collects in the upper chamber, it is not kept warm by the mortar slab and the cork insulation. We solve this by wrapping one or more towels around the top part to keep it warm. Alternatively, you could incorporate heat insulation into the design, for example, with a tea cozy.

## What you need

![Image: The moka pot that we started with. Photo by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/moka-pot_dithered.png)
Image: The moka pot that we started with. Photo by Marie Verdeil.

- _Moka pot_. Choose the size you need. If you get a second-hand device, make sure that the rubber seal is still in good condition. Also, ensure you can easily take off the handle to replace it with a longer, straight handle.

- _Mortar_. Any construction mortar will work. Make sure it’s not too coarse. Read more about mortar in our [solar oven manual](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-a-solar-powered-electric-oven/).

- _Metal reinforcement_. We pour quite a big chunk of mortar, so we reinforce it with a metal mesh to prevent it from breaking. We use a frying sieve. Chicken wire mesh shaped in a cylinder will work as well.

- _Cork_. For thermal insulation, we use cork sheets available at home decor shops.

- _Tiles_. Read more about tiles and tiling in our [solar oven manual](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-a-solar-powered-electric-oven/).

- _Chimney_. Because the water chamber of the coffee pot is sunk in mortar, you need a way to maintain an opening around the valve to release pressure if the coffee maker overheats. We use a metal pastry bag tip, but any metal tube will work. You can also cut a piece out of an aluminum can and roll it up.

- _Nichrome wire, heat-resistant electric cable_. These are the components for building an electric resistance heater (see our [separate manual](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-an-electric-heating-element-from-scratch/)).


## Step 1: Thermal mass and electric resistance heating

![Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 1 to 9). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/step-by-step-cooker-step1-4by5_dithered.png)
Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 1 to 9). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.

- **fig. 1 —** Start by making a mold for the mortar base. Since the moka pot is circular, we decided to shape our cooker’s heating element into a larger cylinder. Get a wooden board. Use a plastic sheet to form a cylinder and tape it to the board with duct tape. We use an old plastic office folder and shape it around a round cork pad that we place on the wooden board.

- **fig. 2 —** Prepare some mortar and pour a layer of about 2 cm at the bottom of the mold. Let it cure for a couple of hours.

- In the meantime, prepare your electric resistance circuit [based on the instructions in our manual](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/10/how-to-build-an-electric-heating-element-from-scratch/). We made a circuit with two nichrome wires in parallel (2 x 64 cm) for a resistance of 3.2 Ohms at 18V. It draws around 5.5 Amps.

- **fig. 3 —** Make two holes in the plastic mold to weave the heat-resistant electric cables through. Distribute the resistance wires evenly on the surface of the mortar layer. Make sure they do not touch each other.

- **fig. 4 —** Prepare some more mortar and pour it on top of the first layer so that the electric heating circuit is completely submerged.

- Add the metal mesh. Gently press it into the mortar. Ensure it doesn’t touch the nichrome wire and that there is sufficient space in the center for the pot to fit. Add a bit more mortar if necessary so that the mesh is trapped at the bottom. Wait for a couple of hours for it to set.

- **fig. 5 —** Cut the chimney tube at an angle to fit snugly around the coffee pot valve while pointing up. Attach it to the moka pot body with hot glue or clay to ensure it stays in place while pouring mortar. It will later be submerged in mortar.

- **fig. 6 —** Place the coffee pot on top of the mortar layer, in the center. Remove the handle; otherwise, its tip would get stuck in the next mortar layer. We’ll replace it with another handle later in the building process.

- **fig. 7 —** Prepare more mortar and pour it into the mold, around the coffee maker. Fill the mold up to the screw rim of the coffee pot. Let the mortar cure for at least 24 hours.

- **fig. 8 —** Once hardened, remove the plastic mold sheet.

- **fig. 9 —** Let the base dry for an additional 48 hours. Position the base on top of a grid to allow the bottom to dry as well. The mortar should feel completely dry to the touch.


![Image on the left: The mold for the mortar slab. Image on the right: The electric resistance heating next to the mold in which the mortar is cast. A metal mesh sieve acts as a reinforcement inside. Photos by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/pouring-mortar_dithered.png)
Image on the left: The mold for the mortar slab. Image on the right: The electric resistance heating next to the mold in which the mortar is cast. A metal mesh sieve acts as a reinforcement inside. Photos by Marie Verdeil.

![Image on the left: The electric resistance is embedded in the mortar. Image on the right: The moka pot, with the original handle removed, in the mortar slab. The chimney is glued to the base. Photos by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/pouring-mortar2_dithered.png)
Image on the left: The electric resistance is embedded in the mortar. Image on the right: The moka pot, with the original handle removed, in the mortar slab. The chimney is glued to the base. Photos by Marie Verdeil.

## Step 2: Insulation

![Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 10 to 15). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/step-by-step-cooker-step2-4by5_dithered.png)
Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 10 to 15). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.

We insulate the mortar slab with a 2 cm thick cork layer on all sides (including the top and bottom). We use rectangular and circular cork sheets, 4 mm thick, which means we use five layers.

- **fig. 10 —** Layer 5 circular cork pads for the bottom part. Use wood glue to secure them together.

- **fig. 11 —** Use another five cork pads for the top. Cut out a circle in the middle, about 2 cm wider than the coffee pot, so that there is room to add a plaster protection to the cork. Glue them together.

- **fig. 12 —** Start cutting and layering cork sheets around the cylinder, using painter’s tape to keep them in place. In each layer, make two holes to weave the electric wires through.

- **fig. 13-15 —** Before adding the last sheet, decide where you want to route the cables from the electric heating resistance. You can cut away a path into the last but one layer of cork to allow the wires to pass. We let them out at the bottom. Add the last sheet of cork (fig 15.). Use some tape to secure it.

- At this stage, you can run a test. We used water only, in order not to stain the cork with coffee. Test how long it takes for the water to reach the top chamber.


![Image on the left: Cork sheets on top of the finished mortar slab. Image on the right: The device is covered in cork and ready to test with a wattmeter. Photos by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/adding-cork_dithered.png)
Image on the left: Cork sheets on top of the finished mortar slab. Image on the right: The device is covered in cork and ready to test with a wattmeter. Photos by Marie Verdeil.

## Step 3: Tiling

![Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 16 to 21). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/step-by-step-cooker-step3-4by5_dithered.png)
Image: Step-by-step instructions (figures 16 to 21). Illustration by Marie Verdeil.

We chose to cover our coffee maker in glazed tiles. They are waterproof, easy to clean, and commonly used in kitchen furniture, walls and counter tops. Tiles are easy to adapt to various shapes and are aesthetically pleasing. Furthermore, they are easy to obtain and tiling doesn’t require expensive tools.

- **fig. 16 —** First, prepare the surface for tiling. Adhesive mortar doesn’t stick well on cork, so start by covering the cork with plaster. We used plaster bands, similar to those used for medical casts. The bands also help to keep the cork sheets together and fill the air gaps. At this stage, protect the coffee maker with painter’s tape to prevent it from getting plastered.

- Leave the plaster to dry for 24 hours.

- **fig. 17 —** Once the plaster has dried, you can tile the surface. We found vintage glazed tiles on the street that we cut into strips and sanded off their sharp edges. For the top part, we use tile fragments from tiles that shattered during the cutting process. Mix approximately a cup of adhesive mortar for walls (which is stronger than adhesive mortar for floors). Using a spatula, spread some mortar at the back of each tile before pressing it against the cylinder. Leave a gap of a few millimeters between each tile for grouting. Repeat this process for the top, and ensure the chimney entrance remains clear. Leave everything to dry as indicated on the mortar packaging.

- **fig. 18 —** Now it’s time to grout the tiles. The aim of grouting is to seal the joints between the tiles to avoid moisture and dirt getting in. Mix the grout with water following the instructions on the package. With a scraper, or an old plastic card, press the paste in between the tiles. After about 20 minutes, clean up the excess grout with a damp sponge. Smooth out each grout line with a wet finger or sponge. Leave everything until it’s dry.


![Image: Tiling the plastered surface. Photos by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/tiling-coffee-brewer_dithered.png)
Image: Tiling the plastered surface. Photos by Marie Verdeil.

## Step 4: Finishing touches

- **fig. 19 —** Add a handle. Remove the original handle of the moka pot, as it has a vertical design that would get stuck in the mortar. Replace it with a horizontal handle, which gives leverage to screw and unscrew the top chamber and helps to serve the coffee. We made a handle out of wood and attached it with a bolt and nut to the coffee pot using the metal attachment welded on the cylinder. A length of about 20 cm is ideal. Use strong wood because the handle needs to withstand significant stress.

- **fig. 20 —** Wiring. Extend the short heat-resistant cable with a longer 1.5 mm² regular electric cable. Use shrink tape to prevent water or coffee from coming in.

- Base. Add a 20 mm thick wood base and cork layer to the underside of the structure. It creates room to lift the coffee maker more easily, and protects the tiles from damaging the countertop surface.

- **fig. 21 —** Done! Brew your first solar-powered coffee.


![Image: The coffee maker is finished. Photo by Marie Verdeil.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/IMG_9899_dithered.png)
Image: The coffee maker is finished. Photo by Marie Verdeil.

## Other ideas

You could also fit the coffee pot in mortar in an existing box, like an old wooden crate or a scavenged metal drum. Instead of tiles, you could use other kinds of coating with a cement, lime or plaster base. You could also decide to integrate the pot in the kitchen furniture counter.

## Credits

- Concept: Kris De Decker, Marie Verdeil.
- Design: Marie Verdeil, with input from Anna Mareschal de Charentenay.
- Construction &#38; documentation: Marie Verdeil, with assistance from Hugo Lopez.
- Thanks to AkashaHub Barcelona for the workspace. Living Energy Farm &#38; Cal Poly for their pioneering work on insulated solar electric cookers.</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/images/dithers/solar-powered-coffee-maker-intro-image_dithered.png" length="29884" type="image/png" />
      <guid>cid://https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/how-to-brew-solar-powered-coffee/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/11/08 - Shein today gone tomorrow..., Problems with Suno 4.5, Epic heartburn, Tilley.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251108</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Shein today gone tomorrow..., Problems with Suno 4.5, Epic heartburn, Tilley.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Shein today gone tomorrow..., Problems with Suno 4.5, Epic heartburn, Tilley.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251108</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Space Sim’s Last Hurrah</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/11/the-space-sims-last-hurrah/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This article tells part of the story of space sims. Amidst so much else, the 1990s saw the rise and fall of the narrative-driven space sim. The sub-genre was effectively invented in 1990, when Wing Commander dared to add a set-piece story line to the sturdy foundation of the more open-ended British classic Elite. It [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>This article tells part of the story of space sims. Amidst so much else, the 1990s saw the rise and fall of the narrative-driven space sim. The sub-genre was effectively invented in 1990, when Wing Commander dared to add a set-piece story line to the sturdy foundation of the more open-ended British classic Elite. It \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/freespace2.mp4" length="9160763" type="video/mp4" />
      <guid>cid://https://www.filfre.net/?p=6531</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Testing my 6530 collection</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/testing-my-6530-collection/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I have a small collection of the MOS 6530 RRIOTs as made by MOS Technology. Mask programmed, ROM and also ports can be used as chip select. See the 6530 pages! I have tested my 6530s with the excellent Backbit Chiptester Pro V2. 6530-002 black all tests passed and ROM dumped OK, confirmed to be [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>I have a small collection of the MOS 6530 RRIOTs as made by MOS Technology. Mask programmed, ROM and also ports can be used as chip select. See the 6530 pages! I have tested my 6530s with the excellent Backbit Chiptester Pro V2. 6530-002 black all tests passed and ROM dumped OK, confirmed to be \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=19170</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>SUSE Dives into the Agentic AI Pool</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/SUSE-Dives-into-the-Agentic-AI-Pool</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>SUSE becomes the first open source company to adopt agentic AI with SUSE Enterprise Linux 16.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>SUSE becomes the first open source company to adopt agentic AI with SUSE Enterprise Linux 16.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://26be7e7b690d9b1de9dd019111c54ad0</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Thematic Book Series: Too Much Combustion, Too Little Fire</title>
      <link>https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/thematic-book-series-too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="article-img ">
        <figure data-imgstate="dither">
        <img src="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/thematic-book-series-too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/images/dithers/EN-THEMATIC5_dithered.png" alt='Image: Book cover.' loading="lazy"/></figure>
        <figcaption class="caption">
         Image: Book cover. 
        </figcaption>
        </div>
        </div>
        <ul>
        <li>Buy the <a href="https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/paperback/product-gjyj24g.html?q=&amp;page=1&amp;pageSize=4">print edition</a>.</li>
        <li>Buy the <a href="https://payhip.com/b/ONIU3">epub edition</a>.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>For most of history, the multifunctional fire was the only source of energy in the household. It served as a cookstove, toaster, heating device, lighting source, hot water boiler, clothes dryer, and refrigerator, among other functions.  During the twentieth century, the fire was replaced by a wide range of appliances plugged into central infrastructures.</p>
        <p>In this series of articles, LOW←TECH MAGAZINE critically examines the efficiency, sustainability, health, and safety of the fire and its flame- and smoke-free modern alternatives. What are we saying when we argue that electrical appliances are “better” than a traditional fire?</p>
        <h2 id="contents-table">Contents table</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>Too Much Combustion, Too Little Fire</li>
        <li>Thermo-electric Stoves: Ditch the Solar Panels?</li>
        <li>How to Make Biomass Energy Sustainable Again</li>
        <li>Well-Tended Fires Outperform Modern Cooking Stoves</li>
        <li>If We Insulate Our Houses, Why Not Our Cooking Pots?</li>
        <li>Wood Gas Vehicles: Firewood in the Fuel Tank</li>
        <li>Medieval Smokestacks: Fossil Fuels in Pre-industrial Times</li>
        </ul>
        <h2 id="available-in-our-bookshop">Available in our bookshop</h2>
        <ul>
        <li><a href="https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/paperback/product-gjyj24g.html?q=&amp;page=1&amp;pageSize=4">Print edition</a>.</li>
        <li><a href="https://payhip.com/b/ONIU3">Epub edition</a>.</li>
        </ul>
        <p><a href="https://www.patreon.com/lowtechmagazine">Patrons</a> get free access to ebooks, as well as early access to new print books at a reduced price.</p>
        <h2 id="other-books-in-the-series">Other books in the series</h2>
        <ul>
        <li>
        <p><a href="https://lulu.com/shop/roel-roscam-abbing-and-marie-otsuka-and-kris-de-decker/how-to-build-a-low-tech-internet/paperback/product-9yq8v7.html?q=&amp;page=1&amp;pageSize=4">How to build a low-tech internet?</a>, Kris De Decker, Roel Roscam Abbing, Marie Otsuka, 2023. <a href="https://payhip.com/b/tZwV9">Ebook edition</a>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><a href="https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/how-to-downsize-a-transport-network/paperback/product-42n4p7.html?q=&amp;page=1&amp;pageSize=4">How to downsize a transport network?</a>, Kris De Decker, 2023. <a href="https://payhip.com/b/foXDM">Ebook edition</a>.</p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><a href="https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/heating-people-not-spaces/paperback/product-zm52en6.html?q=heating+people+not+spaces&amp;page=1&amp;pageSize=4">Heating people not spaces</a>, Kris De Decker, 2024. <a href="https://payhip.com/b/AXGN2">Ebook edition</a></p>
        </li>
        <li>
        <p><a href="https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/how-circular-is-the-circular-economy/paperback/product-84n2mvv.html?q=&amp;page=1&amp;pageSize=4">How circular is the circular economy?</a>, Kris De Decker, 2025. <a href="https://payhip.com/b/76Cnm">Ebook edition</a></p>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <p>The Low-tech Magazine archives are also available as a <a href="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/offline-reading/">chronological series consisting of four volumes</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>![Image: Book cover.](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/thematic-book-series-too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/images/dithers/EN-THEMATIC5_dithered.png)
Image: Book cover.

- Buy the [print edition](https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/paperback/product-gjyj24g.html?q=&#38;page=1&#38;pageSize=4).
- Buy the [epub edition](https://payhip.com/b/ONIU3).

For most of history, the multifunctional fire was the only source of energy in the household. It served as a cookstove, toaster, heating device, lighting source, hot water boiler, clothes dryer, and refrigerator, among other functions. During the twentieth century, the fire was replaced by a wide range of appliances plugged into central infrastructures.

In this series of articles, LOW←TECH MAGAZINE critically examines the efficiency, sustainability, health, and safety of the fire and its flame- and smoke-free modern alternatives. What are we saying when we argue that electrical appliances are “better” than a traditional fire?

## Contents table

- Too Much Combustion, Too Little Fire
- Thermo-electric Stoves: Ditch the Solar Panels?
- How to Make Biomass Energy Sustainable Again
- Well-Tended Fires Outperform Modern Cooking Stoves
- If We Insulate Our Houses, Why Not Our Cooking Pots?
- Wood Gas Vehicles: Firewood in the Fuel Tank
- Medieval Smokestacks: Fossil Fuels in Pre-industrial Times

## Available in our bookshop

- [Print edition](https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/paperback/product-gjyj24g.html?q=&#38;page=1&#38;pageSize=4).
- [Epub edition](https://payhip.com/b/ONIU3).

[Patrons](https://www.patreon.com/lowtechmagazine) get free access to ebooks, as well as early access to new print books at a reduced price.

## Other books in the series

- [How to build a low-tech internet?](https://lulu.com/shop/roel-roscam-abbing-and-marie-otsuka-and-kris-de-decker/how-to-build-a-low-tech-internet/paperback/product-9yq8v7.html?q=&#38;page=1&#38;pageSize=4), Kris De Decker, Roel Roscam Abbing, Marie Otsuka, 2023. [Ebook edition](https://payhip.com/b/tZwV9).

- [How to downsize a transport network?](https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/how-to-downsize-a-transport-network/paperback/product-42n4p7.html?q=&#38;page=1&#38;pageSize=4), Kris De Decker, 2023. [Ebook edition](https://payhip.com/b/foXDM).

- [Heating people not spaces](https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/heating-people-not-spaces/paperback/product-zm52en6.html?q=heating+people+not+spaces&#38;page=1&#38;pageSize=4), Kris De Decker, 2024. [Ebook edition](https://payhip.com/b/AXGN2)

- [How circular is the circular economy?](https://www.lulu.com/shop/kris-de-decker/how-circular-is-the-circular-economy/paperback/product-84n2mvv.html?q=&#38;page=1&#38;pageSize=4), Kris De Decker, 2025. [Ebook edition](https://payhip.com/b/76Cnm)


The Low-tech Magazine archives are also available as a [chronological series consisting of four volumes](https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/offline-reading/).</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/thematic-book-series-too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/images/dithers/EN-THEMATIC5_dithered.png" length="13025" type="image/png" />
      <guid>cid://https://solar.lowtechmagazine.com/2025/11/thematic-book-series-too-much-combustion-too-little-fire/</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Linux Now Runs Most Windows Games</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Linux-Now-Runs-Most-Windows-Games</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The latest data shows that nearly 90 percent of Windows games can be played on Linux.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The latest data shows that nearly 90 percent of Windows games can be played on Linux.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://2d3e7e7c47fee9aae7e939630cd2a838</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>WROCC November 2025 talk on Wednesday - Martin Avison</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2243.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The November 2025 WROCC talk is on Wednesday 5th November and starts at at 7.45pm on Zoom.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The November 2025 WROCC talk is on Wednesday 5th November and starts at at 7.45pm on Zoom.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2243.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>They call it Mister Pibb (again)</title>
      <link>https://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2025/11/they-call-it-mister-pibb-again.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[As Pibb is the official beverage of Old Vintage Computing Research, no doubt to the profound chagrin of the Coca-Cola Company, I feel compelled to offer a public service announcement.
        <p>
        Old and busted:
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhaqaHZYq0MUUYKORLhWcKMFMZ0sTKpL0g3hkXS-b20vYKUsU68Gwo32eJLeS5lmt9sfJUGhLJiCkslZ2xc-s2nDtbl0xxtRWYGBxR90Jws5yXAMaEETigivaofE5zftfqigYIDeVq022GF7bKmr1Zq4O33pL5LUsByEsduYAaTeCUkBEVukuJf7k4lzUM/s4080/PXL_20251102_225658051.jpg" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" width="320" data-original-height="3072" data-original-width="4080" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhaqaHZYq0MUUYKORLhWcKMFMZ0sTKpL0g3hkXS-b20vYKUsU68Gwo32eJLeS5lmt9sfJUGhLJiCkslZ2xc-s2nDtbl0xxtRWYGBxR90Jws5yXAMaEETigivaofE5zftfqigYIDeVq022GF7bKmr1Zq4O33pL5LUsByEsduYAaTeCUkBEVukuJf7k4lzUM/s320/PXL_20251102_225658051.jpg"/></a></div>
        
        New hotness:
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhMhEUR_tqYdBuIoroKIRv0Uhw9iSKnneVJQC0PynjXPRBhT73ePrAuMzuD29iA5S96BO1v9m4WHrVjAgauzzSQ8CoAYOA4vg5OwuhwkaEdwXAALw6FxVFZQoGq-w01WuBMeLwz0kgeZ52dcBnSyhh0x9iAXaYJX4BNjY5w_Rt3G4pzehhLeKvAa9kvuus/s4080/PXL_20251102_214259415~2.jpg" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" width="320" data-original-height="3072" data-original-width="4080" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhMhEUR_tqYdBuIoroKIRv0Uhw9iSKnneVJQC0PynjXPRBhT73ePrAuMzuD29iA5S96BO1v9m4WHrVjAgauzzSQ8CoAYOA4vg5OwuhwkaEdwXAALw6FxVFZQoGq-w01WuBMeLwz0kgeZ52dcBnSyhh0x9iAXaYJX4BNjY5w_Rt3G4pzehhLeKvAa9kvuus/s320/PXL_20251102_214259415~2.jpg"/></a></div>
        
        Yes, Mr Pibb (technically mr P!BB, though Coca-Cola is <a href="https://www.coca-colacompany.com/media-center/mr--pibb-returns-with-bold-flavor-and-more-caffeine">inconsistent on their own brand name</a>) is back and Pibb Xtra, the face of Pibb since 2001, is relegated to the dust heap with Peppo. This explains why I had been unable to buy any more Pibb Xtra for the past month or so &mdash; Coke was probably depleting their stocks for the switchback. Since Old VCR's northern HQ is relatively close to a Coke bottling plant, I was able to pick up two fridge packs at Safeway today, though not exactly what I was expecting!
        <p>
        <a name='more'></a>
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhhu4NJUsKF-D176moBVTwgBycMwmjHxeJ5XTjEAuYbtCE_xhQ9RbdQvggF9RetrS9V8ykWCvmdhP4IxjW7evm8b_NRlj9f-q3JN0iYWy2yH36LPvFxH4zKBDwNeh5mkMsyKDA7g-Y8u6o3YMBc7U_MQBjGHbfkmudYT3l9zOAUve9wkH3h2alsm6TlhS4/s4080/PXL_20251102_221226982.jpg" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" width="320" data-original-height="3072" data-original-width="4080" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhhu4NJUsKF-D176moBVTwgBycMwmjHxeJ5XTjEAuYbtCE_xhQ9RbdQvggF9RetrS9V8ykWCvmdhP4IxjW7evm8b_NRlj9f-q3JN0iYWy2yH36LPvFxH4zKBDwNeh5mkMsyKDA7g-Y8u6o3YMBc7U_MQBjGHbfkmudYT3l9zOAUve9wkH3h2alsm6TlhS4/s320/PXL_20251102_221226982.jpg"/></a></div>
        
        Besides the new can, the additional caffeine (30% more, though 54mg/can vs 40mg/can is probably not physiologically relevant for most people) and the additional ten calories, the other change is the taste. Now, Coke's marketdroids play the usual crap here and describe it in almost contradictory terms as "a comeback" yet possessing "a bold, spicy cherry taste with hints of caramel." But actually ...
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgtEu0Yv0LVq4QD5y4UIMr_oqM1aYNn4MGFAODVuJoOuvVOjj2zasoEkKae8jUJ0n38cSPW8cXWa7YJs4ow955IeQX_t75FcpS6Jyt8iq9LdkYxXSXUqhSdgHrwNrEWbcLEU2Z04fQFpSYzCY7sgDgQA2Gn51EzBd1LAHryfOVXWH7p1nezTVYu1HRXEjs/s4080/PXL_20251102_221614118.jpg" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" height="320" data-original-height="4080" data-original-width="3072" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgtEu0Yv0LVq4QD5y4UIMr_oqM1aYNn4MGFAODVuJoOuvVOjj2zasoEkKae8jUJ0n38cSPW8cXWa7YJs4ow955IeQX_t75FcpS6Jyt8iq9LdkYxXSXUqhSdgHrwNrEWbcLEU2Z04fQFpSYzCY7sgDgQA2Gn51EzBd1LAHryfOVXWH7p1nezTVYu1HRXEjs/s320/PXL_20251102_221614118.jpg"/></a></div>
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhqnD0jAvIGokvDIFIC88_12U7CZG-PHEgE47NuKDFoxLprnCTYGVsgPK6AZOO9X-rhl16w6lH777dNPLjzZYBTErOsYILBKYxeJtpmxbtUwZo6q8qbdM6KQkQMofGDzHS2ZwtvjP1pNtchWcuOC_nWQhNzYBX1hr5AHkSGOmEKdWSN-MIA3AJ-n01T6A4/s4080/PXL_20251102_221615814.jpg" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" height="320" data-original-height="4080" data-original-width="3072" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhqnD0jAvIGokvDIFIC88_12U7CZG-PHEgE47NuKDFoxLprnCTYGVsgPK6AZOO9X-rhl16w6lH777dNPLjzZYBTErOsYILBKYxeJtpmxbtUwZo6q8qbdM6KQkQMofGDzHS2ZwtvjP1pNtchWcuOC_nWQhNzYBX1hr5AHkSGOmEKdWSN-MIA3AJ-n01T6A4/s320/PXL_20251102_221615814.jpg"/></a></div>
        
        ... this tastes mostly like the original. Although I'm disappointed it's HFCS and not cane sugar, it tastes like I remember classic Pibb tasting when McDonald's had it on fountain back in the day. Yes, this is also what my dad would water down with Coke to make a "Poke" because he found it too sweet, but even my wife, who is not a fan of any Pepper-style beverage generally, prefers this flavour to Xtra. The only other mark against it is a mildly spicy aftertaste that lingers a touch longer than it should, though Xtra does that a little bit too.
        <p>
        Overall I like them both, but clearly Xtra is on the way out. It's kind of funny given that Coke not too long ago released those limited edition Stranger Things New Coke cans:
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both; text-align: center;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9MVbR-c0k0i0T2rdsXgB5yhE-4QW06fMDl_HH6lm7bmC75ahe0ArvHaOZ9oOFstYG6n19wPStEO6I9zPr-ncTfNqQz6K2sPS2WrS0xfVCVwPu1Bxwy380tOCHxrj29nj5T2AQWXQ53jxb/s2048/IMG_20190622_105621.jpg" imageanchor="1" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0px;"><img alt="Even New Coke is better than New Blogger!" border="0" data-original-height="2048" data-original-width="1536" height="320" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9MVbR-c0k0i0T2rdsXgB5yhE-4QW06fMDl_HH6lm7bmC75ahe0ArvHaOZ9oOFstYG6n19wPStEO6I9zPr-ncTfNqQz6K2sPS2WrS0xfVCVwPu1Bxwy380tOCHxrj29nj5T2AQWXQ53jxb/w240-h320/IMG_20190622_105621.jpg" title="Even New Coke is better than New Blogger!" width="240" /></a></div>
        
        I actually didn't mind New Coke and the Stranger Things reformulation tasted approximately correct to my fuzzy memories of the original New Coke despite being good to have Classic (this is also true of early versions of Mac OS X). Still, both drinks are retro throwbacks in their own ways, one to the new and busted and the other to the old hotness, though this move implies Coca-Cola has more confidence in reviving old Pibb than New Coke &mdash; or at least is more willing to sink Pibb than Coke if they end up guessing wrong. I'll be putting a can of Pibb Xtra in my collection for posterity along with my last bottle of Dublin Dr Pepper, the finest Dr Pepper variant ever made.
        <p>
        For the sake of my day job, I should also officially state you should consume Mr Pibb/Pibb Xtra or any other sugar-sweetened beverage in moderation. After all, as Steve Jobs famously said to John Sculley, "Do you want to sell sugar water for the rest of your life, or do you want to come with me [from Pepsi] and change the world?" If you don't have a Coke bottling plant in your vicinity, which is probably where the "select markets" are, Coke says you'll get it in the "national rollout" sometime <a href="https://www.coca-colacompany.com/media-center/mr--pibb-returns-with-bold-flavor-and-more-caffeine">in 2026</a> &mdash; and it may also be coming to <a href="https://www.foodandwine.com/coca-cola-mr-pibb-revival-11840005">a soda fountain near you</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>As Pibb is the official beverage of Old Vintage Computing Research, no doubt to the profound chagrin of the Coca-Cola Company, I feel compelled to offer a public service announcement.

Old and busted:

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhaqaHZYq0MUUYKORLhWcKMFMZ0sTKpL0g3hkXS-b20vYKUsU68Gwo32eJLeS5lmt9sfJUGhLJiCkslZ2xc-s2nDtbl0xxtRWYGBxR90Jws5yXAMaEETigivaofE5zftfqigYIDeVq022GF7bKmr1Zq4O33pL5LUsByEsduYAaTeCUkBEVukuJf7k4lzUM/s320/PXL_20251102_225658051.jpg)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhaqaHZYq0MUUYKORLhWcKMFMZ0sTKpL0g3hkXS-b20vYKUsU68Gwo32eJLeS5lmt9sfJUGhLJiCkslZ2xc-s2nDtbl0xxtRWYGBxR90Jws5yXAMaEETigivaofE5zftfqigYIDeVq022GF7bKmr1Zq4O33pL5LUsByEsduYAaTeCUkBEVukuJf7k4lzUM/s4080/PXL_20251102_225658051.jpg)

New hotness:

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhMhEUR_tqYdBuIoroKIRv0Uhw9iSKnneVJQC0PynjXPRBhT73ePrAuMzuD29iA5S96BO1v9m4WHrVjAgauzzSQ8CoAYOA4vg5OwuhwkaEdwXAALw6FxVFZQoGq-w01WuBMeLwz0kgeZ52dcBnSyhh0x9iAXaYJX4BNjY5w_Rt3G4pzehhLeKvAa9kvuus/s320/PXL_20251102_214259415~2.jpg)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhMhEUR_tqYdBuIoroKIRv0Uhw9iSKnneVJQC0PynjXPRBhT73ePrAuMzuD29iA5S96BO1v9m4WHrVjAgauzzSQ8CoAYOA4vg5OwuhwkaEdwXAALw6FxVFZQoGq-w01WuBMeLwz0kgeZ52dcBnSyhh0x9iAXaYJX4BNjY5w_Rt3G4pzehhLeKvAa9kvuus/s4080/PXL_20251102_214259415~2.jpg)

Yes, Mr Pibb (technically mr P!BB, though Coca-Cola is [inconsistent on their own brand name](https://www.coca-colacompany.com/media-center/mr--pibb-returns-with-bold-flavor-and-more-caffeine)) is back and Pibb Xtra, the face of Pibb since 2001, is relegated to the dust heap with Peppo. This explains why I had been unable to buy any more Pibb Xtra for the past month or so — Coke was probably depleting their stocks for the switchback. Since Old VCR&#39;s northern HQ is relatively close to a Coke bottling plant, I was able to pick up two fridge packs at Safeway today, though not exactly what I was expecting!

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhhu4NJUsKF-D176moBVTwgBycMwmjHxeJ5XTjEAuYbtCE_xhQ9RbdQvggF9RetrS9V8ykWCvmdhP4IxjW7evm8b_NRlj9f-q3JN0iYWy2yH36LPvFxH4zKBDwNeh5mkMsyKDA7g-Y8u6o3YMBc7U_MQBjGHbfkmudYT3l9zOAUve9wkH3h2alsm6TlhS4/s320/PXL_20251102_221226982.jpg)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhhu4NJUsKF-D176moBVTwgBycMwmjHxeJ5XTjEAuYbtCE_xhQ9RbdQvggF9RetrS9V8ykWCvmdhP4IxjW7evm8b_NRlj9f-q3JN0iYWy2yH36LPvFxH4zKBDwNeh5mkMsyKDA7g-Y8u6o3YMBc7U_MQBjGHbfkmudYT3l9zOAUve9wkH3h2alsm6TlhS4/s4080/PXL_20251102_221226982.jpg)

Besides the new can, the additional caffeine (30% more, though 54mg/can vs 40mg/can is probably not physiologically relevant for most people) and the additional ten calories, the other change is the taste. Now, Coke&#39;s marketdroids play the usual crap here and describe it in almost contradictory terms as &#34;a comeback&#34; yet possessing &#34;a bold, spicy cherry taste with hints of caramel.&#34; But actually ...

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgtEu0Yv0LVq4QD5y4UIMr_oqM1aYNn4MGFAODVuJoOuvVOjj2zasoEkKae8jUJ0n38cSPW8cXWa7YJs4ow955IeQX_t75FcpS6Jyt8iq9LdkYxXSXUqhSdgHrwNrEWbcLEU2Z04fQFpSYzCY7sgDgQA2Gn51EzBd1LAHryfOVXWH7p1nezTVYu1HRXEjs/s320/PXL_20251102_221614118.jpg)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEgtEu0Yv0LVq4QD5y4UIMr_oqM1aYNn4MGFAODVuJoOuvVOjj2zasoEkKae8jUJ0n38cSPW8cXWa7YJs4ow955IeQX_t75FcpS6Jyt8iq9LdkYxXSXUqhSdgHrwNrEWbcLEU2Z04fQFpSYzCY7sgDgQA2Gn51EzBd1LAHryfOVXWH7p1nezTVYu1HRXEjs/s4080/PXL_20251102_221614118.jpg)

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhqnD0jAvIGokvDIFIC88_12U7CZG-PHEgE47NuKDFoxLprnCTYGVsgPK6AZOO9X-rhl16w6lH777dNPLjzZYBTErOsYILBKYxeJtpmxbtUwZo6q8qbdM6KQkQMofGDzHS2ZwtvjP1pNtchWcuOC_nWQhNzYBX1hr5AHkSGOmEKdWSN-MIA3AJ-n01T6A4/s320/PXL_20251102_221615814.jpg)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEhqnD0jAvIGokvDIFIC88_12U7CZG-PHEgE47NuKDFoxLprnCTYGVsgPK6AZOO9X-rhl16w6lH777dNPLjzZYBTErOsYILBKYxeJtpmxbtUwZo6q8qbdM6KQkQMofGDzHS2ZwtvjP1pNtchWcuOC_nWQhNzYBX1hr5AHkSGOmEKdWSN-MIA3AJ-n01T6A4/s4080/PXL_20251102_221615814.jpg)

... this tastes mostly like the original. Although I&#39;m disappointed it&#39;s HFCS and not cane sugar, it tastes like I remember classic Pibb tasting when McDonald&#39;s had it on fountain back in the day. Yes, this is also what my dad would water down with Coke to make a &#34;Poke&#34; because he found it too sweet, but even my wife, who is not a fan of any Pepper-style beverage generally, prefers this flavour to Xtra. The only other mark against it is a mildly spicy aftertaste that lingers a touch longer than it should, though Xtra does that a little bit too.

Overall I like them both, but clearly Xtra is on the way out. It&#39;s kind of funny given that Coke not too long ago released those limited edition Stranger Things New Coke cans:

[![Even New Coke is better than New Blogger!](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9MVbR-c0k0i0T2rdsXgB5yhE-4QW06fMDl_HH6lm7bmC75ahe0ArvHaOZ9oOFstYG6n19wPStEO6I9zPr-ncTfNqQz6K2sPS2WrS0xfVCVwPu1Bxwy380tOCHxrj29nj5T2AQWXQ53jxb/w240-h320/IMG_20190622_105621.jpg)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEg9MVbR-c0k0i0T2rdsXgB5yhE-4QW06fMDl_HH6lm7bmC75ahe0ArvHaOZ9oOFstYG6n19wPStEO6I9zPr-ncTfNqQz6K2sPS2WrS0xfVCVwPu1Bxwy380tOCHxrj29nj5T2AQWXQ53jxb/s2048/IMG_20190622_105621.jpg)

I actually didn&#39;t mind New Coke and the Stranger Things reformulation tasted approximately correct to my fuzzy memories of the original New Coke despite being good to have Classic (this is also true of early versions of Mac OS X). Still, both drinks are retro throwbacks in their own ways, one to the new and busted and the other to the old hotness, though this move implies Coca-Cola has more confidence in reviving old Pibb than New Coke — or at least is more willing to sink Pibb than Coke if they end up guessing wrong. I&#39;ll be putting a can of Pibb Xtra in my collection for posterity along with my last bottle of Dublin Dr Pepper, the finest Dr Pepper variant ever made.

For the sake of my day job, I should also officially state you should consume Mr Pibb/Pibb Xtra or any other sugar-sweetened beverage in moderation. After all, as Steve Jobs famously said to John Sculley, &#34;Do you want to sell sugar water for the rest of your life, or do you want to come with me \[from Pepsi\] and change the world?&#34; If you don&#39;t have a Coke bottling plant in your vicinity, which is probably where the &#34;select markets&#34; are, Coke says you&#39;ll get it in the &#34;national rollout&#34; sometime [in 2026](https://www.coca-colacompany.com/media-center/mr--pibb-returns-with-bold-flavor-and-more-caffeine) — and it may also be coming to [a soda fountain near you](https://www.foodandwine.com/coca-cola-mr-pibb-revival-11840005).</source:markdown>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (ClassicHasClass)</author>
      <guid>cid://tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8349470052336612452.post-8909424726709325588</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/11/02 - This is not the future we were promised, Coming Home to Tea (AI song x13), Bonus music, My 0.02 on RISC OS, DDE Update.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251102</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This is not the future we were promised, Coming Home to Tea (AI song x13), Bonus music, My 0.02 on RISC OS, DDE Update.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>This is not the future we were promised, Coming Home to Tea (AI song x13), Bonus music, My 0.02 on RISC OS, DDE Update.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251102</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Vintage Computing and Gaming is 20</title>
      <link>https://www.vintagecomputing.com/index.php/archives/3620/vintage-computing-and-gaming-is-20</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Greetings, fellow retro tech fans. 20 years ago today, I launched Vintage Computing and Gaming. The origins of the site have been well-covered elsewhere, so I&#8217;ll spare you the rehash. Just kidding, that was a rehash. I copied and pasted that first paragraph from my 15th anniversary post and changed the number. 🙂 But seriously, [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Greetings, fellow retro tech fans. 20 years ago today, I launched Vintage Computing and Gaming. The origins of the site have been well-covered elsewhere, so I’ll spare you the rehash. Just kidding, that was a rehash. I copied and pasted that first paragraph from my 15th anniversary post and changed the number. 🙂 But seriously, \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.vintagecomputing.com/?p=3620</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/11/01 - Yeah just drive over my lawn why don&#39;t you, Abusing a pumpkin, YouTube error 153, Toussaint.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251101</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Yeah just drive over my lawn why don't you, Abusing a pumpkin, YouTube error 153, Toussaint.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Yeah just drive over my lawn why don&#39;t you, Abusing a pumpkin, YouTube error 153, Toussaint.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251101</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
