<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:source="https://source.scripting.com/">
  <atom:link href="http://localhost:8000/retro_computingxml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Retro Computing News</title>
    <link>http://localhost:8000/retro_computingxml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>09 Oct 25 11:10 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.9</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/10/08 - Crappy fake uSD card, Paracetamol.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251008</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Crappy fake uSD card, Paracetamol.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Crappy fake uSD card, Paracetamol.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251008</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Cairo Dock 3.6 Now Available for More Compositors</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Cairo-Dock-3.6-Now-Available-for-More-Compositors</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>If you're a fan of third-party desktop docks, then the latest release of Cairo Dock with Wayland support is for you.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>If you&#39;re a fan of third-party desktop docks, then the latest release of Cairo Dock with Wayland support is for you.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://fddfab5251f279da08544c6099b77faf</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>System76 Unleashes Pop!_OS 24.04 Beta</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/System76-Unleashes-Pop%21_OS-24.04-Beta</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>System76's first beta of Pop!_OS 24.04 is an impressive feat.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>System76&#39;s first beta of Pop!\_OS 24.04 is an impressive feat.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://8b93859614ee9f9d38ffe2f40f0f8e70</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/10/07 - Shut up Badenoch, What the hell France?, Colours, And Or Eor, White Van Man.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251007</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Shut up Badenoch, What the hell France?, Colours, And Or Eor, White Van Man.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Shut up Badenoch, What the hell France?, Colours, And Or Eor, White Van Man.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251007</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>KIM-1 Revisions, what changed?</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/kim-1-revisions-what-changed/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I know of seven KIM-1 revisions, labeled Rev A-G and the first one unlabeled. Rev C is unknown! What changed between these revisions? Not much. The PCB underwent several changes around the logo area, from KIM-1 MOS to Commodore C-MOS. That happened from Rev A to Rev D, indicating the takeover by Commodore of MOS [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>I know of seven KIM-1 revisions, labeled Rev A-G and the first one unlabeled. Rev C is unknown! What changed between these revisions? Not much. The PCB underwent several changes around the logo area, from KIM-1 MOS to Commodore C-MOS. That happened from Rev A to Rev D, indicating the takeover by Commodore of MOS \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=18996</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>KIM-1, were IC sockets used?</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/kim-1-were-ic-sockets-used/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Before I saw the last revision, Rev G, I had never seen an original KIM-1 with IC sockets. All ICs were soldered right into the PCB. Now I have a KIM-1 Rev G and a photo by Dick Dral of his KIM-1 Rev G with white IC sockets. So the last iteration of the KIM-1 [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Before I saw the last revision, Rev G, I had never seen an original KIM-1 with IC sockets. All ICs were soldered right into the PCB. Now I have a KIM-1 Rev G and a photo by Dick Dral of his KIM-1 Rev G with white IC sockets. So the last iteration of the KIM-1 \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=18984</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The 2025 London Show is less than 3 weeks away...</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2238.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[It's now less than 3 weeks to go until the 2025 London Show.....]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>It&#39;s now less than 3 weeks to go until the 2025 London Show.....</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2238.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Images of the 6530s I have</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/images-of-the-6530s-i-have/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Over the years I have acquired quite some 6530 ICs. Either as IC or built into a KIM-1, Jolt or Chessmate. On this page I show these 6530s. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 needs 2 edge connectors. The specifications are: card edge; PIN: 44; 3.96mm When you search for those, ...Magazines: [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Over the years I have acquired quite some 6530 ICs. Either as IC or built into a KIM-1, Jolt or Chessmate. On this page I show these 6530s. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 needs 2 edge connectors. The specifications are: card edge; PIN: 44; 3.96mm When you search for those, ...Magazines: \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=18977</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The end of AOL dialup</title>
      <link>https://oldvcr.blogspot.com/2025/10/the-end-of-aol-dialup.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[America Online has ceased offering dialup access since first doing so in 1991 (<a href="/2023/06/o-brother-geobook-lets-get-thou-back-on.html">using GeoWorks</a>), and presumably any systems attempting to dial in will no longer be able to make a connection.
        <p>
        We actually had a fairly long history with AOL and its predecessors in our house. We got a copy of PlayNET as a door prize at the local Commodore computer club meeting (dunno where that went) and my folks initially signed up for AOL's C64-based predecessor, QuantumLink &mdash; which I was quickly banned from after they got the first monthly bill. However, when in the mid-1990s my dad decided we should be online again (I already was myself using the dialup at UC San Diego), I suggested AOL to them since it was the easiest approach. It covered the entire family: I used it on medical school away rotations when I didn't have a local POP number to call into the university, back then on <a href="/2022/10/refurb-weekend-powerbook-1400.html">my PowerBook 1400</a>. In fact, the last time I used it was in July 2006, when I drove across the United States <a href="/2025/08/make-your-apple-ii-or-commodore-64.html">from San Diego to Bangor</a> along <a href="http://www.floodgap.com/roadgap/6/">US Highway 6</a>. Wi-Fi was certainly not universal at the time and neither was cell coverage, so it was the least difficult option to use when local network access wasn't available. Here's me logging in on the iBook G4 from Ely, Nevada.
        
        <div class="separator" style="clear: both;"><a href="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiCKI7dNJsPMNol-17nR5zcihmzKD9kacuNBlpA-F0e4Kb4ByawFCTcnAhIKF2MAzbGObF9VSLo9j1sWP2gQa4ORddVlloO59DIba1LMUPRDWs9Ej2hAS7QxzACe2AG9ebv-hM9FBqhqbDAhoRKGH7r6dX_kdy74zHSFGSC2zq5JIgVHKsI6LeFALa5QKY/s2048/01055.JPG" style="display: block; padding: 1em 0; text-align: center; "><img alt="" border="0" width="320" data-original-height="1536" data-original-width="2048" src="https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiCKI7dNJsPMNol-17nR5zcihmzKD9kacuNBlpA-F0e4Kb4ByawFCTcnAhIKF2MAzbGObF9VSLo9j1sWP2gQa4ORddVlloO59DIba1LMUPRDWs9Ej2hAS7QxzACe2AG9ebv-hM9FBqhqbDAhoRKGH7r6dX_kdy74zHSFGSC2zq5JIgVHKsI6LeFALa5QKY/s320/01055.JPG"/></a></div>
        
        You can see the AOL login screen faintly on the iBook's LCD. The last time I remember using AOL was on the same trip from a later stay a few days later in Warren, Pennsylvania. I don't have any pictures of that, but I distinctly remember doing so, because it made uploading images to the road"b"log impractical due to the poor quality of the phone lines at the motel. Still, I could log in and read my E-mail from my servers in the apartment over SSH, so it achieved its purpose.
        <p>
        Although at least one <a href="https://github.com/erfg12/AOL_4.0_Emu">client re-creation</a> exists, it would be more interesting to see someone develop a new AOL <em>server</em> using modern modem emulation tools that the AOL clients can talk to. Much as QuantumLink's server responses can now be simulated, facilitating <a href="https://quantumlink.net/">a fan recreation</a>, and because some pieces of the old PlayNET and QLink architecture underlaid AOL, it should be possible to do the same. Although some work exists on AIM, the instant messenger component (I certainly remember plenty of unsolicited chat requests), the whole experience really ought to be preserved in some fashion because for at least a few years it was the most common way people connected to the Internet no matter its warts. However, as there's obviously no way to serial-snoop the real thing now, hopefully someone at Yahoo/Verizon can leak the source code or protocol description so it can be resurrected. Though I certainly see no reason to use the dialup service as anything other than a historical simulation now that we have hotspotting and ubiquitous Wi-Fi &mdash; and my parents cancelled their dialup account after they got cable Internet &mdash; I also point out that my mom still has the same AOL E-mail address she had back then, and it still does the job for her.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>America Online has ceased offering dialup access since first doing so in 1991 ( [using GeoWorks](/2023/06/o-brother-geobook-lets-get-thou-back-on.html)), and presumably any systems attempting to dial in will no longer be able to make a connection.

We actually had a fairly long history with AOL and its predecessors in our house. We got a copy of PlayNET as a door prize at the local Commodore computer club meeting (dunno where that went) and my folks initially signed up for AOL&#39;s C64-based predecessor, QuantumLink — which I was quickly banned from after they got the first monthly bill. However, when in the mid-1990s my dad decided we should be online again (I already was myself using the dialup at UC San Diego), I suggested AOL to them since it was the easiest approach. It covered the entire family: I used it on medical school away rotations when I didn&#39;t have a local POP number to call into the university, back then on [my PowerBook 1400](/2022/10/refurb-weekend-powerbook-1400.html). In fact, the last time I used it was in July 2006, when I drove across the United States [from San Diego to Bangor](/2025/08/make-your-apple-ii-or-commodore-64.html) along [US Highway 6](http://www.floodgap.com/roadgap/6/). Wi-Fi was certainly not universal at the time and neither was cell coverage, so it was the least difficult option to use when local network access wasn&#39;t available. Here&#39;s me logging in on the iBook G4 from Ely, Nevada.

[![](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiCKI7dNJsPMNol-17nR5zcihmzKD9kacuNBlpA-F0e4Kb4ByawFCTcnAhIKF2MAzbGObF9VSLo9j1sWP2gQa4ORddVlloO59DIba1LMUPRDWs9Ej2hAS7QxzACe2AG9ebv-hM9FBqhqbDAhoRKGH7r6dX_kdy74zHSFGSC2zq5JIgVHKsI6LeFALa5QKY/s320/01055.JPG)](https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/img/b/R29vZ2xl/AVvXsEiCKI7dNJsPMNol-17nR5zcihmzKD9kacuNBlpA-F0e4Kb4ByawFCTcnAhIKF2MAzbGObF9VSLo9j1sWP2gQa4ORddVlloO59DIba1LMUPRDWs9Ej2hAS7QxzACe2AG9ebv-hM9FBqhqbDAhoRKGH7r6dX_kdy74zHSFGSC2zq5JIgVHKsI6LeFALa5QKY/s2048/01055.JPG)

You can see the AOL login screen faintly on the iBook&#39;s LCD. The last time I remember using AOL was on the same trip from a later stay a few days later in Warren, Pennsylvania. I don&#39;t have any pictures of that, but I distinctly remember doing so, because it made uploading images to the road&#34;b&#34;log impractical due to the poor quality of the phone lines at the motel. Still, I could log in and read my E-mail from my servers in the apartment over SSH, so it achieved its purpose.

Although at least one [client re-creation](https://github.com/erfg12/AOL_4.0_Emu) exists, it would be more interesting to see someone develop a new AOL _server_ using modern modem emulation tools that the AOL clients can talk to. Much as QuantumLink&#39;s server responses can now be simulated, facilitating [a fan recreation](https://quantumlink.net/), and because some pieces of the old PlayNET and QLink architecture underlaid AOL, it should be possible to do the same. Although some work exists on AIM, the instant messenger component (I certainly remember plenty of unsolicited chat requests), the whole experience really ought to be preserved in some fashion because for at least a few years it was the most common way people connected to the Internet no matter its warts. However, as there&#39;s obviously no way to serial-snoop the real thing now, hopefully someone at Yahoo/Verizon can leak the source code or protocol description so it can be resurrected. Though I certainly see no reason to use the dialup service as anything other than a historical simulation now that we have hotspotting and ubiquitous Wi-Fi — and my parents cancelled their dialup account after they got cable Internet — I also point out that my mom still has the same AOL E-mail address she had back then, and it still does the job for her.</source:markdown>
      <author>noreply@blogger.com (ClassicHasClass)</author>
      <guid>cid://tag:blogger.com,1999:blog-8349470052336612452.post-7012013262726380909</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>KazuGrid 1.0</title>
      <link>https://sourceforge.net/p/freedos/news/2025/10/kazugrid-10/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="markdown_content"><p>Mateusz Viste has created an interesting set of logic puzzle games for DOS: "Fire up KazuGrid and test your wits with mind-bending challenges, now in crisp VGA high resolution! Each grid is a battlefield of numbers - spot patterns, crack logic puzzles, and prove you're the ultimate gridmaster." Requires VGA and a mouse. MIT license. You can find it at the <a class="" href="https://mateusz.fr/kazugrid/" rel="nofollow">KazuGrid website</a></p></div>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Mateusz Viste has created an interesting set of logic puzzle games for DOS: &#34;Fire up KazuGrid and test your wits with mind-bending challenges, now in crisp VGA high resolution! Each grid is a battlefield of numbers - spot patterns, crack logic puzzles, and prove you&#39;re the ultimate gridmaster.&#34; Requires VGA and a mouse. MIT license. You can find it at the [KazuGrid website](https://mateusz.fr/kazugrid/)</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sourceforge.net04de24a8e79a6f44f1fed8cfd654b3626b91bbba</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>My KIM-1 collection</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/my-kim-1-collection/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In 2024/2025 I completed my KIM-1 collection with one or two from every Revision, from first edition to Rev G, nine in total. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 needs 2 edge connectors. The specifications are: card edge; PIN: 44; 3.96mm When you search for those, ...Magazines: Compute! and Compute IIThe pages [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>In 2024/2025 I completed my KIM-1 collection with one or two from every Revision, from first edition to Rev G, nine in total. See also:KIM-1 connectors: beware the Chinese cheap variants!The KIM-1 needs 2 edge connectors. The specifications are: card edge; PIN: 44; 3.96mm When you search for those, ...Magazines: Compute! and Compute IIThe pages \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=18935</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>ZFP Systems at the London Show</title>
      <link>https://www.riscository.com/2025/zfp-systems-london-show/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[It&#8217;s now just three weeks to go until this year&#8217;s London Show, which takes place at the Harrow District Masonic Centre on 25th October, and the first announcement from an exhibitor has already landed in the RISCOSitory bunker. In fact, the email arrived before last week&#8217;s post about the show, so keen was Paolo Zaino, the exhibitor in question, but I deliberately held it back so that it came after the show preview. Using the name ZFP Systems (the brand under which he originally provided professional services to retail outlets&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>It’s now just three weeks to go until this year’s London Show, which takes place at the Harrow District Masonic Centre on 25th October, and the first announcement from an exhibitor has already landed in the RISCOSitory bunker. In fact, the email arrived before last week’s post about the show, so keen was Paolo Zaino, the exhibitor in question, but I deliberately held it back so that it came after the show preview. Using the name ZFP Systems (the brand under which he originally provided professional services to retail outlets…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.riscository.com/?p=10729</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Looking Glass Half Empty, Part 1: Just Lookin’ for a Hit</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/10/a-looking-glass-half-empty-part-1-just-lookin-for-a-hit/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This article tells part of the story of Looking Glass Studios. There was some discussion about it: &#8220;Wow, gosh, it&#8217;d sure be nice if we were making more money and selling more copies so we could do crazy games of the type we want, as opposed to having to worry about how we&#8217;re going to [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>This article tells part of the story of Looking Glass Studios. There was some discussion about it: “Wow, gosh, it’d sure be nice if we were making more money and selling more copies so we could do crazy games of the type we want, as opposed to having to worry about how we’re going to \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.filfre.net/?p=6497</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>RPNV Calculator v1.0.0</title>
      <link>https://sourceforge.net/p/freedos/news/2025/10/rpnv-calculator-v100/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="markdown_content"><p>RPNV is an RPN calculator inspired by HP Voyager calculator series, in particular the HP-10C. Davide writes "After a few months of fun I've reached a milestone and I've released a full version implementing all the functions of the HP-10C calculator including programming capability." This implements the HP-10C calculator, including 4-level stack (x,y,z,t registers), the last-x register, 10 memory registers (0 to 9), all the basic operations, and up to 99 programming instructions. You can download version 1.0.0 from <a class="" href="https://github.com/Dave1975-spring/RPNV_Calculator" rel="nofollow">RPNV at GitHub</a>.</p></div>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>RPNV is an RPN calculator inspired by HP Voyager calculator series, in particular the HP-10C. Davide writes &#34;After a few months of fun I&#39;ve reached a milestone and I&#39;ve released a full version implementing all the functions of the HP-10C calculator including programming capability.&#34; This implements the HP-10C calculator, including 4-level stack (x,y,z,t registers), the last-x register, 10 memory registers (0 to 9), all the basic operations, and up to 99 programming instructions. You can download version 1.0.0 from [RPNV at GitHub](https://github.com/Dave1975-spring/RPNV_Calculator).</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sourceforge.netf116d8fa63792fe91e34df96095d7daf09365d56</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Versions of the KIM-1 User Manual</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/versions-of-the-kim-1-user-manual/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I have so far found 5 versions of the KIM-1 User Manual. First Edition January 1976 Second Edition March 1976 Second Edition August 1976 Rockwell branded version 1977. German version 1977 Only small updates, some errors, and the change of keyboard with SST switch right to left. All available here: KIM-1 manuals and MOS Technology [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>I have so far found 5 versions of the KIM-1 User Manual. First Edition January 1976 Second Edition March 1976 Second Edition August 1976 Rockwell branded version 1977. German version 1977 Only small updates, some errors, and the change of keyboard with SST switch right to left. All available here: KIM-1 manuals and MOS Technology \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=18901</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>FDNPKG16 version 0.99.81</title>
      <link>https://sourceforge.net/p/freedos/news/2025/10/fdnpkg16-version-0998/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="markdown_content"><p>Developer sparky4 has been working on an updated version of the FDNPKG package manager. The new version is aimed at 16-bit, and works on an 8088 system now. The new version retries re-fetching files it couldn't download on the first attempt, and has several other small improvements throughout the code. <em>Update:</em> FDNPKG16 version 0.99.81 has a new feature: you can use a short version of the command, with or without the slash, like "li" or "/li" to display the license. The license screen also includes my contact information. This also includes several bug fixes: one fixes a bug with watt32, and another avoids a 16-bit integer overflow. You can find the latest version at the <a class="" href="https://github.com/sparky4/fdnpkg16" rel="nofollow">FDNPKG16 repository</a> on GitHub.</p></div>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Developer sparky4 has been working on an updated version of the FDNPKG package manager. The new version is aimed at 16-bit, and works on an 8088 system now. The new version retries re-fetching files it couldn&#39;t download on the first attempt, and has several other small improvements throughout the code. _Update:_ FDNPKG16 version 0.99.81 has a new feature: you can use a short version of the command, with or without the slash, like &#34;li&#34; or &#34;/li&#34; to display the license. The license screen also includes my contact information. This also includes several bug fixes: one fixes a bug with watt32, and another avoids a 16-bit integer overflow. You can find the latest version at the [FDNPKG16 repository](https://github.com/sparky4/fdnpkg16) on GitHub.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sourceforge.neta429e1e6a6522cf6eebbeecf352bbcf7b5efa581</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/10/02 - The radical left?</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251002</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The radical left?]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The radical left?</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20251002</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>DOS Game Club</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/10/dos-game-club/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I had a long talk recently with some nice folks at the DOS Game Club podcast. Our subject was one from the early days of this site, the Infocom game Planetfall. Maybe some of you will find it interesting. You can get it from the DOS Game Club homepage, or more than likely wherever you get [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>I had a long talk recently with some nice folks at the DOS Game Club podcast. Our subject was one from the early days of this site, the Infocom game Planetfall. Maybe some of you will find it interesting. You can get it from the DOS Game Club homepage, or more than likely wherever you get \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.filfre.net/?p=6511</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>WROCC October 2025 meeting - R-Comp and ROD Show teaser</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2239.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Wakefield's October speaker was Andrew Rawnsley from R-Comp, giving us some updates and teasers for the London Show (in case you need more reasons to attend the Show!)]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Wakefield&#39;s October speaker was Andrew Rawnsley from R-Comp, giving us some updates and teasers for the London Show (in case you need more reasons to attend the Show!)</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2239.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>jSH 0.98</title>
      <link>https://sourceforge.net/p/freedos/news/2025/10/jsh-098/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="markdown_content"><p>jSH is a Javascript scripting engine for DOS, with a focus on file i/o and text mode user interfaces.  Version 0.98 is a minor update that includes updated versions of mbedTLS and curl. You can download the new version from <a class="" href="https://github.com/SuperIlu/jSH" rel="nofollow">jSH at GitHub</a></p></div>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>jSH is a Javascript scripting engine for DOS, with a focus on file i/o and text mode user interfaces. Version 0.98 is a minor update that includes updated versions of mbedTLS and curl. You can download the new version from [jSH at GitHub](https://github.com/SuperIlu/jSH)</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://sourceforge.net20f837586a8b2220e024aa48738f71544a8f15f9</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>More Memory? GIM’m’E!</title>
      <link>https://www.go4retro.com/2025/09/30/more-memory-gimme/?utm_source=rss&#38;utm_medium=rss&#38;utm_campaign=more-memory-gimme</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[With the introduction of the TANDY Color Computer (CoCo) 3, engineers were faced with 2 significant and implied mutually exclusive goals: To satisfy both of these goals, the CoCo 3 consolidated the MC6883/74LS783 Synchronous Address Multiplexer (SAM) and the MC6847 Video Display Generator (VDG) into a single Application Specific integrated Circuit (ASIC) while adding additional &#8230; <a href="https://www.go4retro.com/2025/09/30/more-memory-gimme/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">More Memory? GIM&#8217;m&#8217;E!</span></a>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>With the introduction of the TANDY Color Computer (CoCo) 3, engineers were faced with 2 significant and implied mutually exclusive goals: To satisfy both of these goals, the CoCo 3 consolidated the MC6883/74LS783 Synchronous Address Multiplexer (SAM) and the MC6847 Video Display Generator (VDG) into a single Application Specific integrated Circuit (ASIC) while adding additional … [Continue reading More Memory? GIM’m’E!](https://www.go4retro.com/2025/09/30/more-memory-gimme/)</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.go4retro.com/?p=1861</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Linux Kernel 6.17 is Available</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Linux-Kernel-6.17-is-Available</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Linus Torvalds has announced that the latest kernel has been released with plenty of core improvements and even more hardware support.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Linus Torvalds has announced that the latest kernel has been released with plenty of core improvements and even more hardware support.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://63d00452a5ec3a0431c3a90b3a9a5dc9</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>WROCC October 2025 talk on Wednesday - R-Comp</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2232.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The October 2025 WROCC talk is on Wednesday 1st October and starts at at 7.45pm on Zoom.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The October 2025 WROCC talk is on Wednesday 1st October and starts at at 7.45pm on Zoom.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2232.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/09/28 - The parcel that eventually was, Ghosts, Ghosts (the other kind), Google and the enshittification of the web.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250928</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The parcel that eventually was, Ghosts, Ghosts (the other kind), Google and the enshittification of the web.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The parcel that eventually was, Ghosts, Ghosts (the other kind), Google and the enshittification of the web.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250928</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>London Show 2025 – just four weeks to go</title>
      <link>https://www.riscository.com/2025/london-show-four-weeks/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Today is Saturday, 27th September, 2025, and I&#8217;ve scheduled this post to appear at 11:00am &#8211; which means at the time this article appears it will be precisely four weeks to the minute until the doors are open to the public on the 2025 RISC OS London Show, which takes place on Saturday, 25th October. The precise details you need, as a discerning RISC OS user and show visitor, are: Harrow District Masonic Centre,Northwick Circle,Kenton,Harrow,HA3 0EL. The venue has ample (and free) parking for visitors making the trip by car,&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Today is Saturday, 27th September, 2025, and I’ve scheduled this post to appear at 11:00am – which means at the time this article appears it will be precisely four weeks to the minute until the doors are open to the public on the 2025 RISC OS London Show, which takes place on Saturday, 25th October. The precise details you need, as a discerning RISC OS user and show visitor, are: Harrow District Masonic Centre,Northwick Circle,Kenton,Harrow,HA3 0EL. The venue has ample (and free) parking for visitors making the trip by car,…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.riscository.com/?p=10718</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This Week on The Analog Antiquarian</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/09/this-week-on-the-analog-antiquarian/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Chapter 4: The Man Who Saw Infinity]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Chapter 4: The Man Who Saw Infinity</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.filfre.net/?p=6510</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Latest news from R-Comp: WROCC meeting, 1st October</title>
      <link>https://www.riscository.com/2025/latest-news-r-comp-wrocc-1st-october/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Wakefield RISC OS Computer Club (WROCC) will be holding their next meeting on Wednesday, 1st October, with Andrew Rawnsley taking centre stage to bring the group up to date with all things R-Comp. Andrew will bring the group up to date with all the latest developments at R-Comp and RCI, and with the London Show (at the time of the meeting) just three and a half weeks away, there&#8217;s a chance he may be able to share some details or sneak peaks of new releases for the event. He&#8230;]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The Wakefield RISC OS Computer Club (WROCC) will be holding their next meeting on Wednesday, 1st October, with Andrew Rawnsley taking centre stage to bring the group up to date with all things R-Comp. Andrew will bring the group up to date with all the latest developments at R-Comp and RCI, and with the London Show (at the time of the meeting) just three and a half weeks away, there’s a chance he may be able to share some details or sneak peaks of new releases for the event. He…</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://www.riscository.com/?p=10725</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Rockwell KIM-1, myth or?</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/the-rockwell-kim-1-myth-or/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Was there a Rockwell KIM-1? A myth or? Yes and no. There is a KIM-1 packaged and sold by Rockwell in 1977. I bought one in 1977. No, it is a MOS Technology produced KIM-1 PCB. Yes, Rockwell added documents with Rockwell title pages and contents 99% written by MOS Technology. The Rockwell KIM-1 is [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Was there a Rockwell KIM-1? A myth or? Yes and no. There is a KIM-1 packaged and sold by Rockwell in 1977. I bought one in 1977. No, it is a MOS Technology produced KIM-1 PCB. Yes, Rockwell added documents with Rockwell title pages and contents 99% written by MOS Technology. The Rockwell KIM-1 is \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=18893</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>September 2025 News Summary</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2233.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Some things we noticed this month. What did you see?]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Some things we noticed this month. What did you see?</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2233.html</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/09/25 - The parcel that was.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250925</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The parcel that was.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The parcel that was.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250925</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Kali Linux 2025.3 Released with New Hacking Tools</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Kali-Linux-2025.3-Released-with-New-Hacking-Tools</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>If you're a Kali Linux fan, you'll be glad to know that the third release of this famous pen-testing distribution is now available with updates for key components.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>If you&#39;re a Kali Linux fan, you&#39;ll be glad to know that the third release of this famous pen-testing distribution is now available with updates for key components.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://ee8ffdb57df6408ab9f7f652d10d03eb</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Lightweight Authentication Schema</title>
      <link>https://www.c64os.com/post/lightweightauthentication</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<img src='https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.c64os.resources/weblog/lightweightauthentication/icon-lightweightauthentication.jpg'> This post is basically a white paper, but it's in a non-formal blog post style. I've been working on a new Application for C64 OS that makes use of networking. I've got a long list of Apps and Utilities that I'd love to have on the platform, but I have to prioritize the one I think will be most useful to have first. For now, until I get further along and decide to share some details, I'm keeping the App a secret. But suffice it to say that, as with many online services, you need to authenticate yourself somehow and preferably share some account profile details, like your name and maybe your country, and perhaps your email address. Authentication by a C64 OS Application or Utility to a network service is a tricky problem. It isn't just one problem but a collection of several different problems that all need to be solved in an elegant way. And it is that elegant solution that I've been daydreaming about. I think I have a pretty nice schema and I've been testing it with real code to make . . .]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>![](https://s3.amazonaws.com/com.c64os.resources/weblog/lightweightauthentication/icon-lightweightauthentication.jpg) This post is basically a white paper, but it&#39;s in a non-formal blog post style. I&#39;ve been working on a new Application for C64 OS that makes use of networking. I&#39;ve got a long list of Apps and Utilities that I&#39;d love to have on the platform, but I have to prioritize the one I think will be most useful to have first. For now, until I get further along and decide to share some details, I&#39;m keeping the App a secret. But suffice it to say that, as with many online services, you need to authenticate yourself somehow and preferably share some account profile details, like your name and maybe your country, and perhaps your email address. Authentication by a C64 OS Application or Utility to a network service is a tricky problem. It isn&#39;t just one problem but a collection of several different problems that all need to be solved in an elegant way. And it is that elegant solution that I&#39;ve been daydreaming about. I think I have a pretty nice schema and I&#39;ve been testing it with real code to make . . .</source:markdown>
      <author>gregorynacu@me.com (Gregory Nacu)</author>
      <guid>cid://https://www.c64os.com/post?p=132</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/09/24 - The parcel that never was, Finally my autism has been explained!</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250924</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The parcel that never was, Finally my autism has been explained!]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The parcel that never was, Finally my autism has been explained!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250924</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Zorin OS 18 Beta Available for Testing</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Zorin-OS-18-Beta-Available-for-Testing</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The latest release from the team behind Zorin OS is ready for public testing, and it includes plenty of improvements to make it more powerful, user-friendly, and productive.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The latest release from the team behind Zorin OS is ready for public testing, and it includes plenty of improvements to make it more powerful, user-friendly, and productive.</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://cc07138f0fcae08f24de6c2aea9efdda</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/09/22 - No promises.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250922</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[No promises.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>No promises.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250922</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/09/21 - Time wasted on dumb things, Mower Racing and Made Of Fail, A gentle walk, The price of tea.</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250921</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Time wasted on dumb things, Mower Racing and Made Of Fail, A gentle walk, The price of tea.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Time wasted on dumb things, Mower Racing and Made Of Fail, A gentle walk, The price of tea.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250921</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>MCS6500 Family Hardware manual 6500-10 and Programming Manual Synertek 6500-50 added</title>
      <link>http://retro.hansotten.nl/mcs6500-family-hardware-manual-6500-10-and-programming-manual-synertek-6500-50-added/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[New good quality scans added to the Manuals page &#8211; MCS6500 Hardware Manual August 1975 First Edition, Version 6500-10, with errata letter. Not the usual 6500-10A but the rare first edition. No ROR instruction documented! &#8211; MCS6500 Programming Manual by Synertek, version 6500-50. Not the First Edition alas, the contents are the 6500-50A version. I [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>New good quality scans added to the Manuals page – MCS6500 Hardware Manual August 1975 First Edition, Version 6500-10, with errata letter. Not the usual 6500-10A but the rare first edition. No ROR instruction documented! – MCS6500 Programming Manual by Synertek, version 6500-50. Not the First Edition alas, the contents are the 6500-50A version. I \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://retro.hansotten.nl/?p=18850</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Fedora Linux 43 Beta Now Available for Testing</title>
      <link>http://www.linux-magazine.com/Online/News/Fedora-Linux-43-Beta-Now-Available-for-Testing</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Fedora Linux 43 Beta ships with Gnome 49 and KDE Plasma 6.4 (and other goodies).</p>]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Fedora Linux 43 Beta ships with Gnome 49 and KDE Plasma 6.4 (and other goodies).</source:markdown>
      <author>webdevel@sparkhausmedia.com (Gwen Clark)</author>
      <guid>cid://f2de27ed096fbe72ecc6db0d5fa5d114</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Outcast</title>
      <link>https://www.filfre.net/2025/09/outcast/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[As longtime readers of these histories know already, I&#8217;ve never been overly enamored with the so-called &#8220;French Touch&#8221; in vintage computer games, that blending of elevated aesthetic and thematic aspirations &#8212; some might prefer to use the word &#8220;pretensions&#8221; &#8212; with a, shall we say, less thoroughgoing commitment to the details of gameplay and mechanics. [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>As longtime readers of these histories know already, I’ve never been overly enamored with the so-called “French Touch” in vintage computer games, that blending of elevated aesthetic and thematic aspirations — some might prefer to use the word “pretensions” — with a, shall we say, less thoroughgoing commitment to the details of gameplay and mechanics. \[…\]</source:markdown>
      <enclosure url="https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/outcast.mp3" length="11103209" type="audio/mpeg" />
      <enclosure url="https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/outtake.mp4" length="811768" type="video/mp4" />
      <enclosure url="https://www.filfre.net/wp-content/uploads/2025/09/outcast.mp4" length="3905373" type="video/mp4" />
      <guid>cid://https://www.filfre.net/?p=6480</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>b.log 2025/09/18 - Free speech?, Gameboy Advance, The Great Strike!</title>
      <link>https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250918</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Free speech?, Gameboy Advance, The Great Strike!]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>Free speech?, Gameboy Advance, The Great Strike!</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://https://heyrick.eu/blog/entry/20250918</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>September developer &#39;fireside&#39; chat on saturday night</title>
      <link>http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2235.html</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The nights are definitely drawing in now. So what better way to spend Saturday night than at next 'fireside' chat on saturday night (20th September). As usual, 7:30pm UK time kick-off and the event is on Zoom. Stay for as long or as short a time as you like.]]>
      </description>
      <source:markdown>The nights are definitely drawing in now. So what better way to spend Saturday night than at next &#39;fireside&#39; chat on saturday night (20th September). As usual, 7:30pm UK time kick-off and the event is on Zoom. Stay for as long or as short a time as you like.</source:markdown>
      <guid>cid://http://www.iconbar.com/comments/rss/news2235.html</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
