<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science and Technology</title>
    <lastBuildDate>2025-08-30 19:25:27</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.1</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Programmers: you have to watch your weight, too</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/30/programmers_watch_your_weight/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>We are drowning in code, but at least some folks are swimming</h4> <p><strong>opinion</strong>  To fight the enshittification of software, the first step is to pinpoint why and how it happens. Some observers are trying to do that.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241665</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-30T10:41:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Kilopixel creator kills livestream switch before woodblock display hits Crysis point</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/30/kilopixel_creator_switches_it_off/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>All good things must come to an end</h4> <p>All good things must come to an end, and so too must the blocky glory of the Kilopixel. As the wood and robotic marvel crested the 200,000-pixel mark, its creator pulled the metaphorical plug.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241629</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-30T07:31:11Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>It turns out Nokia’s legendary font makes for a great general user interface font</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143222/it-turns-out-nokias-legendary-font-makes-for-a-great-general-user-interface-font/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[If you&#8217;re of a certain age (and not American), there&#8217;s a specific corporate font you&#8217;re most likely aware of. You may not know its exact name, and you may not actively remember it, but once you see it, you know exactly what you&#8217;re looking at. The font&#8217;s called Nokia Sans (and Nokia Serif), and it was used by pretty much every single Nokia device between roughly 2002 and 2013 or so, when it was replaced by a very bland font made by Bruno Maag (with help from the person who designed Comic Sans) that they used after that. I can&#8217;t remember why, exactly, but I got majorly nostalgic for Nokia&#8217;s characteristic, recognisable font, and decided to see if it would work as a user interface font. Now, the font is still owned by Nokia and I couldn&#8217;t find a proper place to download it, but I eventually stumbled upon a site that had each individual variant listed for download. I downloaded each of them, installed them using KDE&#8217;s font installation method, and tried it out as my user interface font. You&#8217;ll quickly discover you shouldn&#8217;t use the regular variant, but should instead opt for the Nokia Sans Wide variant. Back in 2011, when Nokia originally announced it was replacing Nokia Sans, the creator of the font, Erik Spiekermann, responded to the announcement on his blog. Apparently, one of the major reasons for Nokia to change fonts was that they claimed Nokia Sans wouldn&#8217;t work as a user interface font, but Spiekermann obviously disagrees, pointing specifically to the Wide variant. In fact, Spiekermann does not pull any punches. After 10 years it was high time to look at Nokia’s typefaces as the dominant visual voice of the brand but whoever decided on a completely new direction was either not aware of what was available or was persuaded by Bruno Maag to start over. Bruno may not create the most memorable typefaces, but he certainly knows how to sell them. And technically, their fonts are excellent. Too bad they didn’t have the confidence to work with me on an update. Instead they’re throwing out ten years of brand recognition in favour of blandness. ↫ Erik Spiekermann I was pleasently surprised by just how nice the font looks when used as a general user interface font. It&#8217;s extremely legible at a variety of sizes, and has a ton of character without becoming gimmicky or overbearing. What originally started as mere curiosity has now become my UI font of choice on all my machines, finally displacing Inter after many years of uncontested service. Of course, all of this is deeply personal and 95% an issue of taste, but I wanted to write about it to see if I&#8217;m just entirely crazy, or if there&#8217;s some method to my madness. Do note that I&#8217;m using high DPI displays, and KDE on Wayland, and that all of this may look different on Windows or macOS, or on displays with lower DPI. One of Inter&#8217;s strengths is that it renders great on both high and lower DPI displays, but since I don&#8217;t have any lower DPI displays anymore, I can&#8217;t test it in such an environment. I&#8217;m also not entirely sure about the legal status of downloading fonts like this, but I am fairly sure you&#8217;re at least allowed to use non-free fonts for personal, non-commercial use, but please don&#8217;t quote me on that. Since downloading each variant of these Nokia fonts is annoying, I&#8217;d love to create and upload a zip file containing all of them, but I&#8217;m sure that&#8217;s illegal. I&#8217;m not a font connoisseur, so I may be committing a huge faux pas here? Not that I care, but reading about font nerds losing their minds over things I never even noticed is always highly entertaining.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143222</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T22:22:06Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Uncle Sam doesn&#39;t want Samsung, SK Hynix making memories in China</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/uncle_sam_doesnt_want_samsung/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>End of verified end user status means South Korean memory vendors will need licenses to bring restricted chipmaking tech into Chinese fabs</h4> <p>The US government already has a lot to say about what products chipmakers can and can&#39;t sell in China. This week the Commerce Department moved to make it harder for South Korean memory vendors Samsung and SK Hynix to continue manufacturing in the region.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241668</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T21:49:24Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How Much Can a Giant Waterlily Hold? See One Carry 183 Pounds Before Sinking, Winning a Social Media Contest</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/how-much-can-a-giant-waterlily-hold-see-one-carry-183-pounds-before-sinking-winning-a-social-media-contest-180987268/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Now in its third year, the Waterlily Weigh-Off invites public gardens and zoos to show off the strength of their aquatic plants]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/ed/bf/edbf11a0-be26-444e-aae2-2cd5c41a2b65/20250814_155406598_ios.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T21:09:15Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Researcher who found McDonald&#39;s free-food hack turns her attention to Chinese restaurant robots</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/pudu_robots_hackable/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>The controls were left wide open on Pudu&#39;s robots</h4> <p>A researcher caught the world’s leading supplier of commercial service robots using shoddy admin security that let attackers redirect the delivery machines to anywhere and make them follow any command.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241664</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T21:01:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Alibaba looks to end reliance on Nvidia for AI inference</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/china_alibaba_ai_accelerator/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Chinese cloud provider reportedly joins the homegrown silicon party</h4> <p>Alibaba has reportedly developed an AI accelerator amid growing pressure from Beijing to curb the nation&#39;s reliance on Nvidia GPUs. …</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241666</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T20:35:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>xAI&#39;s Grok has no place in US federal government, say advocacy groups</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/xais_grok_has_no_place/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Bias, a lack of safety reporting, and the whole &#39;MechaHitler&#39; thing are all the evidence needed, say authors</h4> <p>Public advocacy groups are demanding the US government cease any use of xAI&#39;s Grok in the federal government, calling the AI unsafe, untested, and ideologically biased.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241663</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T19:59:02Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Gun Linked to Emmett Till&#39;s Murder Is Now on Display at a Museum in Mississippi</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/the-gun-linked-to-emmett-tills-murder-is-now-on-display-at-a-museum-in-mississippi-180987266/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The weapon is thought to have belonged to J.W. Milam, one of the two men who kidnapped, tortured and killed the Black teenager for whistling at a white woman in a grocery store in 1955]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/q164-ySZgMHwgQRFAQvi0jGMM3E=/420x240/filters:focal(1024x575:1025x576)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/af/3c/af3c6334-d19e-4db1-8186-63a89327d794/539383389_1182039187292462_17200861569485898_n.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T19:53:39Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Blocky Planet: making Minecraft spherical</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143220/blocky-planet-making-minecraft-spherical/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Blocky Planet is a tech demo I created in the&#160;Unity game engine&#160;that attempts to map Minecraft’s cubic voxels onto a spherical planet. The planet is procedurally generated and fully destructible, allowing players to place or remove more than 20 different block types. While much of the implementation relies on common techniques you’d expect from your average Kirkland brand Minecraft clone, the spherical structure introduces a number of unique design considerations. This post will focus on these more novel challenges. ↫ Bowerbyte What a great read. Turning a &#8216;flat earth&#8217; game like Minecraft into something taking place on a spherical world seems impossible at first, but it seems Bowerbyte managed to do it. If you&#8217;ve ever wondered what it would be like to play a Minecraft-like game on an actual sphere, this is it.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143220</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T19:44:05Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Researchers Create Rechargeable, Glow-in-the-Dark Succulents</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/researchers-create-rechargeable-glow-in-the-dark-succulents-180987265/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The team hopes their work, which is still in the early phases, might one day build the foundation for a novel sustainable lighting system]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/lUBw-y4m9eGlLSs6wVEAHnXEFBQ=/420x240/filters:focal(350x210:351x211)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/e2/a7/e2a73750-beea-4bd1-b993-bcc565792f8d/low-res_1_1.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T19:42:50Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>America&#39;s Largest-Ever Exhibition on Raphael Will Open at the Met Next Year</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/anericas-largest-ever-exhibition-on-raphael-will-open-at-the-met-next-year-180987252/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[More than 200 of the Renaissance master's works will be on display in the landmark show, which debuts in March 2026]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/L36IyHTQj9duP2dmbkHuuyVlRP8=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/d5/60/d560a5cb-481f-4625-8dc5-9b4c30e5fae3/raphael.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T18:24:52Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>AMD Ryzen CPUs fry twice in the face of heavy math load, GMP says</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/amd_ryzen_twice_fails_in/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>GMP library test meltdown has AMD looking for answers</h4> <p>Chipmaker AMD is looking into a report from the GMP project about two Ryzen processors that failed during testing. Could too much math be to blame?…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241662</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T18:16:22Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Astronomers Spot a Rare Quadruple Star System in the Milky Way, Shedding Light on Mysterious Brown Dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/astronomers-spot-a-rare-quadruple-star-system-in-the-milky-way-shedding-light-on-mysterious-brown-dwarfs-180987241/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The discovery can help astronomers better understand these little-known objects nicknamed “failed stars”]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/MSU7W2HtuDVyz_jQ7TQAMaocSrM=/420x240/filters:focal(1200x903:1201x904)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/35/61/3561667c-29ec-4def-baf3-1a08c7a9bba2/rare-quadruple-star-sy.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T18:05:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>AI web crawlers are destroying websites in their never-ending hunger for any and all content</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/ai_web_crawlers_are_destroying/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>But the cure may ruin the web....</h4> <p><strong>Opinion</strong>  With AI&#39;s rise, AI web crawlers are strip-mining the web in their perpetual hunt for ever more content to feed into their Large Language Model (LLM) mills. How much traffic do they account for? According to <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/" rel="nofollow">Cloudflare</a>, a major content delivery network (CDN) force, <a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/from-googlebot-to-gptbot-whos-crawling-your-site-in-2025/" rel="nofollow">30% of global web traffic now comes from bots.</a> Leading the way and growing fast? AI bots.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241660</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T17:45:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>AWS catches Russia&#39;s Cozy Bear clawing at Microsoft credentials</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/aws_catches_russias_apt29_trying/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Look who&#39;s visiting the watering hole these days</h4> <p>Amazon today said it disrupted an intel-gathering attempt by Russia&#39;s APT29 to trick Microsoft users into unwittingly granting the Kremlin-backed cyberspies access to their accounts and data.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241659</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T17:17:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>GitHub engineer claims team was &#39;coerced&#39; to put Grok into Copilot</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/github_deepens_ties_with_elon/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Platform&#39;s staffer complains security review was &#39;rushed&#39;</h4> <p>Microsoft-owned collaborative coding platform GitHub is deepening its ties with Elon Musk&#39;s xAI, bringing early access to the company&#39;s Grok Code Fast 1 large language model (LLM) into GitHub Copilot. However, a whistleblower has claimed that the rollout suffers from inadequate security testing and an engineering team operating under duress.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241651</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T16:45:14Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Oldest Known Fossil of an Armored Ankylosaur Is &#39;Far Weirder&#39; Than Paleontologists Expected</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/oldest-known-fossil-of-an-armored-ankylosaur-is-far-weirder-than-paleontologists-expected-180987258/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The 13-foot dinosaur, covered in long spikes fused into its bones, suggests ankylosaurs developed tail weapons 30 million years earlier than thought]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/NKE7ezqKHkcvTvNhyc554-K24rk=/420x240/filters:focal(960x494:961x495)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/a7/6e/a76edc1d-9693-422d-adc3-37f74d63ea00/spicomellus-dinosaur-reconstruction-full-width-matthew-dempseyjpgthumb19201920.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T16:31:00Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Pentagon ends Microsoft&#39;s use of China-based support staff for DoD cloud</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/pentagon_ends_microsofts_use_of/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>&#39;It blows my mind,&#39; says SecDef</h4> <p>The Pentagon has formally kiboshed Microsoft&#39;s use of China-based employees to support Azure cloud services deployed by US government agencies, and it&#39;s demanding Microsoft do more of its own digging to determine whether any sensitive data was compromised. …</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241656</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T16:16:14Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This Christian Cross Found in Abu Dhabi Illuminates the Lives of Monks Who Lived 1,400 Years Ago</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/this-christian-cross-found-in-abu-dhabi-illuminates-the-lives-of-monks-who-lived-1400-years-ago-180987248/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers discovered the intricately decorated artifact at an archaeological site near a seventh-century C.E. monastery on the island of Sir Bani Yas]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/9pVUMzy_rxu5Gcg232oMNGdaZWI=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/cb/d6/cbd6eb69-9473-4975-b6a6-b5c9dcd63cb6/cross.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T16:09:33Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Intel’s deal with Trump includes a penalty clause against selling off its fabs</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/intel_trump_deal_fab_selling_penalty/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>The $5.7B check has cleared, CFO says</h4> <p>Intel&#39;s agreement with the US government incudes a clause that would allow the feds to take an additional five percent stake in the chipmaker if it ceases to have a controlling share in its foundry business.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241657</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T15:55:03Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>FTC chair accuses Google of treating GOP&#39;s emails as spam</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/gmail_republican_email_spam/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Chocolate Factory says people keep marking them as such, so QED</h4> <p>The Trump administration has accused Google of discriminating against Republicans&#39; emails and warned that the tech giant could be in line for a crackdown.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241654</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T15:26:09Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NASA Astronaut Megan McArthur Retires</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-astronaut-megan-mcarthur-retires/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[NASA astronaut Megan McArthur has retired, concluding a career spanning more than two decades. A veteran of two spaceflights, McArthur logged 213 days in space, including being the first woman to pilot a SpaceX Dragon spacecraft and the last person to “touch” the Hubble Space Telescope with the space shuttle’s robotic arm. McArthur launched as [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?post_type=press-release&p=907035</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T15:21:40Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Landsat 9 Sees Buccaneer Archipelago</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/image-article/landsat-9-sees-buccaneer-archipelago/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Operational Land Imager on&#160;Landsat 9&#160;captured this image of Buccaneer Archipelago on June 11, 2025.&#160;The scene encapsulates the striking interactions between land and water in the area where King Sound opens to the Indian Ocean. The powerful tidal currents stir up sediment in shallow areas, producing the beautiful turquoise swirls visible in this image. This [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?post_type=image-article&p=906166</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T15:08:27Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>RefreshOS 2.5: The Debian remix that borrows from every desk in the house</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/refreshos_25/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>A remarkable mixture of different components, but it works</h4> <p>RefreshOS is a Debian and KDE-based distro with a difference: it casts its net a lot wider for tools and components.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241633</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T14:44:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>30 years later, Doom returns to SNES with Raspberry Pi RP2350 muscle</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/30_years_snes_doom/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Limited Run Games swaps in silicon to emulate Super FX chip and hit 20 fps</h4> <p>Forget Windows 95, it&#39;s 30 years since Doom was released on the Super Nintendo Entertainment System. And thanks to the Raspberry Pi RP2350 microcontroller, the game is back in cartridge form.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241652</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T13:44:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Hubble Homes in on Galaxy’s Star Formation</title>
      <link>https://science.nasa.gov/missions/hubble/hubble-homes-in-on-galaxys-star-formation/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This NASA/ESA Hubble Space Telescope image features a galaxy whose asymmetric appearance may be the result of a galactic tug of war. Located 35 million light-years away in the constellation Leo, the spiral galaxy Messier 96 is the brightest of the galaxies in its group. The gravitational pull of its galactic neighbors may be responsible […]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://science.nasa.gov/missions/hubble/hubble-homes-in-on-galaxys-star-formation/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T13:43:32Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Enterprise password management outfit Passwordstate patches Emergency Access bug</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/enterprise_password_management_outfit_passwordstate/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Up to 29,000 organizations and potentially 370,000 security and IT pros affected</h4> <p>Australian development house Click Studios has warned users of its Passwordstate enterprise password management platform to update immediately if not sooner, following the discovery of an authentication bypass vulnerability that opens the doors to an emergency administration account with nothing more than a &#34;carefully crafted URL.&#34;…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241646</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T13:13:49Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>HP bottom line fattens up on a diet of AI PCs and Windows 11</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/hp_ai_pc_windows_11/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Nobody knows why they need one, but folk seem to be buying them</h4> <p>HP says AI PCs now make up a quarter of its sales, boosting revenue thanks to their higher price tags and the Windows 11 refresh.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241648</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T12:34:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>UK government dragged for incomplete security reforms after Afghan leak fallout</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/uk_government_breach_review/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Senior officials summoned to science and tech committee to explain further</h4> <p>Senior officials are being summoned to the UK&#39;s Science, Innovation and Technology Committee to explain why the government has not fully implemented the security recommendations made in a secret review following the 2021 Afghan data breach.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241649</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T11:45:10Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Windows Mobile Plans app to be disconnected in 2026</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/windows_mobile_plans/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Microsoft shifts cellular management to Settings and the web</h4> <p>Microsoft is to permanently hang up on its Mobile Plans app, directing users to the web and the Windows Settings app in the future.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241645</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T11:05:10Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>UK datacenter developers turn to gas rather than wait for grid power for builds</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/uk_dc_gas_install/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Hang on, what happened to gov.UK&#39;s bitbarn-favoring Industrial Strategy?</h4> <p>Datacenter developers in the UK are turning to gas for power generation amid lengthy wait times for a connection to the electricity grid.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241619</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T10:08:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How Windows 11 is breaking from its bedrock and moving away</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/opinion_windows_11/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>The once mighty Wintel supercontinent is cracking in more ways than you might think</h4> <p><strong>Opinion</strong>  Say what you like about its role in the destruction of civilization, the net is still good for a few party games. Take bets on when the &#34;Wintel Empire&#34; was first reported as under attack, and by what. Then go and find out.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241586</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T09:33:14Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Cloud computing has become so normal, it&#39;s invisible</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/cloud_computing/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Maybe someday we&#39;ll just call it &#39;data processing&#39; again</h4> <p><strong>Feature</strong>  In IT, terms and categories come and go. Distinctions disappear as computing evolves and as something that was shiny and new simply becomes the way that we do things.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241602</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T08:36:14Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Techie fooled a panicked daemon and manipulated time itself to get servers in sync</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/on_call/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Network Time Protocol sometimes needs help from a temporal cops</h4> <p><strong>On Call</strong>  Why, look at the time! 7:30 AM on Friday morning, the moment at which <em>The Register</em> regularly runs a fresh instalment of On Call, the reader-contributed column that shares your finest tech support stories.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241585</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T07:30:10Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>China turns on giant neutrino detector that took a decade to build</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/china_turns_on_giant_neutrino/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>700 meters under a mountain, a 20,000-tonne detector and a giant sphere await elusive particles</h4> <p>More than a decade after construction began, China has commenced operation of what it claims is the world’s most sensitive neutrino detector.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241643</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T06:30:11Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>China’s KylinOS Linux takes a great leap forward to v11 and kernel 6.6</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/29/kylinos_11/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Supports several Chinese chips and GPUs – and of course it has AI inside</h4> <p>China’s KylinSoft has delivered a major update to its flagship Linux, which Beijing hailed as a great leap forward for the nation’s ambition to develop operating systems that match and exceed the capabilities of western products.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241644</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T04:26:12Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Quiet Revolution: GNU/Linux Crosses 6% Desktop Market Share—And It’s Just the Beginning</title>
      <link>https://puri.sm/posts/the-quiet-revolution-gnu-linux-crosses-6-desktop-market-share-and-its-just-the-beginning/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>For decades, the phrase “Year of the Linux Desktop” has been tossed around like a tech industry punchline. But now, it’s no longer a meme—it’s a movement. According to the U.S. government’s own analytics, GNU/Linux has officially crossed the 6% threshold in desktop usage. That’s not hype. That’s hard data.</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/posts/the-quiet-revolution-gnu-linux-crosses-6-desktop-market-share-and-its-just-the-beginning/">The Quiet Revolution: GNU/Linux Crosses 6% Desktop Market Share—And It’s Just the Beginning</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://puri.sm/?p=84000</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-29T01:21:31Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>FBI cyber cop: Salt Typhoon pwned &#39;nearly every American&#39;</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/fbi_cyber_cop_salt_typhoon/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Plus millions of other people across 80+ countries</h4> <p>China&#39;s Salt Typhoon cyberspies hoovered up information belonging to millions of people in the United States over the course of the years-long intrusion into telecommunications networks, according to a top FBI cyber official.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241642</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T23:59:11Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Older developers are down with the vibe coding vibe</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/older_developers_ai_code/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>They use AI more but also check it more</h4> <p>For those who thought AI vibe coding was just for the youngsters, newly published research shows that developers with over 10 years of experience are more than twice as likely to do it.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241641</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T23:31:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Microsoft unveils home-made ML models amid OpenAI negotiations</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/microsoft_unveils_housemade_models_amid/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Microsoft AI honcho insists partnership with Sam Altman&#39;s brainbox behemoth is alive and well</h4> <p>Microsoft has introduced two home-grown machine learning models, potentially complicating negotiations with its current favored model supplier, OpenAI.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241640</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T22:42:16Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Genode OS Framework 25.08 released</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143214/genode-os-framework-25-08-released/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Genode 25.08 is ripe with deeply technical topics that have been cooking since the beginning of the year or even longer. In particular our new kernel scheduler as the flagship feature of this release has been in the works since February 2024. Section&#160;Kernel scheduling for fairness and low latency&#160;tells its background story and explains the approach taken. Another culmination of a long-term endeavor is the introduction of an alternative to XML syntax, specifically designed for the usage patterns of Genode and Sculpt OS. Section&#160;Consideration of a lean alternative to XML&#160;kicks off the practical evaluation of an idea that gradually evolved over more than two years. Also the holistic storage optimizations presented in Section&#160;Block-storage stack renovations&#160;are the result of careful long-term analysis, planning, and execution. ↫ Genode 25.08 release notes While these are the three tentpole features for this release, there&#8217;s a whole lot more here, as well. Genode&#8217;s Linux-based PC device drivers have all been updated to Linux 6.12, there are a ton of fixes related to USB, optional EFI boot support in VirtualBox 6, and tons more.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143214</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T21:31:37Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Five years – that&#39;s how long Anthropic will store Claude chats unless you opt out</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/anthropic_five_year_data_retention/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>My brain hurts a lot</h4> <p>Claude creator Anthropic has given customers using its Free, Pro, and Max plans one month to prevent the engine from storing their chats for five years by default and using them for training.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241638</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T21:31:09Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Elusive Sailback Houndshark Rediscovered in Papua New Guinea After 50 Years</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/elusive-sailback-houndshark-rediscovered-in-papua-new-guinea-after-50-years-180987260/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The creatures are occasionally caught by local fishermen but hadn’t been scientifically recorded since the 1970s]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/TZeWm31W3tJoGHLq56ihjVzBTIE=/420x240/filters:focal(257x181:258x182)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/ca/4f/ca4fb2bf-8fcb-4093-a4a3-3df4792e2af7/screenshot_2025-08-28_at_110504am.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T21:29:29Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>DOGE delayed deals, says Nutanix</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/nutanix_q4_2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>But private cloud contender sees upside in its modernization mission</h4> <p>Donald Trump&#39;s DOGE cost-cutting unit has made it harder to do business with the US federal government, according to private cloud contender Nutanix.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241639</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T21:00:14Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NASA Awards Spaceflight Operations, Systems Organization Contract</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-awards-spaceflight-operations-systems-organization-contract/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[NASA has awarded ASCEND Aerospace &#38; Technology of Cape Canaveral, Florida, the Contract for Organizing Spaceflight Mission Operations and Systems (COSMOS), to provide services at the agency’s Johnson Space Center in Houston. The COSMOS is a single award, indefinite-delivery/indefinite-quantity contract valued at $1.8 billion that begins its five-year base period no earlier than Dec. 1, [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?post_type=press-release&p=906808</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T20:52:40Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The EU needs a corporate “open source contribution tax” to fund open source maintainers</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143211/the-eu-needs-a-corporate-open-source-contribution-tax-to-fund-open-source-maintainers/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Open source, the thing that drives the world, the thing Harvard says has an economic value of 8.8 trillion dollars (also a big number). Most of it is one person. And I can promise you not one of those single person projects have the proper amount of resources they need. If you want to talk about possible risks to your supply chain, a single maintainer that’s grossly underpaid and overworked. That’s the risk. The country they are from is irrelevant. ↫ Josh Bressers If the massive corporations that exploit the open source world for massive personal profit don&#8217;t want to contribute back, perhaps it&#8217;s time we start making them. I envision an European Economic Area-wide &#8220;open source contribution tax&#8221;, levied against any technology corporation operating within the European Economic Area, whether they actually make use of open source code or not, not entirely unlike how insurance works &#8211; you pay into it even if you don&#8217;t make any claims. Such tax could be based on revenue, number of users, or any combination thereof or other factors. The revenue from this open source contribution tax is put into an EEA-wide fund and redistributed to EEA-based open source maintainers in the form of a monetary subsidy. Such types of taxes and money redistribution frameworks already exist in virtually every country for a whole wide variety of purposes and in a wide variety of forms, both in non-commercial and commercial settings. While it may seem complicated at first, it really isn&#8217;t. The most difficult aspect is definitely figuring out who, exactly, would be eligible to receive the subsidy and how much, but that, too, is a question both governments and commercial entities answer every single day. No, it will never be perfect, and some people will receive a subsidy who shouldn&#8217;t, and some who should receive it will not, but if that&#8217;s a valid reason not to implement a tax like this, no tax or insurance should be implemented. The benefits are legion. Of course, there is the primary benefit of alleviating the thousands of open source maintainers who form the backbone of pretty much out entire digital infrastructure, which in and of itself should be reason enough. On top of that, it would also strengthen the open source world &#8211; on which, I wish to reiterate, our entire digital infrastructure is built &#8211; against the kind of infiltration we saw with XZ Utils. And to put another top on top of that, it would cement Europe, or the EEA more specifically, as the hub for open source development, innovation, and leadership, and would surely attract countless open source maintainers to relocate to Europe. In other words, it would serve the grander European ambition to become less dependent on the criminal behaviour US tech giants and the erratic behaviour of the US government. We can either wait indefinitely for those who exploit the free labour of open source maintainers to contribute, or we make them.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143211</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T20:52:34Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>vSphere upgrades are not near the top of VMware&#39;s to-do list</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/whats_next_vmware/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Nor is its Arm port</h4> <p>When VMware delivered its Cloud Foundation 9 suite in June, it marked the end of a two-year push to integrate its compute, storage, and networking products. What’s next for the Broadcom business unit? At the VMware Explore conference this week, <i>The Register</i> sniffed out a few other items on its to-do list.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241637</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T20:33:06Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Sharks&#39; Teeth Could Suffer Damage as Ocean Acidification Intensifies, Study Suggests</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/sharks-teeth-could-suffer-damage-as-ocean-acidification-intensifies-study-suggests-180987251/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Higher concentrations of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere are leading to a drop in ocean pH, a change that might eventually make it harder for sharks to eat their prey]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/qq3MJAf4OF3e_THsMcK4CNE--Zo=/420x240/filters:focal(960x640:961x641)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/fb/ce/fbceee08-3514-4deb-822d-beff79ad4fa1/cmelanopterus1_small.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T20:11:47Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>DHS says it needs $100M worth of counter-drone tech to protect America</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/dhs_100m_anti_drone_tech/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Our drones are OK, but those other drones?</h4> <p>The US Department of Homeland Security has revealed plans to spend more than $100 million on systems designed to take out hostile drones.  …</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241636</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T20:05:11Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NASA Invites Media to Learn About New Missions to Map Sun’s Influence</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-invites-media-to-learn-about-new-missions-to-map-suns-influence/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[NASA will hold a media teleconference at 12 p.m. EDT on Thursday, Sept. 4, to discuss the agency’s upcoming Sun and space weather missions, IMAP (Interstellar Mapping and Acceleration Probe) and Carruthers Geocorona Observatory. The two missions are targeting launch on the same rocket no earlier than Tuesday, Sept. 23. The IMAP mission will map [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?post_type=press-release&p=906659</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T19:44:27Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How a Spontaneous Food Fight Became La Tomatina, Spain&#39;s Annual Tomato-Throwing Festival</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/how-a-spontaneous-food-fight-became-la-tomatina-spains-annual-tomato-throwing-festival-180987257/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Thousands of people gathered in a small Spanish town this week for the event, which is celebrating its 80th anniversary]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/P2ZqMAKV2B8Mb3_2SB9z90eOTrA=/420x240/filters:focal(3000x1943:3001x1944)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/27/14/271476d2-e23e-46c2-a609-b9c075bb2c9e/gettyimages-2231600939.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T19:41:21Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Not in my browser! Vivaldi capo doubles down on generative AI ban</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/vivaldi_capo_doubles_down_on/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Web browsing belongs to the people, not the bots</h4> <p>Jon von Tetzchner, CEO of Norway-based browser maker Vivaldi, believes the tech industry&#39;s efforts to automate web browsing using generative AI models have gone too far.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241635</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T19:33:13Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>FBI, Dutch cops seize fake ID marketplace that sold identity docs for $9</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/fbi_dutch_cops_seize_veriftools/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>$6.4M VerifTools marketplace offline</h4> <p>The FBI and Dutch police today said that they seized two domains and a blog tied to VerifTools, an international criminal marketplace that sold identity documents for as little as $9.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241634</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T19:10:12Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How does China keep stealing our stuff, wonders DoD group responsible for keeping foreign agents out</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/how_does_china_keep_stealing/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>&#39;The homeland is no longer secure,&#39; says Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency leader</h4> <p>The Pentagon outfit responsible for preventing foriegn agents from infiltrating defense agencies says the US isn&#39;t doing a very good job of preventing state secrets from falling into Chinese hands.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241630</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T18:40:07Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>She Spent Three Weeks Digging for a Diamond for Her Engagement Ring—and Unearthed a 2.3-Carat Stunner</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/she-spent-three-weeks-digging-for-a-diamond-for-her-engagement-ring-and-unearthed-a-2-3-carat-stunner-180987254/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[When Micherre Fox and her boyfriend decided to get married, she flew to Crater of Diamonds State Park in Arkansas to search for the diamond herself]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/yF8mx_uMCCZdTW-CFLtLRXuabgM=/420x240/filters:focal(3000x2000:3001x2001)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/9a/53/9a53b92b-6b92-4c62-90da-f7fdd7239181/dsc_0779.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T18:33:38Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Dialing Earth: Skylo set to leapfrog T-Mobile and offer voice calls via satellite</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/skylo_satellite_voice_calls/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Only a few Android phones will be able to support the service</h4> <p>Users of Google Pixel and Samsung Galaxy phones could soon find themselves able to make voice calls via a satellite connection, if Skylo Technologies can get all its ducks in a row.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241626</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T18:13:05Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NASA Marsquake Data Reveals Lumpy Nature of Red Planet’s Interior</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/missions/insight/nasa-marsquake-data-reveals-lumpy-nature-of-red-planets-interior/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Rocky material that impacted Mars lies scattered in giant lumps throughout the planet’s mantle, offering clues about Mars’ interior and its ancient past. What appear to be fragments from the aftermath of massive impacts on Mars that occurred 4.5 billion years ago have been detected deep below the planet’s surface. The discovery was made thanks [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?p=906379</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T18:09:04Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NASA, International Astronauts to Address Students from New York</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/news-release/nasa-international-astronauts-to-address-students-from-new-york/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[NASA astronaut Jonny Kim and JAXA (Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency) astronaut Kimiya Yui will connect with students in New York as they answer prerecorded science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) questions aboard the International Space Station. The Earth-to-space call will begin at 9:20 a.m. EDT on Friday, Sept. 5, and will stream live on the [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?post_type=press-release&p=906540</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T17:56:26Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NASA Scientists Help Maryland County Plan to Beat Summer Heat Risks</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/earth/nasa-helps-md-county-beat-heat/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Thousands of Americans are impacted each summer by excessive heat and humidity, some suffering from heat-related illnesses when the body can’t cool itself down. Data from NASA satellites could help local governments reduce the sweltering risks, thanks to a collaboration between NASA scientists and officials in Prince George’s County, Maryland. The effort demonstrates how local [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?p=902620</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T17:31:58Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Whisper it: FFmpeg 8 can now subtitle your videos on the fly</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/ffmpeg_8_huffman/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Media multitool taps Vulkan for GPU encoding, adds VVC support, and dusts off some ancient formats</h4> <p>FFmpeg 8.0 brings GPU-accelerated video encoding via Vulkan – and can now subtitle your videos automatically using integrated speech recognition.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241627</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T17:29:12Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>AmiBrowser brings 21st century web to 20th century Amigas</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/amiga_web_browser_amibrowser/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Also, not one but two new models of the classic 1200</h4> <p>The new native 68K AmigaOS web browser leans on the machines&#39; underlying emulation system to offer modern facilities on a retro OS.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241604</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T17:03:13Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Early Humans Moved Stones Long Distances to Make Tools 600,000 Years Earlier Than Thought</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/early-humans-moved-stones-long-distances-to-make-tools-600000-years-earlier-than-thought-180987247/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new study takes another look at some of the oldest known stone tools and suggests their makers transported materials for up to eight miles]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/XFtlaWId5nb3yzNZX_CLWhuDCqQ=/420x240/filters:focal(2592x1728:2593x1729)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/60/5f/605fb4ed-5c1a-41f1-b4f2-c54d3c45fe35/b_-_nyayanga_ampitheater.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T16:55:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>&#39;It isn&#39;t designed to solve privacy concerns,&#39; Grafana CTO says of Bring Your Own Cloud</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/grafanas_tom_wilkie_interview/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Think BYOC will solve all your sovereignty and privacy worries? You might be missing the point</h4> <p><strong>INTERVIEW</strong>  Bring Your Own Cloud (BYOC) is a concept gaining traction as companies seek ways to resolve sovereignty and privacy issues, but its implementation can vary widely depending on interpretation.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241625</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T16:18:13Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>NASA’s Chandra Reveals Star’s Inner Conflict Before Explosion</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/missions/chandra/nasas-chandra-reveals-stars-inner-conflict-before-explosion/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The inside of a star turned on itself before it spectacularly exploded, according to a new study from NASA’s Chandra X-ray Observatory. Today, this shattered star, known as the Cassiopeia A supernova remnant, is one of the best-known, well-studied objects in the sky. Over three hundred years ago, however, it was a giant star on [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?p=906427</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T16:17:50Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Google and Zed push protocol to pry AI agents out of VS Code&#39;s clutches</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/google_zed_acp/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Because not every bot wants to live inside Microsoft&#39;s walled garden</h4> <p>Google and code editor company Zed Industries have introduced the Agent Client Protocol (ACP) as a standard way for AI agents to integrate with an IDE, with the idea that this will prevent developers getting locked into VS Code.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241623</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T15:34:12Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>SK Telecom walloped with $97M fine after schoolkid security blunders let attackers run riot</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/sk_telecom_regulator_fine/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Regulator points to lack of &#39;basic access controls&#39; between internet-facing systems, internal network</h4> <p>South Korea&#39;s privacy watchdog has slapped SK Telecom with a record ₩134.5 billion ($97 million) fine after finding that the mobile giant left its network wide open to hackers through a catalog of bungles.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241628</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T14:53:29Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Archaeologists Are Digging Up Scotland&#39;s Very First Outdoor Skatepark</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/archeologists-are-digging-up-scotlands-very-first-outdoor-skatepark-180987231/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Kelvin Wheelies skatepark, which hosted the country's first national skateboarding competition, has been buried under rubble for decades]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/azuBPotQMEfHQoXK3RVukngTYXk=/420x240/filters:focal(325x214:326x215)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/a5/be/a5be8545-2e61-43d3-90e8-a1c44ad747c5/media_1204410_smxx.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T14:52:28Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Firefly reckons thermal tweaks will stop next rocket tearing itself apart</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/firefly_alpha_clear_launch/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Company cleared to launch again after April failure</h4> <p>Firefly Aerospace has been given the green light to resume launches after its April failure.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241618</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T14:41:13Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Sudden Surges That Forge Evolutionary Trees</title>
      <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/the-sudden-surges-that-forge-evolutionary-trees-20250828/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[An updated evolutionary model shows that living systems evolve in a split-and-hit-the-gas dynamic, where new lineages appear in sudden bursts rather than during a long marathon of gradual changes.            <p>The post <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/the-sudden-surges-that-forge-evolutionary-trees-20250828/" target="_blank">The Sudden Surges That Forge Evolutionary Trees</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org" target="_blank">Quanta Magazine</a></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=153646</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T13:58:29Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>TransUnion admits 4.5M affected after third-party support app breached</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/transunion_support_app_breach/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Credit agency offers own services as compensation</h4> <p>Credit scoring and monitoring biz TransUnion says that it recently suffered a breach affecting nearly 4.5 million individuals.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241624</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T13:54:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This Is What Our Thumbs Say About Our Brains, in a Pattern That Holds True for Other Primates</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/this-is-what-our-thumbs-say-about-our-brains-in-a-pattern-that-holds-true-for-other-primates-180987250/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers have found a link between long thumbs and big brains, suggesting the two features evolved together]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/nFmgAALBU-SWAyZnMV4EcyRcCH0=/420x240/filters:focal(3680x2488:3681x2489)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/cb/23/cb23f2fe-7fcd-4e93-9022-010a371cdf8a/close-up-woman-s-hand-hitchhiking-countryside-road.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T13:39:15Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Thousands of Citrix NetScaler boxes still sitting ducks despite patches</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/thousands_of_citrix_netscaler_boxes/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Shadowserver counts more than 13,000 appliances still wide open – including thousands in US, Germany, and UK</h4> <p>Thousands of Citrix NetScaler appliances remain exposed to a trio of security flaws that the vendor patched this week, one of which is already being actively exploited in the wild.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241615</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T13:17:14Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Ransomware crooks knock Swedish municipalities offline for measly sum of $168K</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/sweden_council_ransomware/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Miljödata meltdown leaves 200 local authorities scrambling over 1.5 BTC</h4> <p>Sweden&#39;s municipal governments have been knocked offline after ransomware crooks hit IT supplier Miljödata, reportedly demanding the bargain-basement sum of $168,000.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241622</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T12:39:05Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>PureOS Crimson Development Report: July 2025</title>
      <link>https://puri.sm/posts/pureos-crimson-development-report-july-2025/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Welcome back!  In our last update, we mentioned a fix in pureos-meta for some missing essential system components.</p>
        <p>This seemed trivial at the time - just add the missing components.  However, when the fix went into review and we looked deeper, it turned out to be anything but trivial.</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/posts/pureos-crimson-development-report-july-2025/">PureOS Crimson Development Report: July 2025</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://puri.sm/?p=84155</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T12:18:53Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Good morning, Brit Xbox fans – ready to prove your age?</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/xbox_online_safety_act/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Microsoft blames incoming UK Online Safety Act, says you have until 2026</h4> <p>Microsoft has begun emailing users of its Xbox gaming platform with likely unwelcome news: users will need to verify their age if they want to keep access to the company&#39;s various social services, and it&#39;s blaming the UK Online Safety Act.…</p> <p><!--#include virtual='/data_centre/_whitepaper_textlinks_top.html' --></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241617</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T12:17:10Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Katie Bisci: Resourcing for Big Science</title>
      <link>https://www.nasa.gov/centers-and-facilities/goddard/katie-bisci-resourcing-for-big-science/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Deputy Project Manager for Resources &#8211; Goddard Space Flight Center How are you helping set the stage for the Roman mission? I’m a deputy project manager for resources on the Nancy Grace Roman Space Telescope team, sharing the role with Kris Steeley. Together, we oversee the business team, finance, outreach, scheduling, and more. I focus [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.nasa.gov/?p=899721</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T12:00:00Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Euro banks block billions in rogue PayPal direct debits after fraud glitch</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/euro_banks_block_paypal_direct_debits/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>US payments platform back in action, says it&#39;s informing affected customers</h4> <p>Shoppers and merchants in Germany found themselves dealing with billions of euros in frozen transactions this week, thanks to an apparent failure in PayPal&#39;s fraud-detection systems.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241620</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T11:41:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Law firm email blunder exposes Church of England abuse victim details</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/lawyer_coe_email_blunder/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Apology issued after names tied to redress scheme revealed in mass mailing</h4> <p>A London law firm leaked the details of nearly 200 people who requested to receive updates about the redress scheme set up for victims of abuse at the hands of the Church of England (CoE).…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241616</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T11:02:17Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>UK unions want &#39;worker first&#39; plan for AI as people fear for their jobs</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/uk_unions_want_worker_first/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>Labor group says new technologies could increase inequality if we&#39;re not careful</h4> <p><strong>AI-Pocalypse</strong>  Over half of the British public are worried about the impact of AI on their jobs, according to employment unions, which want the UK government to adopt a &#34;worker first&#34; strategy rather than simply allowing corporations to ditch employees for algorithms.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241593</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T10:20:06Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Wastewater monitoring project could catch next pandemic early, says health agency</title>
      <link>https://go.theregister.com/feed/www.theregister.com/2025/08/28/wastewater/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h4>UK starts early warning system combing through stuff that folks flush away</h4> <p>The UK Health Security Agency is looking to set up an early warning system ahead of future pandemics, launching a £1.3 million (around $1.75 million) program to identify &#34;cutting-edge technologies&#34; which could turn people&#39;s pee and poop into valuable data on the spread of viruses.…</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>tag:theregister.com,2005:story241589</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T09:33:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>In-application browsers: the worst erosion of user choice you haven’t heard of</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143207/in-application-browsers-the-worst-erosion-of-user-choice-you-havent-heard-of/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A long, long time ago, Android treated browser tabs in a very unique way. Individual tabs were were seen as &#8216;applications&#8217;, and would appear interspersed with the recent applications list as if they were, indeed, applications. This used to be one of my favourite Android features, as it made websites feel very well integrated into the overall user experience, and gave them a sense of place within your workflows. Eventually, though, Google decided to remove this unique approach, as we can&#8217;t have nice things and everything must be bland, boring, and the same, and now finding a website you have open requires going to your browser and finding the correct tab. More approachable to most people, I&#8217;d wager, but a reduction in usability, for me. I still mourn this loss. Similarly, we&#8217;ve seen a huge increase in the use of in-application browsers, a feature designed to trap users inside applications, instead of letting them freely explore the web the moment they click on a link inside an application. Application developers don&#8217;t want you leaving their application, so almost all of them, by default, will now open a webview inside the application when you click on an outbound link. For advertising companies, like Google and Facebook, this has the additional benefit of circumventing any and all privacy protections you may have set up in your browser, since those won&#8217;t apply to the webview the application opens. This sucks. I hate in-application browsers with a passion. Decades of internet use have taught me that clicking on a link means I&#8217;m opening a website in my browser. That&#8217;s what I want, that&#8217;s what I expect, and that&#8217;s how it should be. In-application webviews entirely break this normal chain of events; not because it improves the user experience, but because it benefits the bottom line of others. It&#8217;s also a massive security risk. Worst of all, this switch grants these apps the ability to spy and manipulate third-party websites. Popular apps like Instagram, Facebook Messenger and Facebook have all been caught injecting JavaScript via their in-app browsers into third party websites. TikTok was running commands that were essentially a keylogger. While we have no proof that this data was used or exfiltrated from the device, the mere presence of JavaScript code collecting this data combined with no plausible explanation is extremely concerning. ↫ Open Web Advocacy Open Web Advocacy has submitted a detailed and expansive report to the European Commission detailing the various issues with these in-application browsers, and suggests a number of remedies to strengthen security, improve privacy, and preserve browser choice. I hope this gets picked up, because in-application browsers are just another way in which we&#8217;re losing control over our devices.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143207</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T09:13:57Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Word to save new files on Microsoft’s servers by default</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143202/word-to-save-new-files-on-microsofts-servers-by-default/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[You already need custom scripts and third-party applications that make custom Windows ISOs to make installing Windows somewhat bearable &#8211; unless you enjoy spending hours manually disabling all the anti-user settings in Windows &#8211; and now there&#8217;s another setting to add to the massive, growing list of stuff you have to fix after setting up a new Windows installation. Microsoft has announced that Word will start saving every new file to OneDrive (or another provider if you&#8217;ve installed one) by default. We are modernizing the way files are created and stored in Word for Windows! Now you don’t have to worry about saving your documents: Anything new you create will be saved automatically to OneDrive or your preferred cloud destination. ↫ Raul Munoz on the Microsoft 365 Insider Blog There&#8217;s the usual spiel of how this is safer and supposedly more convenient, but I suspect the real reason Microsoft is doing this is listed right there at the end of the list of supposed benefits: this enables the use of Copilot&#8217;s &#8220;AI&#8221; features right from the beginning. In other words, by automatically saving your new Word documents to OneDrive by default, you&#8217;re giving Microsoft access to whatever you write for &#8220;AI&#8221; training purposes. The setting can be changed, but defaults matter and few people change them. It&#8217;s also possible to set another provider than OneDrive as your online storage, but again &#8211; defaults matter. In fact, I wouldn&#8217;t be surprised if few people will even realise their Word documents will be stored not on their local PC, but on Microsoft&#8217;s servers.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143202</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-28T08:23:45Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Seasonal Waves Could Reach Some of Easter Island&#39;s Massive Moai Statues by 2080, New Study Suggests</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/seasonal-waves-could-reach-some-of-easter-islands-massive-moai-statues-by-2080-new-study-suggests-180987245/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers warn that rising sea levels could cause flooding that will endanger the historically significant statues, which were created by the Rapa Nui people between roughly 1300 and 1600 C.E.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/SwKYE3LZeiOHdpsY0B7yXxOYL_o=/420x240/filters:focal(3680x2488:3681x2489)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/22/62/22622d26-0e59-4e9a-b6ec-e60a8666e980/ahutongariki15moais.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-27T20:18:59Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>See the Rare &#39;Electric Blue&#39; Lobster Found Off the Coast of Massachusetts</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/see-the-rare-electric-blue-lobster-found-off-the-coast-of-massachusetts-180987249/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Meet Neptune, an American lobster with a vibrantly colored shell that results from a genetic mutation affecting pigmentation]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/i7juW0IM5p3QW1qXapZzgAoS5s0=/420x240/filters:focal(550x367:551x368)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/9a/f9/9af9d94e-37aa-4813-aa3f-2132d6320092/082125_mm_neptune_006.webp" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-27T18:57:02Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Man Noticed a Strange Shape on Satellite Images. It Turned Out to Be a 138-Year-Old Shipwreck in Lake Michigan</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-man-noticed-a-strange-shape-on-satellite-images-it-turned-out-to-be-a-138-year-old-shipwreck-in-lake-michigan-180987237/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[While sailing through a heavy blanket of fog, the "Frank D. Barker" went off course and ran into a limestone outcropping in October 1887]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/69/bb/69bbc77c-4718-4852-b4f9-893a54bb5293/frank_d_barker_4_photo_credit_-_wisconsin_historical_society.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-27T18:45:09Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Want to See the Original Lyrics for &#39;Over the Rainbow&#39;? All You Need Is a Library Card</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/want-to-see-the-original-lyrics-for-over-the-rainbow-all-you-need-is-a-library-card-180987238/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Library of Congress has acquired a collection of musical manuscripts and other rare artifacts connected to "The Wizard of Oz"]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/H8bi6HUwce3cPL8TZ8gGXSNt1mI=/420x240/filters:focal(4096x2731:4097x2732)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/9a/82/9a827b0f-2f85-455c-9fcf-79d81db605a7/701721.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-27T17:07:58Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Astrophysicists Find No ‘Hair’ on Black Holes</title>
      <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/astrophysicists-find-no-hair-on-black-holes-20250827/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[According to Einstein’s theory of gravity, black holes have only a small handful of distinguishing characteristics. Quantum theory implies they may have more. Now an experimental search finds that any of this extra ‘hair’ has to be pretty short.            <p>The post <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/astrophysicists-find-no-hair-on-black-holes-20250827/" target="_blank">Astrophysicists Find No ‘Hair’ on Black Holes</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org" target="_blank">Quanta Magazine</a></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=153590</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-27T14:15:31Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Librem PQC Comms Server</title>
      <link>https://puri.sm/posts/introducing-the-librem-pqc-comms-server/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>SF, CA, US – Purism is excited to announce its <a href="https://puri.sm/products/librem-pqc-comms-server/">Librem PQC Comms Server</a>, encrypting data-in-transit (DIT) with post-quantum cryptography (PQC) according to the <a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/fips/203/final">NIST FIPS 203</a> standard. When bundled as a complete ecosystem with the <a href="https://puri.sm/products/liberty-phone/">Liberty Phone</a> or other Purism Products will also address data-at-rest (DAR) encrypted with PQC.</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/posts/introducing-the-librem-pqc-comms-server/">Introducing the Librem PQC Comms Server</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://puri.sm/?p=83993</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-27T11:44:55Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Dick Pick’s unique database operating system</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143184/dick-picks-unique-database-operating-system/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[We usually at least recognize old computer hardware and software names. But Asianmoetry taught us a new one: Pick OS. This 1960s-era system was sort of a database and sort of an operating system for big iron used by the Army. The request was for an English-like query language, and TRW assigned two guys, Don Nelson and Dick Pick, to the job. The planned query language would allow for things like “list the title, author, and abstract of every transportation system reference with the principal city ‘Los Angeles’.” This was GIM or generalized information management, and, in a forward-looking choice, it ran in a virtual machine. ↫ Al Williams at Hackaday The linked article is a short summary of a YouTube video by the YouTube channel Asianometry, which goes into a lot more detail about Pick OS, where it came from, what it can do, who the people involved were, and where Pick OS eventually ended up. I had never heard of this system before, and it&#8217;s easy to see why &#8211; not only was it used almost exclusively in vertically integrated complete solutions, it was also whitelabeled, so it existed under countless different names. Regardless, it seems the people who actually had to use it were incredibly enthusiastic about it, and to this day you can read new comments from people fondly remembering how easy to use it was. It has always been proprietary, and still is to this day, apparently owned by a company called Rocket Software, who don&#8217;t seem to actually be doing anything with it.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143184</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T21:28:30Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Last Known Surviving American Ace Pilot From World War II Dies at 103</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/last-known-surviving-american-ace-pilot-from-world-war-ii-dies-at-103-180987239/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Donald McPherson shot down five planes in the Pacific theater in the final years of the war, earning him the title of "ace"]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/imwYZ9xyuN-IGZkgV-kP9UCJbxE=/420x240/filters:focal(480x320:481x321)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/bb/4c/bb4c5d12-1665-4bb2-8e87-e295ff2f4f7c/top_photo-_donald_mcpherson_us_navy.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T21:08:50Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Guix gets a new Rust packaging model</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143182/guix-gets-a-new-rust-packaging-model/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[While Nix and NixOS get all the attention when it comes to declarative package management, there are other, competing implementations of the same general idea. Guix, developed as part of the GNU Project, was originally based on Nix, but grew into its own thing. The project recently announced a major change to how it packages Rust and its countless dependencies and optional &#8216;crates&#8217;. We have changed to a simplified Rust packaging model that is easier to automate and allows for modification, replacement and deletion of dependencies at the same time. The new model will significantly reduce our Rust packaging time and will help us to improve both package availability and quality. ↫ Hilton Chain at the Guix blog I hear people talk about Nix and NixOS all the time &#8211; I tried it myself, too, but I felt I was using an IBM z17 mainframe to watch a YouTube video &#8211; and in fact, Nix has kind of become a meme in and of itself, but you never hear people talk about Guix. With this being OSNews, I&#8217;m assuming there&#8217;s going to be people here using it, and I&#8217;m incredibly curious about your experiences. What are the features and benefits that make you use it? If you&#8217;re curious &#8211; the best way to try Guix is probably to install the GNU Guix System, the Linux distribution built around Guix and Shepard, GNU&#8217;s alternative init system. It&#8217;s available for i686, x86_64, ARMv7, and AArch64, and can be virtualised too, of course.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143182</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T20:45:43Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Migratory Flamingos Age Differently From Resident Ones, Offering a New Clue About Getting Old</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/migratory-flamingos-age-differently-from-resident-ones-offering-a-new-clue-about-getting-old-180987243/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new study of the pink birds in France finds that aging sets in later for flamingos that migrate, though they face higher mortality in early adulthood]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/4e/71/4e7128e0-9d5b-48f7-a74a-0121f3ad1e5d/flamants-roses-poussins-colonie-fangassiercharlotte-peerot_tdv.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T20:41:12Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Privacy Shield in the Wake of AT&#38;T Data Breaches</title>
      <link>https://puri.sm/posts/a-privacy-shield-in-the-wake-of-att-data-breaches/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Purism AweSIM: A Privacy Shield in the Wake of AT&#38;T Data Breaches AT&#38;T was found liable to pay customers an estimated $177M to resolve multiple lawsuits stemming from two separate data breaches – March 30 and July 12, 2024. Both breaches exposed huge amounts of Personal Identifiable Information (PII) to the public. These two breaches [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/posts/a-privacy-shield-in-the-wake-of-att-data-breaches/">A Privacy Shield in the Wake of AT&#038;T Data Breaches</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://puri.sm/?p=84140</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T19:55:51Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Researchers Develop a &#39;Superfood&#39; for Honeybees to Fight the Drastic Decline of Their Colonies</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/researchers-develop-a-superfood-for-honeybees-to-fight-the-drastic-decline-of-their-colonies-180987234/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Bees fed an enriched yeast supplement saw 15 times more of their larvae reach the developmental stage right before adulthood, according to a new study]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/twqNbHPZAR2nyRb-m8gFaWOQ0Qk=/420x240/filters:focal(2000x1343:2001x1344)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/3b/e0/3be08d1f-1302-4c03-99ce-014f7dc1c746/gettyimages-2153379415.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T19:16:11Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Ancient Statues Emerge From the Waters Off Egypt&#39;s Coast, Where They&#39;d Been Hiding  for Thousands of Years</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/ancient-statues-emerge-from-the-waters-off-egypts-coast-where-theyd-been-hiding-for-thousands-of-years-180987230/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Several large sculptures were among the trove of artifacts that divers recovered from the waters near Alexandria, Egypt. Officials say the site may have been an extension of the nearby city of Canopus]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/eGYimO0bvNkmZ2Dsweedx6x7nH0=/420x240/filters:focal(2751x1834:2752x1835)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/c0/21/c021e132-16dd-41e2-80d7-4f78a9e3ad56/gettyimages-2230468057.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T17:42:28Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Astronomers Spot the Brightest Fast Radio Burst Ever Detected and Observe Stars Around Its Origin for the First Time</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/astronomers-spot-the-brightest-fast-radio-burst-ever-detected-and-observe-stars-around-its-origin-for-the-first-time-180987233/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Using two telescopes, scientists were able to pinpoint the location of the fleeting phenomenon with surprising accuracy]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/JLvsSpFYqkEx6q1wgQCJvXxWHME=/420x240/filters:focal(3442x2261:3443x2262)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/84/f0/84f012ae-1454-4665-9553-f736cae7b321/chime_array_artist_rendition_high_res.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T17:39:19Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>COSMIC Alpha 7: Never Been Beta</title>
      <link>https://blog.system76.com/post/cosmic-alpha-7-never-been-beta</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Wrapping up COSMIC’s main features before the first beta release.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://images.prismic.io/blog-system76/aAlwmPIqRLdaBjDE_cosmicalpha7blogheader.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpg" />
      <guid>https://blog.system76.com/post/cosmic-alpha-7-never-been-beta</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T16:32:29Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The size of Adobe Reader installers through the years</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143180/the-size-of-adobe-reader-installers-through-the-years/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The following chart shows how the Adobe Reader installer has grown in size over the years. When possible, 64-bit versions of installers were used. ↫ Alexander Gromnitsky Disk space is cheap, sure, but this is insanity.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143180</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T14:40:36Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>“My OpenBSD home network setup”</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143177/my-openbsd-home-network-setup/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I recently moved to an area with more internet provider options, all of which were not satellite-based. This change allowed me leave my current provider (Starlink) and also freed my network from being locked behind CGNAT. The jump from ~150Mbps to 1Gbps has been fantastic, but the real benefit in this switch has been the ability to overhaul my home network setup. ↫ Bradley Taunt OpenBSD is generally the way to go for custom router setups, it seems, and if it wasn&#8217;t for my own full Ubiquiti setup, I&#8217;d definitely consider this too.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143177</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T14:35:05Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Reading for Pleasure Has Declined by a &#39;Deeply Concerning&#39; 40 Percent Over the Past Two Decades</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/reading-for-pleasure-has-declined-by-a-deeply-concerning-40-percent-over-the-past-two-decades-180987228/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Between 2003 and 2023, the proportion of Americans who read for fun on a given day has been steadily falling, a new study suggests]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/r4-zlABu_F7hwEOnNVlacjkPJdk=/420x240/filters:focal(4096x2750:4097x2751)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/85/cb/85cb42c2-c471-489f-9665-23fb58837506/gettyimages-1957612313.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-26T14:02:47Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>FTC Issues Letters to Big Tech: No Back Doors</title>
      <link>https://puri.sm/posts/ftc-issues-letters-to-big-tech-no-back-doors/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>FTC to Big Tech: No Back Doors — Purism Was Already There Protecting against Jurisdictional Arbitrage When the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) makes a determined move like this, it’s not a casual policy tweak — it’s a line drawn in permanent ink. On August 21, FTC Chairman Andrew Ferguson sent formal notices to over a [&#8230;]</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/posts/ftc-issues-letters-to-big-tech-no-back-doors/">FTC Issues Letters to Big Tech: No Back Doors</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://puri.sm/?p=84107</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T21:07:47Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Google to require developer certification to install Android applications, even outside of the Play Store</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143173/google-to-require-developer-certification-to-install-android-applications-even-outside-of-the-play-store/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Google&#8217;s grip on Android keeps tightening. In what will certainly be another step that we will look back upon as just another nail in the coffin, Google is going to require every Android developer to register with Google, even if they don&#8217;t publish anything in the Play Store. In other words, even if you develop Android applications ad only make them available through F-Droid or GitHub, you&#8217;ll still have to register with Google and hand over a bunch of personal information and a small fee of $25. Google is effectively recreating Apple&#8217;s Gatekeeper for macOS, but on Android. It won&#8217;t come as a surprise to you that Google is doing this in the name of security and protecting users. The company claims that its own analysis found &#8220;over 50 times more malware from internet-sideloaded sources than on apps available through Google Play&#8221;, and the main reason is that malware developers can hide behind anonymity. As such, Google&#8217;s solution is to simply deanonymise every single Android developer. Starting next year, Android will require all apps to be registered by verified developers in order to be installed by users on certified Android devices. This creates crucial accountability, making it much harder for malicious actors to quickly distribute another harmful app after we take the first one down. Think of it like an ID check at the airport, which confirms a traveler&#8217;s identity but is separate from the security screening of their bags; we will be confirming who the developer is, not reviewing the content of their app or where it came from. This change will start in a few select countries specifically impacted by these forms of fraudulent app scams, often from repeat perpetrators. ↫ Suzanne Frey at the Android Developer Blog This new policy will only apply to &#8220;certified Android devices&#8221;, which means Android devices that ship with Google Play Services and all related Google stuff preinstalled. How this policy will affect devices running de-Googled Android ROMs like GrapheneOS where the user has opted to install the Play Store and Google Play Services is unclear. Google does claim the personal information you hand over as part of your registration will remain entirely private and not be shown to anyone, but that&#8217;s not going to reassure anyone. To its small credit, Google intends to create an Android Developer Console explicitly for developers who only operate outside of the Play Store, and a special workflow for students and hobbyists that waives the $25 fee. First tests will start in October of this year, with an official rollout in a number of countries later in 2026, which will then expand to cover the whole world. The first countries seeing the official rollout will be countries hit especially hard by scams (according to Google&#8217;s research, at least): Brazil, Indonesia, Singapore, and Thailand. Google has been trying to claw back control over Android for years now, and it seems the pace is accelerating lately. None of these steps should surprise you, but they should highlight just how crucially important it is that we somehow managed to come to a viable third way, something not controlled by either Apple or Google.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143173</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T20:35:14Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>French Official Rules That 1,000-Year-Old Bayeux Tapestry Isn&#39;t Too Fragile to Travel to London</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/french-official-rules-that-1000-year-old-bayeux-tapestry-isnt-too-fragile-to-travel-to-london-180987229/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The 230-foot-long medieval tapestry is scheduled to go on view at the British Museum next year, but critics worry that transporting the delicate artifact is too risky]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/3QzD0_8qdlnvnfYkFpY-F2f7g6I=/420x240/filters:focal(1904x1306:1905x1307)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/37/ad/37ad8807-281d-42d0-88c4-396ed93d5097/gettyimages-79521106.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T20:12:39Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s Tallest Douglas Fir Tree Damaged in Mysterious, Multi-Day Blaze, but It&#39;s Alive After Firefighters Extinguish Flames</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/worlds-tallest-douglas-fir-tree-damaged-in-mysterious-multi-day-blaze-but-its-alive-after-firefighters-extinguish-flames-180987232/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The fire started burning on August 16 and only affected a single tree—the historic Doerner Fir in southern Oregon. Authorities are still investigating the cause]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/x50OabwzSpf6xAizRAqYPUvl-A4=/420x240/filters:focal(1024x770:1025x771)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/a2/4d/a24d0616-fb62-41fc-89b8-627b5b89f9b4/536286096_1548841393158149_9111245366194712207_n.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T19:57:16Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>College Sophomore Discovers New Origami Pattern That Could Be Used to Build Telescopes and Satellites</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/college-sophomore-discovers-new-origami-pattern-that-could-be-used-to-build-telescopes-and-satellites-180987226/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Based on the work of a student at Brigham Young University, origami theorists have unlocked a new set of patterns that could change space exploration]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/PoD7h_kYzS9kmIC40tzPhqzHTHo=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/01/b5/01b57710-7619-4208-a243-4a322392e5e8/origami.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T18:39:28Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Neolithic Cow&#39;s Tooth Helps Point to the Mysterious Origins of Stonehenge&#39;s Iconic Stones</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-neolithic-cows-tooth-helps-point-to-the-mysterious-origins-of-stonehenges-iconic-stones-180987222/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Isotope analysis of a molar from a cow’s jawbone found buried at the monument provides details of the life story of the animal—and how it may relate to the construction of Stonehenge]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/bu7PfZibYlAZsK7VCbXQw3Ukc0A=/420x240/filters:focal(1116x680:1117x681)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/55/08/5508bd93-4894-4a39-9b46-8c5b27f71932/gettyimages-1364722615.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T18:36:34Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>To Save This Historic Church, Workers Loaded It Onto Trailers and Rolled It Across Town. See How They Pulled It Off</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/to-save-this-historic-church-workers-loaded-it-onto-trailers-and-rolled-it-across-town-see-how-they-pulled-it-off-180987219/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The 672.4-ton church is one of several buildings that have been relocated in the Swedish town of Kiruna, where Europe's largest underground iron ore mine is weakening the ground beneath the city center]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/hmLsq50madgVSPr5duzpHXq9CNQ=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/57/3b/573bb5c3-0af3-4c77-b64c-96eb9c34c2e8/church.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T16:35:09Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Unique Supernova &#39;Dazzled&#39; Astronomers and Revealed the Inner Layers of Stars</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-unique-supernova-dazzled-astronomers-and-revealed-the-inner-layers-of-stars-180987217/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers observed a supernova in progress that showed the onion-like structure of elements in stars, and the explosion may belong to a class of its own]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/CX9mPsNnHsTNPF5F2xkh2mvSpvc=/420x240/filters:focal(600x554:601x555)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/7f/8a/7f8add4b-0fb7-46dd-bdeb-d77ad5b99482/sn2021yfj.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T14:20:11Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>‘Ten Martini’ Proof Uses Number Theory to Explain Quantum Fractals</title>
      <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/ten-martini-proof-uses-number-theory-to-explain-quantum-fractals-20250825/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The proof, known to be so hard that a mathematician once offered 10 martinis to whoever could figure it out, connects quantum mechanics to infinitely intricate mathematical structures.            <p>The post <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/ten-martini-proof-uses-number-theory-to-explain-quantum-fractals-20250825/" target="_blank">‘Ten Martini’ Proof Uses Number Theory to Explain Quantum Fractals</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org" target="_blank">Quanta Magazine</a></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=153531</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T14:15:16Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>“I revived pkgsrc on AIX”</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143168/i-revived-pkgsrc-on-aix/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Earlier this year, I was trying to get actual daily work done on HP-UX 11.11 (11i v1) running on HP&#8217;s last and greatest PA-RISC workstation, the HP c8000. After weeks of frustration caused first by outdated software no longer working properly with the modern web, and then by modern software no longer compiling on HP-UX 11.11, I decided to play the ace up my sleeve: NetBSD&#8217;s pkgsrc has support for HP-UX. Sadly, HP-UX is obviously not a main platform or even a point of interest for pkgsrc developers &#8211; as it should be, nobody uses this combination &#8211; so various incompatibilities and more modern requirements had snuck into pkgsrc, and I couldn&#8217;t get it to bootstrap. I made some minor progress here and there with the help of people far smarter than I, but in the end I just lacked the skills to progress any further. This story will make it to OSNews in a more complete form, I promise. Anyway, in May of this year, it seems Brian Robert Callahan was working on a very similar problem: getting pkgsrc to work properly on IBM&#8217;s AIX. The state of packages on AIX genuinely surprises me. IBM hosts a&#160;repository&#160;of open source software for AIX. But it seems pretty sparse compared to what you&#160;could&#160;get with pkgsrc. Another&#160;website&#160;offering AIX packages seems quite old. I think pkgsrc would be a great way to bring modern packages to AIX. I am not the first to think this. There are AIX 7.2 pkgsrc packages available at&#160;this repository, however all the packages are compiled as 32-bit RISC System/6000 objects. I would greatly prefer to have everything be 64-bit XCOFF objects, as we could do more with 64-bit programs. There also aren&#8217;t too many packages in that repository, so I think starting fresh is in our best interest. As we shall see, this was not as straightforward as I would have hoped. ↫ Brian Robert Callahan Reading through his journey getting pkgsrc to work properly on AIX, I can&#8217;t help but feel a bit better about myself not being to get it to work on HP-UX 11.11. Callahan was working with AIX 7.2 TL4, which was released in November 2019 and still actively supported by IBM on a maintained architecture, while I was working with HP-UX 11.11 (or 11i v1), which last got some updates in and around 2005, running on an architecture that&#8217;s well dead and buried. Looking at what Callahan still had to figure out and do, it&#8217;s not surprising someone with my lack of skill in this area couldn&#8217;t get it working. I&#8217;m still hoping someone far smarter than I stumbles upon a HP c8000 and dives into getting pkgsrc to work on HP-UX, because I feel pkgsrc could turn an otherwise incredibly powerful HP c8000 from a strictly retro machine into something borderline usable in the modern world. HP-UX is much harder to virtualise &#8211; if it&#8217;s even possible at all &#8211; so real hardware is probably going to be required. The NetBSD people on Mastodon suggested I could possibly give remote access to my machine so someone could dive into this, which is something I&#8217;ll keep under consideration.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143168</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T13:49:18Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Windows 11 to get ability to resume applications from Android which nobody will implement</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143165/windows-11-to-get-ability-to-resume-applications-from-android-which-nobody-will-implement/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The history of Android applications on Windows is convoluted, with various failed and cancelled attempts by Microsoft to allow Windows users to run Android applications behind us. Now that these attempts are well dead and buried, Microsoft is going at it from a different perspective: what if you could continue where you left off on your Android phone, right on your Windows machine, but without having to run an Android applications on Windows? We are beginning to gradually roll out the ability to seamlessly resume using your favorite apps from your Android phone on your Windows 11 PC to Windows Insiders in the Dev and Beta Channels. To start with, you will be able to resume or continue listening to your favorite Spotify tracks and episodes right from where you left off on the Spotify app on your Android phone. First, start listening to one of your favorite songs or episodes in the Spotify app on your Android phone. On your PC (running the latest Insider Preview builds in the Dev or Beta Channels) a ‘Resume alert’&#160;will appear on&#160;your taskbar. When you click on that alert, Spotify’s desktop app will open and the same track will now continue playing on your PC. ↫ Amanda Langowski and Brandon LeBlanc So basically, the Spotify application on Windows will know where you left off on the Spotify application on Android, and resume playback. This is table-stakes for most services, and it doesn&#8217;t seem like it would warrant such a big announcement from Microsoft, and while I don&#8217;t use Spotify, I assume it was already built into the service anyway. It seems all Microsoft is doing is providing a nice little notification to expose that functionality a little bit more clearly, but it also explains that you need to manually link your device and the Spotify Android application to the Windows PC and Spotify Windows application, which seems like a lot of manual steps. Does this mean every application developer needs to opt into this and add this feature, thereby making it dead on arrival? Well, yes, you&#8217;ll need to add support on both sides of the equation, which I can guarantee you very few developers will do. Not only does this feature require you to already have a Windows version of your application &#8211; which, statistically, you don&#8217;t &#8211; it also requires you to do the work yourself, and manually apply to Microsoft to even gain access to the required APIs and SDKs. The odds of this feature making it beyond a few very big names Microsoft can give money to is slim.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143165</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-25T13:27:05Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>My other email client is a daemon</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143161/my-other-email-client-is-a-daemon/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[I have a slight problem wherein every time I start up a game of NetHack, I completely lose touch with my surroundings for hours on end. Thankfully&#160;The DevTeam Thinks Of Everything&#160;and there’s a solution that allows communication with the outside world without breaking immersion: the mail daemon! If compiled with&#160;-DMAIL&#160;and&#160;OPTIONS=mail&#160;is set in your runtime configuration (the default on Linux), NetHack will periodically check a user specified mbox file (MAIL) for new mail, and upon receiving an email a mail daemon will spawn in and deliver a scroll of mail to the player. Upon reading this scroll a mail program (MAILREADER) will be executed, which hopefully allows you to read your mail. ↫ George Huebner I love everything about this.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143161</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-24T20:54:55Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Nitro: a tiny but flexible init system and process supervisor</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143156/nitro-a-tiny-but-flexible-init-system-and-process-supervisor/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The most unlikely subsystem of contention is definitely the init system used by Linux, with most popular distributions opting for systemd, while a vocal minority prefers to use something else. Neither of these two groups are wrong or right, as we live in a free world and different people have different needs and desires. Personally, I don&#8217;t think there&#8217;s a more utterly pointless and meaningless debate than this, and people who make the init system they use their entire personality more often than not come across as really, really sad. It&#8217;s a tool; use the one you like and move on with life. A brand new init system was recently released by Leah Neukirchen, who among a ton of other things, contributes to Void Linux. It&#8217;s called nitro, and it&#8217;s a &#8220;tiny process supervisor that also can be used as pid 1 on Linux&#8221;, and it also can be used on FreeBSD supervised by FreeBSD&#8217;s init. There&#8217;s some overlap with runit here, so Neukirchen published a blog post detailing the differences between the two, which should help in getting a better understanding of what makes nitro stand apart. While both use a directory of services managed by small scripts, nitro seems to opt for a more contained, monolithic approach, as it keeps everything in a single process. On top of that, Nitro contains some new features runit doesn&#8217;t have. The focus seems to be on integrating a few capabilities that on runit require hacks, but on nitro are just built-in, like &#8220;support for one-shot &#8216;services&#8217;, i.e. running scripts on up/down without a process to supervise (e.g. persist audio volume, keep RNG state)&#8221;, running service directories multiple times, and more. Nitro also maintains its runtime state in RAM and provides an IPC service to query it, meaning it can be run on read-only filesystems without special configuration. There&#8217;s a lot more information in Neukirchen&#8217;s blog post, including a look at some of the current limitations of Nitro. I highly suggest reading it, and perhaps we will see nitro as another valid alternative to the popular systemd.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143156</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-24T19:19:23Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>These Lizards Have So Much Lead in Their Blood, They Should Be Dead. Instead, They&#39;re Thriving</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/these-lizards-have-so-much-lead-in-their-blood-they-should-be-dead-instead-theyre-thriving-180987224/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Brown anoles around New Orleans have the highest blood concentrations of lead ever recorded in vertebrates—and scientists aren't sure why they can survive it]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/tWCCc_nvM1JWAePjT-V3nGLvmwI=/420x240/filters:focal(2319x1138:2320x1139)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/dd/df/dddf5106-62d1-4124-a453-f728cc6b3187/cuban_brown_anole_anolis_sagrei_sagrei_juvenile.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-22T20:21:50Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This 102-Year-Old Man Just Became the Oldest Person on Record to Summit Japan&#39;s Mount Fuji</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/this-102-year-old-man-just-became-the-oldest-person-on-record-to-summit-japans-mount-fuji-180987223/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Kokichi Akuzawa is an experienced climber who trained for his journey up the mountain by walking for one hour every morning]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/CfjSvhHSWefBYHb1lndlnkyDMjk=/420x240/filters:focal(289x195:290x196)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/df/8e/df8e5876-89c4-40fb-b6f8-5c4eec3332e6/kokichi-climbing-mount-fuji.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-22T19:45:52Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Light Pollution Is Making Days Longer for Birds, Extending the Hours When They&#39;ll Sing</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/light-pollution-is-making-days-longer-for-birds-extending-the-hours-when-theyll-sing-180987221/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new study looked at millions of recordings of birdsong and found that some species in areas with more light pollution are active for almost an hour longer than average]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/6ifHHtQKzy4UlvRunT9tDfvLhZQ=/420x240/filters:focal(960x722:961x723)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/90/63/9063e183-240a-4803-bbd9-228bf10a5be5/american_robin_71307.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-22T18:44:03Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Watch as Experts Preserve a 249-Year-Old Gunboat That Sank During the American Revolution</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/watch-as-experts-preserve-a-249-year-old-gunboat-that-sank-during-the-american-revolution-180987220/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Badly damaged during the Battle of Valcour Island, the "Philadelphia" is now the focus of a new exhibition at the Smithsonian's National Museum of American History]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/2hTPbr6FweNJxaSdrs07Yr2ryFQ=/420x240/filters:focal(3768x2297:3769x2298)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/49/aa/49aae25f-824a-4473-8c6b-95c5d3e201ad/jn2025-01100.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-22T18:17:34Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Archaeologists Are Investigating an Ancient Mosaic Depicting Sandals That Look Strangely Like Modern Flip-Flops</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/archaeologists-are-investigating-an-ancient-mosaic-depicting-sandals-that-look-strangely-like-modern-flip-flops-180987214/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The colorful artwork decorates the frigidarium of the Villa Romana del Casale, a UNESCO World Heritage site located in Sicily]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/3e82b1UpJ4WeMZQv_u16tXRLBz4=/420x240/filters:focal(640x363:641x364)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/fc/30/fc303d52-74d3-4186-84c9-eba9f2c232a4/piazzaarmerina-nuovescoperte_news.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-22T16:51:47Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Busy Beaver Hunters Reach Numbers That Overwhelm Ordinary Math</title>
      <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/busy-beaver-hunters-reach-numbers-that-overwhelm-ordinary-math-20250822/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The quest to find the longest-running simple computer program has identified a new champion. It’s physically impossible to write out the numbers involved using standard mathematical notation.             <p>The post <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/busy-beaver-hunters-reach-numbers-that-overwhelm-ordinary-math-20250822/" target="_blank">Busy Beaver Hunters Reach Numbers That Overwhelm Ordinary Math</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org" target="_blank">Quanta Magazine</a></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=153477</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-22T13:57:50Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This month in Servo: new image formats, canvas backends, automation, and more!</title>
      <link>https://servo.org/blog/2025/08/22/this-month-in-servo/</link>
      <guid>https://servo.org/blog/2025/08/22/this-month-in-servo/</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-22T00:00:00Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The “AI” bubble is showing cracks, and Microsoft ruins Excel</title>
      <link>https://www.osnews.com/story/143148/the-ai-bubble-is-showing-cracks-and-microsoft-ruins-excel/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[It&#8217;s not AI winter just yet, though there is a distinct chill in the air. Meta is shaking up and downsizing its artificial intelligence division. A new report out of MIT finds that 95 percent of companies&#8217; generative AI programs have failed to earn any profit whatsoever. Tech stocks tanked Tuesday, regarding broader fears that this bubble may have swelled about as large as it can go. Surely, there will be no wider repercussions for normal people if and when Nvidia, currently propping up the market like a load-bearing matchstick, finally runs out of fake companies to sell chips to. But getting in under the wire, before we&#8217;re all bartering gas in the desert and people who can read become the priestly caste, is Microsoft, with the single most &#8220;Who asked for this?&#8221; application of AI I&#8217;ve seen yet: They&#8217;re jamming it into Excel. ↫ Barry Petchesky at Defector I&#8217;m going to skip over the mounting and palpable uneasiness that the cracks in the &#8220;AI&#8221; bubble are starting to form, and go right to that thing about Excel. Quite possible one of the most successful applications of all time, and the backbone of countless small, medium, and even large business, it started out as a Mac program to supplant Microsoft&#8217;s MultiPlan, which was being clobbered in the market by Lotus 1-2-3. It wasn&#8217;t until version 2.0 that it came to Intel, as an application that contained a Windows runtime. It was a port of Excel 2.0 for the Mac. Anyway, it took a few years, but Excel took over the market, and I don&#8217;t think any other spreadsheet program has ever even remotely threatened its market dominance ever since. Well, not until Google Sheets arrived on the scene &#8211; it&#8217;s hard to find any useful numbers, but it seems Google Sheets is insanely popular in all kinds of sectors, at least according to Statista. They claim Google&#8217;s online office suite has a 49% market share, with Microsoft Office sitting at 29%. I have no idea how that translates into the usage shares of Google Sheets versus Microsoft Excel, but it&#8217;s a sign of the times, regardless. One of the things you&#8217;d expect a spreadsheet to do is calculate numbers and tabulate data, and to do so accurately. The core competency of a computer is to compute, do stuff with numbers, and we&#8217;d flip out collective shit if our computers failed to do such basic arithmetic. So, what if I told you that Microsoft, in its infinite wisdom, has decided to add &#8220;AI&#8221; to Excel, and as such, has to add a disclaimer that this means Excel may not do basic arithmetic correctly? Look, we can all disagree on the use of &#8220;AI&#8221;, where it makes sense, where it doesn&#8217;t, if it even does anything useful, and so on, but I would assume &#8211; for the world&#8217;s sake &#8211; that we can at least agree that using &#8220;AI&#8221; in an application used to do very important calculations for a lot of business is a really, really dumb idea? Is the person doing the bookkeeping in Excel at Windmill Restaurant, in Spearville, Kansas, properly aware of the limitations of &#8220;AI&#8221;, or are they not following technology that closely, and as such only hear the marketing and hype? A spreadsheet should give accurate outcomes based on the input given by humans. The moment you let a confabulator loose on your spreadsheet, it ceases being a tool that can be used for anything even remotely serious. The fact that Microsoft is adding this nonsense to Excel and letting it loose on the unsuspecting public at large is absolutely wild to me, and I can assure you it&#8217;s going to have serious consequences for a lot of people. Microsoft, of course, will be able to point at the disclaimer buried in some random support document and absolve itself of any and all responsibility. I&#8217;d like to point out that Lotus 1-2-3 probably still runs on Windows 11, for no reason at all.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.osnews.com/?p=143148</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-21T21:15:57Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Two Friends Went Fishing on the Mississippi River. Police Say They May Have Just Solved a 1967 Cold Case</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/two-friends-went-fishing-on-the-mississippi-river-police-say-they-may-have-just-solved-a-1967-cold-case-180987215/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Investigators pulled a 1960s Buick sedan from the waterway in central Minnesota that provides new details about a man’s disappearance more than 50 years ago]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/fRs0E0M8KC0V5GaFIY84KnxVo-g=/420x240/filters:focal(720x542:721x543)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/57/ad/57ad17a7-19ab-4d96-8df5-6493ac66d895/police.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-21T20:39:09Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>These Big, Meat-Eating Bats Also Have a Cuddly Side. Rare Videos Reveal &#39;Hugging,&#39; Playing and Sharing Food</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/these-big-meat-eating-bats-also-have-a-cuddly-side-rare-videos-reveal-hugging-playing-and-sharing-food-180987218/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Scientists observed a family of four spectral bats in their roost in a tree in Costa Rica, capturing an inside look at their social behavior]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/uydHg1tjL7vz8ZtAeYDRpCyQVvo=/420x240/filters:focal(1378x1496:1379x1497)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/2c/33/2c336c9a-6771-4183-8423-be479745e7b0/social_roosting_of_the_spectral_bats_vamyprum_spectrum.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-21T18:49:28Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Cows, Hikers and Mountain Bikers Coexist at This National Monument, With Help From New Technology</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/cows-hikers-and-mountain-bikers-coexist-at-this-national-monument-with-help-from-new-technology-180987209/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Established in 2017, the Cotoni-Coast Dairies national monument in California is now open to the public]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/UBfwZJjm_nuXbz60pzYL5jcXMcg=/420x240/filters:focal(1024x683:1025x684)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/8c/c2/8cc24a2e-43ab-4cf5-9b1e-5a55564399a9/15650124019_626490c0f4_k.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-21T18:42:01Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>1.04-Million-Year-Old Stone Tools Found on Indonesian Island Offer Clues About Some of the Region&#39;s Earliest Human Relatives</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/1-04-million-year-old-stone-tools-found-on-indonesian-island-offer-clues-about-some-of-the-regions-earliest-human-relatives-180987129/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The toolmakers or their ancestors might have arrived on Sulawesi by clinging to vegetation during a storm, but their identities remain a mystery]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/cybtIBdK4dX_JOmmHwZ7W9TcG00=/420x240/filters:focal(828x627:829x628)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/1c/50/1c501b03-db30-476d-98d0-7bcad802a574/screenshot_2025-08-21_at_123701pm.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-21T17:14:01Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Someone Returned a Library Book That Their Grandmother Checked Out Eight Decades Ago</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/someone-returned-a-library-book-that-their-grandmother-checked-out-eight-decades-ago-180987216/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The San Antonio Public Library received the book in the mail along with a letter: "I hope there is no late fee for it because Grandma won't be able to pay for it anymore"]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/cgfayvRud6CQqyHVIhAJ8_Vk9lM=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/3d/b0/3db01aee-9f00-440f-be15-507d0be446b9/book.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-21T15:50:10Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Do Beautiful Birds Have an Evolutionary Advantage?</title>
      <link>https://www.quantamagazine.org/do-beautiful-birds-have-an-evolutionary-advantage-20250821/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Richard Prum explains why he thinks feathers and vibrant traits in birds evolved not solely for survival, but also through aesthetic choice.            <p>The post <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/do-beautiful-birds-have-an-evolutionary-advantage-20250821/" target="_blank">Do Beautiful Birds Have an Evolutionary Advantage?</a> first appeared on <a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org" target="_blank">Quanta Magazine</a></p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://www.quantamagazine.org/?p=153437</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-21T13:17:04Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Hear the Long-Lost Chants of English Monks Whose Monasteries Were Dissolved by Henry VIII</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/hear-the-long-lost-chants-of-english-monks-whose-monasteries-were-dissolved-by-henry-viii-180987204/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A university choir has revived music found hiding in plain sight in a book from southern England's Buckland Abbey]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/Ph8seZOIBEBOGwztMzaMtJNymSY=/420x240/filters:focal(375x250:376x251)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/62/2d/622db95e-7928-4b44-b317-f6aa13886d84/choir-3.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-20T19:36:51Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Partial Dire Wolf Skull Is Headed to Auction This Month—and It Could Sell for $30,000</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-partial-dire-wolf-skull-is-headed-to-auction-this-month-and-could-sell-for-30000-180987213/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Collectors have a rare opportunity to bid on the remains of the fearsome creature, a large canid that went extinct around the end of the last ice age]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/tLOA7AqSg4C5kvDFMZ3x1jtyot0=/420x240/filters:focal(1453x1093:1454x1094)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/39/f3/39f3274b-babe-4088-9a72-1165ad5bf169/image_8-20-25_at_1122am_1.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-20T19:25:49Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Read the Dramatic 17th-Century Memoirs of Alice Thornton, Who Wrote Four Versions of Her Life Story</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/read-the-dramatic-17th-century-memoirs-of-alice-thornton-who-wrote-four-versions-of-her-life-story-180987167/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers have digitized all four volumes, which are now available online. The autobiographies offer a compelling window into a tumultuous period in English history]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/EaQF29xMVX6ZGB6pq_xQ-sIC7iw=/420x240/filters:focal(687x458:688x459)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/4b/f4/4bf4708e-bd0c-4661-a103-66ee0cdf09fe/ahrc-050825-alices-book-of-remembrances-gb-0033-ccom_38-182.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-20T17:43:57Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>&#39;Delulu,&#39; &#39;Skibidi&#39; and &#39;Tradwife&#39; Are Among More Than 6,000 Words Added to the Cambridge Dictionary</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/delulu-skibidi-and-tradwife-are-among-more-than-6000-words-added-to-the-cambridge-dictionary-180987210/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Many of the additions reflect how internet culture has changed the English language in recent years]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/UGVqfdIm--ZtQEziAfpQxYYes8M=/420x240/filters:focal(2592x1950:2593x1951)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/90/13/90131a83-1032-4b77-8041-44c98795ff35/gettyimages-1445192194.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-20T16:03:43Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Video Footage Accidentally Reveals the Strange Pooping Behavior of These Large Seabirds</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/video-footage-accidentally-reveals-the-strange-pooping-behavior-of-these-large-seabirds-180987206/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers set out to investigate how streaked shearwaters take off and instead were surprised to discover that the birds poop very frequently and regularly, which could play a role in marine ecology]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/bdJSvjHOjXa3MzhaRg54NWtjXhA=/420x240/filters:focal(350x263:351x264)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/3d/30/3d3027aa-a132-408a-aca7-1a06dfff7cbb/low-res_shearwater_goto.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-20T13:16:48Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>World&#39;s First &#39;Robot Olympics&#39; Featured Soccer, Kickboxing and Lots of Falling Down</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/worlds-first-robot-olympics-features-soccer-kickboxing-and-lots-of-falling-down-180987199/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Hundreds of humanoids from 16 countries stumbled over each other while competing in the World Humanoid Robot Games in Beijing]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/NM7-kEgQvZ5WTSsLAQ1K13M4Ktg=/420x240/filters:focal(3039x2040:3040x2041)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/9a/4b/9a4b7723-ec4d-4ad6-9722-14deda6f04fa/gettyimages-2230557252.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-19T19:59:56Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Nobody Has Been Able to Solve the CIA&#39;s Famous &#39;Kryptos&#39; Sculpture. Soon, the Solution Will Be Sold to the Highest Bidder</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/nobody-has-been-able-to-solve-the-cias-famous-kryptos-sculpture-soon-the-solution-will-be-sold-to-the-highest-bidder-180987200/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Three of the four messages carved into the sculpture have been deciphered, but the final puzzle has left amateur sleuths stumped. In November, the solution could fetch up to $500,000 at auction]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/hj8SuGCQcsAWNeB2BoU0lYjiByo=/420x240/filters:focal(1692x1128:1693x1129)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/e6/fc/e6fcdb25-28b0-4695-9e06-45b17a6fb18d/art_made_of__code__named_kryptos_sits_on_the_grounds_of_the_cia_headquarters_in_virginia_lcc.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-19T18:35:54Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Habitat Loss Is Leading to Inbreeding Among Michigan&#39;s Only Species of Venomous Snake</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/habitat-loss-is-leading-to-inbreeding-among-michigans-only-species-of-venomous-snake-180987207/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Roads, buildings and other manmade barriers are preventing the small pit vipers from slithering around to find mates from other populations]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/-JODPR6Vmt_a3k_TbcwGcUzYfu0=/420x240/filters:focal(2000x1505:2001x1506)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/87/e7/87e75ab0-8f44-49a8-ba9c-d2916201f636/119_1.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-19T17:35:19Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Researchers Discover Fossilized Teeth That May Have Come From an Unknown Hominin Species</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/researchers-discover-fossilized-teeth-that-may-have-come-from-an-unknown-hominin-species-180987188/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The find suggests that as many as four different hominin lineages lived in eastern Africa between 2.5 million and 3 million years ago]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/3zG88l6HQLkwAxr-M_w7PAcHLj0=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/92/68/926805d3-c5f7-4ce2-9ba6-a78637b92cff/smithsonian_feature_images_12.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-19T16:44:37Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>See the First 3D Images of a Human Embryo Implanting, Shedding Light on the Crucial but Little-Known Process</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/see-the-first-3d-images-of-a-human-embryo-implanting-shedding-light-on-the-crucial-but-little-known-process-180987201/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new study shows how human embryos reshape their environment by pulling on uterine tissue]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/kJC390j22Ac2GPuoCt0iEe8hLjE=/420x240/filters:focal(1684x978:1685x979)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/49/cd/49cd57d0-258b-437a-a04e-58ef44d3948d/screenshot_2025-08-18_at_184700.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-19T16:38:05Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Italian Police Catch Tourist Stealing Stones From the Ancient City of Pompeii</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/italian-police-catch-tourist-stealing-stones-from-the-ancient-city-of-pompeii-180987193/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[According to legend, travelers who remove artifacts from the historic Italian city are cursed to endure hardship. Many have even returned the stolen items years later]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/HmzSKBJBHlDPhyRoUgxnq9Y737E=/420x240/filters:focal(600x349:601x350)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/7d/b0/7db05b7b-4ce6-4529-b36f-2a0d9a15ae0e/direttore-e-carabinieri-1200x688.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-19T16:33:08Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Custom Furnishings From Frank Lloyd Wright&#39;s Only Skyscraper Have Been Preserved for Posterity</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/custom-furnishings-from-frank-lloyd-wrights-only-skyscraper-have-been-preserved-for-posterity-180987155/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The Frank Lloyd Wright Building Conservancy hopes to return the 11 artifacts to the Price Tower in Bartlesville, Oklahoma]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/LgELjJ4uqbtvG50fQqlqJICuFK4=/420x240/filters:focal(782x521:783x522)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/20/bc/20bc0c63-92ff-4e6f-878b-6abec8025558/copper_tables_credit_20cdesign.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-18T20:35:25Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Whales and Dolphins Interact More Often Than Scientists Thought, Engaging in Mutual Play, Study Suggests</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/whales-and-dolphins-interact-more-often-than-scientists-thought-engaging-in-mutual-play-study-suggets-180987198/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers analyzed nearly 200 videos and photographs documenting interactions between the various kinds of cetaceans]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/55W4lR4xWTi3dJ3Y9dSCsWORSI0=/420x240/filters:focal(772x533:773x534)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/43/ce/43cecf61-41a7-4077-b226-18b321178999/bow-riding-bottlenose-hastings-credit-roving-media-1.webp" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-18T19:43:06Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The New York City Studio Where Artist Mark Rothko Worked Is for Sale</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/the-new-york-city-studio-where-artist-mark-rothko-worked-is-for-sale-180987196/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The private unit takes up the second and third floor of the carriage house, which was originally an equestrian training space. The apartment is listed at $9.5 million]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/VAg5Vgm_Qeu2CXWNJ5mR1DZragw=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/b9/74/b9744ec8-7ba7-4b8d-8a67-aa663e3b4401/studio.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-18T19:05:02Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Volunteers Discover 115-Million-Year-Old Dinosaur Tracks Revealed in the Wake of Devastating Texas Floods</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/volunteers-discover-115-million-year-old-dinosaur-tracks-revealed-in-the-wake-of-devastating-texas-floods-180987197/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Fifteen large prints were probably left behind by meat-eating dinosaurs, and they were revealed as floodwaters washed away dirt in early July]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/08PECSLCJ4fAdbMO4toKiZ9F7k8=/420x240/filters:focal(800x533:801x534)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/d8/e1/d8e193c1-8be0-4a40-8855-f29dfd1e1ea1/texas_floods_devastate_local_communities_-_54639631105.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-18T15:57:09Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Drones Are Blasting Iconic Argument From &#39;Marriage Story&#39; to Scare Wolves Away From Cows in Oregon</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/drones-are-blasting-iconic-argument-from-marriage-story-to-scare-wolves-away-from-cows-in-oregon-180987154/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Scarlet Johansson and Adam Driver's charged dialogue is playing from speakers attached to drones as wildlife officials get creative in their efforts to stop wolves from killing cattle]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/3nI7HjAPUDBFV52Kki3EssCLj98=/420x240/filters:focal(526x350:527x351)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/c1/c9/c1c96313-08e8-4cea-82b6-4a47a94847a2/4394641125_27eb149969_o.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-18T15:07:01Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rabbits With &#39;Horns&#39; Seen in Colorado Are Going Viral. Here&#39;s What&#39;s Really Happening</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/rabbits-with-horns-seen-in-colorado-are-going-viral-heres-whats-really-happening-180987195/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Though the strange growths on these animals may look intimidating, experts say there’s not much to worry about, and they're caused by a fairly common virus]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/mKLb0Xq49OhYp_jyU54sauKL_YA=/420x240/filters:focal(430x287:431x288)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/1e/e1/1ee1217f-c9c8-49d6-8ebd-9aeaac896142/gettyimages-481662845.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-15T20:36:45Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Italy Plans World&#39;s Longest Suspension Bridge to Connect Mainland With Sicily</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/italy-plans-worlds-longest-suspension-bridge-to-connect-mainland-with-sicily-180987164/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The bridge, expected to cost more than $15 billion, would stretch more than two miles across the Messina Strait]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/Wo6Ry4Rjx8FxKUpCBriGA_QC_Fk=/420x240/filters:focal(640x512:641x513)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/9e/b2/9eb2e396-6373-45e0-8e19-ca2d46ead58c/ponte2520messina25202529.webp" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-15T19:56:35Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Science Fiction? Think Again. Scientists Are Learning How to Decode Inner Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/science-fiction-think-again-scientists-are-learning-how-to-decode-inner-thoughts-180987194/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A brain-computer interface has gotten better than ever before at translating thoughts from people with speech difficulties. Researchers are also thinking through how to protect users’ privacy]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/HIvD_mMrUTWR0TyZl_FO2ShRkV4=/420x240/filters:focal(1061x707:1062x708)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/5a/c5/5ac5de6b-2d84-4b23-ae4c-e151893cbb3b/gettyimages-1421511892.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-15T19:00:38Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>FBI Returns Long-Lost Manuscript Signed by Hernán Cortés in 1527 to Mexico&#39;s National Archives</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/fbi-returns-long-lost-manuscript-signed-by-hernan-cortes-in-1527-to-mexicos-national-archives-180987191/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The document, which vanished decades ago, includes logistical details linked to the travels of the Spanish conquistador, who had conquered the Aztec Empire several years earlier]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/gRCDiRNVGuhVDTnAPwWHnpkZJ0M=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/dd/16/dd160558-7412-4d7b-b024-6a2abf2c8cc1/cortes.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-15T16:37:06Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Lock of Braided Human Hair Could Change How We Think About Inca Society and Record-Keeping</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-lock-of-braided-human-hair-could-change-how-we-think-about-inca-society-and-record-keeping-180987187/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The khipu knot-tying system was thought to have only been used by elites, but one artifact suggests commoners, too, knew how to use it]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/eRbnNjwZUHQma5MSzhh6qE7flG0=/420x240/filters:focal(1050x705:1051x706)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/88/59/88597901-b4dd-40ea-a20e-d9758d40d2d7/sciadvadv1950-f1.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-15T15:48:23Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A 2,000-Year-Old Sun Hat Worn by a Roman Soldier in Egypt Goes on View After a Century in Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-2000-year-old-sun-hat-worn-by-a-roman-soldier-in-egypt-goes-on-view-after-a-century-in-storage-180987192/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The felt cap—one of only three surviving examples of its kind—was recently conserved by a museum in England]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/q9E7wSEW25dxF66w8UiB-cP4bE0=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/08/90/08904cbc-097a-4518-bf3c-37768924c879/hat.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-15T12:42:09Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>An Archaeology Student Found a Medieval Gold Artifact During Her First Dig</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/an-archaeology-student-found-a-medieval-gold-artifact-during-her-first-dig-180987185/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The piece resembles another found in the same area four years ago]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/Ru3DQg70KLGcneep-9rNAVOu298=/420x240/filters:focal(419x279:420x280)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/42/58/42588609-e8ed-4438-b5cc-ded241e9a7f4/the_gold_object_discovered_in_northumberland.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-14T20:20:55Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Weaver Ants Use Teamwork to Become &#39;Superefficient,&#39; Building Complex Nests From Leaves With Extra Pulling Power</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/weaver-ants-use-teamwork-to-become-superefficient-building-complex-nests-from-leaves-with-extra-pulling-power-180987186/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[When humans work in large teams, they become less individually effective. But each ant grows more efficient when collaborating—a discovery that could help engineers build better robots]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/TyYig0HzspfYzd5oyEXJ50MxRUs=/420x240/filters:focal(1800x1354:1801x1355)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/f6/5d/f65d9b59-17b0-4c5f-91b0-1557d343d3ce/weaver_ants_-_oecophylla_smaragdina.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-14T19:51:38Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Bones Found in Spanish Cave Suggest This Neolithic Group Butchered and Cannibalized a Rival Community</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/bones-found-in-spanish-cave-suggest-this-neolithic-group-butchered-and-cannibalized-rival-community-180987182/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The 5,700-year-old remains exhibit signs of human consumption, including bite marks and traces of cutting, cremation and boiling]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/jULVXK4LKEzUSCCAgBxVBuSYV-g=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/ea/2b/ea2b769b-8b04-4c92-9caf-24ec2c776567/excavation_site.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-14T19:32:27Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>William the Conqueror&#39;s Norwich Castle to Reopen Following $37 Million Renovation</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/william-the-conquerors-norwich-castle-to-reopen-following-37-million-renovation-180987183/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[In partnership with the British Museum, 900 Norman artifacts will be displayed across the reimagined space’s five floors]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/qjDf5KAaEGOOFCY8vcfMue0VqZ8=/420x240/filters:focal(1611x913:1612x914)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/35/65/3565d652-283e-4442-a989-174dfd1e32df/norwich_castle_keep_exterior_16-9__norfolk_museums_service.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-14T18:18:11Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Student Spotted a Jawbone at a Beach. It Turned Out to Be a New, Mouse-Sized Mammal That Lived Among Dinosaurs</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-student-spotted-a-jawbone-at-a-beach-it-turned-out-to-be-a-new-mouse-sized-mammal-that-lived-among-dinosaurs-180987146/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The species was named for its pointy teeth and could shed light on early mammal adaptations]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/LE40q_urrU-AjChjX90lO0Q4unE=/420x240/filters:focal(270x193:271x194)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/2b/7a/2b7ad76f-66ba-488c-b754-8c32fccb3af2/fossil_new.webp" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-14T18:10:29Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Newly Discovered Prehistoric Whale Is &#39;Deceptively Cute&#39;—It&#39;s Tiny but Has a Mouth Full of Razor-Sharp Teeth</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/newly-discovered-prehistoric-whale-is-deceptively-cute-its-tiny-but-has-a-mouth-full-of-razor-sharp-teeth-180987165/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Found on the southern coast of Australia, the species could fill gaps in scientists' understanding of baleen whale evolution]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/FeOl8Qgul5ImTOf4OHjq7yO_2lU=/420x240/filters:focal(1900x1430:1901x1431)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/85/6d/856d6e34-6087-4a09-8597-ed8843291606/janjucetus_dullardi_calf_and_mother_artwork_by_ruairidh_duncan.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-14T15:00:42Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Sex Reversal Is More Common in Birds Than Previously Thought, Suggests Study of Australian Species</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/sex-reversal-is-more-common-in-birds-than-previously-thought-suggests-study-of-australian-species-180987163/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers find that about 5 percent of birds studied have a mismatch between genetic and physical sex—including one male bird that seems to have laid an egg]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/B9bWdVHnZpBloEC-sP8e7M8jTFY=/420x240/filters:focal(750x421:751x422)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/83/a0/83a0f950-21d1-4f2a-a1cc-55d74ed6dea8/lorikeet.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-14T12:32:39Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>What Is a Black Moon? The Unusual Sky Phenomenon Will Occur Later This Month, but Don&#39;t Expect to See It</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/what-is-a-black-moon-the-unusual-sky-phenomenon-will-occur-later-this-month-but-dont-expect-to-see-it-180987166/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A seasonal black moon, to appear on August 22 or 23, is the third of four new moons within an astronomical season]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/kaKa3NJwydvPbc3seDmdnFTuqpg=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/58/65/58653467-1b09-4e28-b38b-e0acb891dc34/smithsonian_feature_images_11.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-13T20:18:44Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Sounds of AOL Dial-Up Defined the Early Internet. Now, the Service Is Shutting Down for Good</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/the-sounds-of-aol-dial-up-defined-the-early-internet-now-the-service-is-shutting-down-for-good-180987177/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Many of today's internet users remember browsing the web for the first time via AOL dial-up. But as subscribers dwindle, the service will be sunsetting on September 30]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/sbkfeUksjy_I0hJcE9q4EwjMepA=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/1a/47/1a4757c9-4e8d-432b-99db-f7c440c31bf7/cds.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-13T20:01:47Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Rare First-Edition Copy of ‘The Hobbit’ Found in English Home Sells for Nearly $60,000</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/rare-first-edition-copy-of-the-hobbit-found-in-english-home-sells-for-nearly-60000-180987135/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Experts found the volume while appraising the items in a home in Bristol, England. Only a few hundred copies are thought to survive]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/b0RkGrBjWm2uBAvx-nNOrrbk4y4=/420x240/filters:focal(720x480:721x481)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/0c/08/0c087eae-a155-439e-a1ca-e3c8001420a9/528734323_1297929272342007_1213691427736600629_n.jpeg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-13T18:48:34Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Tropical Birds Are Struggling to Cope With Extreme Heat, Research Suggests</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/tropical-birds-are-struggling-to-cope-with-extreme-heat-research-suggests-180987157/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A first-of-its-kind data analysis links high temperatures caused by climate change to tropical bird population declines]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/2xzFXhKFZKK9AKhvq4J7plq8a9Y=/420x240/filters:focal(1061x707:1062x708)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/2c/74/2c74a43f-f969-4fbf-9165-2b8227ec68a6/gettyimages-898596862.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-13T18:47:04Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Suffering From Sleep Apnea? Try Blowing Into a Conch Shell Almost Daily, New Study Suggests</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/suffering-from-sleep-apnea-try-blowing-into-a-conch-shell-almost-daily-new-study-suggests-180987158/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Researchers say the practice might provide a simpler and low-cost alternative to the standard treatment for obstructive sleep apnea, though trials with more participants are needed]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/QVrqNzdM6xe8V-HIxqEP8CF4AQ0=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/b2/1d/b21daa73-0376-4ddb-b7fa-478b414d15ec/blowing_conch.png" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-13T17:05:06Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This Mid-Century Motel Described in Reviews as &#39;Eerie&#39; Just Became a Los Angeles Historic Monument</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/this-mid-century-motel-described-in-reviews-as-eerie-just-became-a-los-angeles-historic-monument-180987128/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Built in 1960, the Hollywood Premiere is the first motel to be added to the list of more than 1,300 protected sites in the city]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/EW9Xhv_7fgZHYyHziv6ff0eEXhM=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/90/10/9010e067-7510-4525-9f3d-a93ef199a577/motel.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-13T14:56:43Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Instagram’s Mapping Feature: A Privacy Wake-Up Call</title>
      <link>https://puri.sm/posts/instagrams-mapping-feature-a-privacy-wake-up-call/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Instagram’s latest update introduces a mapping feature that quietly turns your location into a public breadcrumb trail. While it may seem like a harmless way to tag your favorite coffee shop or scenic overlook, the reality is more insidious: this feature keeps your location sharing always-on by default. That means every time you post, you’re potentially broadcasting your whereabouts—not just to friends, but to advertisers, data brokers, and anyone else watching. It’s a textbook example of how convenience is weaponized against privacy.</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/posts/instagrams-mapping-feature-a-privacy-wake-up-call/">Instagram’s Mapping Feature: A Privacy Wake-Up Call</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://puri.sm/?p=84003</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-13T01:38:59Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Introducing the Librem PQC Encryptor</title>
      <link>https://puri.sm/posts/introducing-the-librem-pqc-encryptor/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>SF, CA, US – Purism is excited to announce its <a href="https://puri.sm/products/librem-pqc-encryptor/">Librem PQC Encryptor</a>, encrypting data-in-transit with post-quantum cryptography (PQC) according to the <a href="https://csrc.nist.gov/pubs/fips/203/final">NIST FIPS 203</a> standard.</p>
        <p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/posts/introducing-the-librem-pqc-encryptor/">Introducing the Librem PQC Encryptor</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://puri.sm/">Purism</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>https://puri.sm/?p=83982</guid>
      <pubDate>2025-08-12T22:12:45Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Remains of a Lost Antarctic Researcher Are Finally Recovered, 66 Years After He Fell Into a Crevasse</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/remains-of-an-antarctic-researcher-are-finally-recovered-66-years-after-he-fell-into-a-crevasse-180987156/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A team of Polish scientists found bone fragments and items belonging to Dennis “Tink” Bell near Ecology Glacier on Antarctica’s King George Island]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/XxTixlXrwZjyIb2CFtBNljxxCZs=/420x240/filters:focal(800x602:801x603)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/9a/8b/9a8b7687-fac5-4be1-a12e-4305b7aa01cf/ecology_glacier_king_george_island_winter.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-12T20:04:41Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>After Mount Vesuvius Erupted, Pompeii&#39;s Poorest Survivors Lived Amid the Rubble of the Ancient City for Hundreds of Years</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/after-mount-vesuvius-erupted-pompeiis-poorest-survivors-lived-amid-the-rubble-of-the-ancient-city-for-hundreds-of-years-180987153/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Some residents who couldn't afford to resettle elsewhere returned to the city, where they occupied the upper floors of buildings that had been buried in ash, according to new research]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/e0CDfqTTEfaiVBwc_HkvTKNy8oI=/420x240/filters:focal(600x337:601x338)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/bb/6a/bb6af876-3e9b-4994-9ed2-7b6f94e34c47/insula-meridionalis-2-1200x674.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-12T18:41:30Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Scientists Find Links to Chronic Fatigue Syndrome in Genes and in the Gut Microbiome</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/scientists-find-links-to-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-in-genes-and-in-the-gut-microbiome-180987141/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Two studies present new data on ME/CFS, offering "credibility and validity" to the experiences of patients struggling with symptoms]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/j93CamUU6aIjCT5ktuPNYpbgyds=/420x240/filters:focal(3000x2000:3001x2001)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/98/76/9876ecc4-4219-404e-a316-6e3b2cdc7e59/mecfs-liegenddemo_berlin_2_-_foto_maria_wagner.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-12T17:55:01Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>See the Abstract Artworks That Defined Radiohead&#39;s Iconic Visual Style</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/see-the-abstract-artworks-that-defined-radioheads-iconic-visual-style-180987125/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new exhibition explores the artistic collaborations between Thom Yorke, the rock band's frontman, and artist Stanley Donwood, his longtime friend]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/_8Wj2bGthGxEb7TolrVYVxJtx24=/420x240/filters:focal(2500x1667:2501x1668)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/bc/d1/bcd13e45-9140-4c86-afd6-9ed1f3d4092f/thom_yorke_and_stanley_donwood_c_julian_broad.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-12T17:36:13Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>In the Muddy Banks of North Carolina, Student Archaeologists May Have Discovered the Remnants of a Centuries-Old Spanish Ship</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/timber-from-colonial-era-spanish-ship-among-four-shipwrecks-discovered-in-north-carolina-180987139/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[While taking measurements of an abandoned wharf site, the students found timber from what experts believe may be part of La Fortuna, a Spanish ship destroyed nearly 300 years ago]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/IYQe8k9uto3B7h1zmnoKEfY6TMA=/420x240/filters:focal(310x208:311x209)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/d0/3c/d03c147a-d4e0-44f7-b659-c3c78708b932/la-fortuna-shipwreck.webp" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-12T11:00:00Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>A Meteorite Tore Through a Georgia Home&#39;s Roof. It Turns Out the Space Rock Is Older Than Our Planet</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/a-meteorite-tore-through-a-georgia-homes-roof-it-turns-out-the-space-rock-is-older-than-our-planet-180987137/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A planetary geologist finds that the meteorite, which fell in June, came from the main asteroid belt between Mars and Jupiter]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/PBSazt1MNyAWIPIfhL8Cz_CujSM=/420x240/filters:focal(1050x590:1051x591)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/df/5c/df5cc331-531d-438c-b4d4-a73062feaf06/mcdonough_meteorite.webp" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-11T18:47:32Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>This Colorful Mural of Stars and Fish Is the First of Its Kind Found on the Coast of Northern Peru</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/this-colorful-mural-of-stars-and-fish-is-the-first-of-its-kind-found-on-the-coast-of-northern-peru-180987144/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[The 3,000- to 4,000-year-old artwork decorated the wall of a temple atrium during Peru's Formative Period]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/wDQxQx3hqFVD_IlbMu_pixigN_A=/420x240/filters:focal(750x500:751x501)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/43/14/43144eb6-2d69-4e23-a7fd-1e59b1f7c12a/mural.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-11T18:45:49Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>One of San Francisco&#39;s Most Famous Houses Is Hosting a Pop-Up Museum of Street Artist Fnnch&#39;s Honey Bears</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/one-of-san-franciscos-most-famous-houses-is-hosting-a-pop-up-museum-of-street-artist-fnnchs-honey-bears-180987145/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[Visitors to the Pink Painted Lady near Alamo Square Park will be able to see 116 editions of fnnch's honey bear paintings]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/XIR13MbaBmtQC09QpmujJLxof6E=/420x240/filters:focal(512x344:513x345)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/0e/0d/0e0d903e-b91b-4f6b-8379-85e554cd1207/gettyimages-1322103191.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-11T17:53:02Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Popular Perseid Meteor Shower Will Peak This Week—Here&#39;s How to Watch, Despite a Bright Moon</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/the-popular-perseid-meteor-shower-will-peak-this-week-heres-how-to-watch-despite-a-bright-moon-180987142/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A waning gibbous moon will impact viewing the shooting stars, but the famous meteor shower is still worth observing]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/8XnVM-BIQrC1dJVb_cbN78rdGOI=/420x240/filters:focal(2862x1663:2863x1664)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/75/61/7561047d-e807-4d17-8783-d5ca9474cf86/54696755851-f9236d059b-o.webp" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-11T17:22:22Z</pubDate>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Dinosaur Teeth Provide Key Clues to Earth&#39;s Climate Past, Revealing High Levels of Carbon Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/dinosaur-teeth-provide-key-clues-to-earths-climate-past-revealing-high-levels-of-carbon-dioxide-180987119/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[A new study finds that the Mesozoic Era saw significantly higher quantities of the greenhouse gas than both pre-industrial and modern levels, likely due to volcanic activity]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="https://th-thumbnailer.cdn-si-edu.com/Q8OBYBQSoW3HGIRLOJEYOj6tvaE=/420x240/filters:focal(1440x1083:1441x1084)/https://tf-cmsv2-smithsonianmag-media.s3.amazonaws.com/filer_public/f5/77/f5774a2c-59cd-4fd8-a510-de291ccb60eb/dinosaur-teeth-as-time-1.jpg" length="" type="" />
      <pubDate>2025-08-11T14:59:29Z</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
