<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <atom:link href="https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/writing.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Writing</title>
    <link>https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/writing.xml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>21 Sep 25 15:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.6</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Are Copyright Anxiety and Legal Chill Hampering Your Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.authorsalliance.org/2025/09/18/are-copyright-anxiety-and-legal-chill-hampering-your-work/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This is guest post by Amanda Wakaruk, Jane Secker, and Chris Morrison. Amanda Wakaruk has worked as a copyright librarian [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.authorsalliance.org/?p=12175</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>BookTok and Beyond: How Young Readers Are Reviving Physical Bookstores</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/booktok-and-beyond-how-young-readers-are-reviving-physical-bookstores</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7932</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Robert Redford, RIP</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/robert-redford-rip</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Robert Redford’s remarkable career as an actor and director enabled his biggest triumph, the Sundance Institute. I was lucky to be part of it.</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/robert-redford-rip">Robert Redford, RIP</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23458</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Places, Everyone</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/places-everyone</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>John welcomes back Liz Hannah (The Post, The Girl from Plainville) to discuss how to construct and communicate setting in a script. They talk about the balance between establishing a sense of space while avoiding the beginner’s mistake of over-blocking. We also follow up on accountability groups, last looks, and French composers. Then, we answer [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/places-everyone">Places, Everyone</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23449</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How To Write Dialogue in a Story</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/how-to-write-dialogue-in-a-story</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7909</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Thank you! Stretch Goal for the 2025 Colossal Fund</title>
      <link>https://blog.ifcomp.org/post/794594738802196480</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the incredible generosity of our community, the 2025 Colossal Fund has already reached its $8,000 goal! We are deeply grateful to everyone who has contributed so far. </p><p>As always, 80% of Colossal Fund proceeds will be distributed among the top two-thirds of IFComp finishers. This year marked the second-highest number of entries in IFComp history! That means more authors will receive a share of the cash prize pool, but with the funds spread across more recipients, each individual prize is a little smaller than we anticipated.</p><p><b>That’s why we’re setting a stretch goal of $10,000.</b> Reaching this new milestone will boost the prize amounts.</p><p>If you haven’t yet donated and would like to help us reach our stretch goal, please visit <a href="https://ifcomp.org/">IFComp.org</a> and click the big blue Donate button. You can choose to be recognized on our donor page or listed anonymously. Every contribution, large or small, strengthens the prize pool and directly supports the authors who make IFComp possible.</p><p>As ever, the remaining 20% of Colossal Fund proceeds support the management of IFComp and other programs of the Interactive Fiction Technology Foundation, which you can learn more about <a href="https://iftechfoundation.org/programs/">here</a>.</p><p>Thank you once again for your generosity, and for helping us celebrate the creativity and dedication of the interactive fiction community!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.ifcomp.org/post/794594738802196480</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Spike Lee’s &#39;Highest 2 Lowest&#39; and 6 Other Akira Kurosawa Adaptations</title>
      <link>https://blog.finaldraft.com/spike-lees-highest-2-lowest-and-6-other-akira-kurosawa-adaptations</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"> 
         <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/spike-lees-highest-2-lowest-and-6-other-akira-kurosawa-adaptations" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"> <img src="https://blog.finaldraft.com/hubfs/Denzel%20Washington%20in%20Highest%202%20Lowest.png" alt="Denzel Washington in Highest 2 Lowest" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"> </a> 
        </div> 
        <p>With Spike Lee’s newest film, <em>Highest 2 Lowest</em>, the acclaimed New York director not only reteams for the fifth time with his Academy Award-winning muse, the great Denzel Washington, but joins a lineage of distinguished filmmakers who have adapted the works of legendary Japanese filmmaker Akira Kurosawa.&nbsp;<br><br>The new film is a reimagining of Kurosawa’s 1963 classic, <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0057565/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">High and Low</a>, about a business tycoon thrown into a moral crisis when his chauffeur’s son is kidnapped and held for an enormous ransom. Kurosawa adapted the original film from a police procedural book written by New York crime author Evan Hunter, reinterpreting the text to add a deeper pathos and exploration of class in a changing post-war Japan.&nbsp;<br><br>But this was far from the first time Kurosawa had adapted a film from previous works of western pop culture. Frequently collaborating with screenwriters like Hideo Oguni, Shinobu Hashimoto and Ryûzô Kikushima, Kurosawa found influence for his samurai films, dramas and contemporary thrillers alike in American suspense yarns, John Ford westerns and the plays of William Shakespeare (<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050613/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">Throne Of Blood</a> (1957), <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0054460/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">The Bad Sleep Well</a> (1960) and <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0089881/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">Ran</a> (1985) all owe a debt to The Bard). While Kurosawa was always generous in crediting his influences from across the globe, his acclaimed films are unique in how often and in what a broad range of filmmaking styles they’ve been reinterpreted as well.<br><br>From a star-making 1960s spaghetti western to a recent low-key British Oscar nominee, Kurosawa’s storytelling fingerprints have echoed through history, across countries and genres. Even filmmakers who haven’t remade his films explicitly, like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?si=sWjOwucg28eP3HZC&amp;v=E9V2T1ONA2I&amp;feature=youtu.be">George Lucas</a> and <a href="http://youtube.com/watch?si=sDe_axLe2K5ASD_K&amp;v=ErelcWcNelQ&amp;feature=youtu.be">Martin Scorsese</a>, are still quick to acknowledge the extraordinary influence his cinema has had on their work.&nbsp;<br><br>By filtering aspects of Hollywood genre cinema and western literature through his own culture and distinct cinematic language, Kurosawa became an international star, and subsequently reinvigorated countless western storytellers. In studying Kurosawa’s influence, one finds an ever-lengthening daisy chain of inspirations and remakes whose links have traveled the better part of a century to arrive at one of this year’s most high profile films by a modern master in his own right.&nbsp;<br><br>Here are 7 English-language reinterpretations of the great Japanese master, Akira Kurosawa.&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.finaldraft.com/spike-lees-highest-2-lowest-and-6-other-akira-kurosawa-adaptations</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Scriptnotes, Episode 701: Connections, Transcript</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-701-connections-transcript</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The original post for this episode can be found here. John August: Hello, and welcome. My name is John August. Craig Mazin: My name is Craig Mazin. John: You’re listening to Episode 701 of Scriptnotes. It’s a podcast about screenwriting and things that are interesting to screenwriters. Today on the show, how do you leverage [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-701-connections-transcript">Scriptnotes, Episode 701: Connections, Transcript</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23445</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How To Use Final Draft: The Outline Editor</title>
      <link>https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-use-final-draft-the-outline-editor</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"> 
         <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-use-final-draft-the-outline-editor" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"> <img src="https://blog.finaldraft.com/hubfs/Image%20of%20people%20sitting%20in%20a%20circle%20working%20on%20computers%20with%20the%20words%20Tech%20Tips%20off%20to%20the%20side.png" alt="Image of people sitting on the floor in a circle working on their computers" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"> </a> 
        </div> 
        <h2>Outlining for Screenwriting Success</h2> 
        <p>Have an idea for a movie or TV pilot and want to write a screenplay, but you don’t know where to begin?&nbsp;<br><br>Whether you’re a professional screenwriter or a beginner, it’s best to <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/to-outline-or-not-to-outline-your-screenplay-that-is">outline beforehand</a>. Outlining helps you figure out how you’re going to tell your story and structure it appropriately (e.g. most feature scripts follow the classic <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/three-act-structure-the-foundation-of-screenwriting">three-act structure</a>).&nbsp;<br><br>Not only does Final Draft offer <a href="https://www.finaldraft.com/company/why-screenwriting-software/">industry standard formatting</a> for feature and TV scripts, but it also has various <span style="font-weight: bold;">outlining tools</span> that can help you construct and piece together your story at the earliest stages — one of the most important being <span style="font-weight: bold;">the Outline Editor</span>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-use-final-draft-the-outline-editor</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Scriptnotes, Episode 700: The Live Call-In Show, Transcript</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-700-the-live-call-in-show-transcript</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The original post for this episode can be found here. John August: Hello, and welcome. My name is John August. Craig Mazin: My name is Craig Mazin. John: You’re listening to episode 700 of Scriptnotes, a podcast about screenwriting and things that are interesting to screenwriters. Today on the show, we are doing something we [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-700-the-live-call-in-show-transcript">Scriptnotes, Episode 700: The Live Call-In Show, Transcript</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23441</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Mystery in a Screenplay</title>
      <link>https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-write-a-mystery-in-a-screenplay</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"> 
         <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-write-a-mystery-in-a-screenplay" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"> <img src="https://blog.finaldraft.com/hubfs/Brad%20Pitt%20and%20Morgan%20Freeman%20in%20Se7en%20(1).png" alt="Brad Pitt and Morgan Freeman sit around a coffee table studying evidence in Se7en" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"> </a> 
        </div> 
        <p>Mysteries are one of the oldest and most effective storytelling devices. Audiences are drawn to &nbsp;them because they are challenging and engaging. It’s a step above a normal story narrative because a good mystery is not just entertaining - it’s interactive. The audience lives vicariously through the protagonist(s), creating an even more visceral cinematic experience.<br><br>When we watch movies full of mystery, we become detectives ourselves. We’re tasked with looking at the clues, finding the most obvious suspects, and solving the mystery. But writing a mystery isn’t just about withholding information. It’s about <em>how</em> and <em>when</em> you reveal it. It’s about giving the audience just enough to keep them invested and guessing.&nbsp;<br><br>Then there’s the added thrill of anticipation and expectation. The best mysteries play with audience anticipation, and do all they can to subvert their expectations to create new, unique, memorable, and cathartic cinematic experiences.&nbsp;<br><br>Here we offer a beginner’s guide to writing mysteries in your screenplays. Let’s see if we can anticipate your questions, subvert your expectations with pro writing tips on the subject, and offer you a new outlook on how to write effective mystery.&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-write-a-mystery-in-a-screenplay</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Work with Poetry Projects in Scrivener</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/how-to-create-and-work-with-poetry-projects-in-scrivener</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7753</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Getting Period Right</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/getting-period-right</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>John and Craig ask, how do you keep your period films from being a boring history lesson? They offer ten tips to keep your setting from taking over your story, defining the scope of your research, and how to balance the reality of the era with what’s relevant to audiences today. We also follow up [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/getting-period-right">Getting Period Right</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23434</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Anthropic Settlement – what it is and isn’t (and who could get paid)</title>
      <link>https://www.authorsalliance.org/2025/09/07/the-anthropic-settlement-what-it-is-and-isnt-and-who-could-get-paid/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[EDIT: On Sunday evening, Judge Alsup granted the motion for a hearing on Monday, September 8th, but expressed disappointment over [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.authorsalliance.org/?p=12155</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Bartz v. Anthropic: A Preliminary Look at What LibGen Books May Be Included in the Class Action</title>
      <link>https://www.authorsalliance.org/2025/09/05/bartz-v-anthropic-a-preliminary-look-at-what-libgen-books-may-be-included-in-the-class-action/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[For this post, we relied heavily on the help of Charles Horn, self-described “metadata wrangler,” for data analysis.&#160; As readers [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.authorsalliance.org/?p=12144</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Write Now with Scrivener, Episode no. 54: Tim Queeney, Author of a History of Rope</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/write-now-with-scrivener-episode-no-54-tim-queeny-author-of-a-history-of-rope</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7558</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Return of the Spec Screenplay Sale</title>
      <link>https://blog.finaldraft.com/the-return-of-the-spec-screenplay-sale</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"> 
         <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/the-return-of-the-spec-screenplay-sale" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"> <img src="https://blog.finaldraft.com/hubfs/Graph%20Going%20Up%20With%20Rocket.jpeg" alt="Graph going up with Rocket " class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"> </a> 
        </div> 
        <p>In my article <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-much-money-can-you-make-selling-a-screenplay"><span>“How Much Money Can You Make Selling a Screenplay,”</span></a> I wrote about the return of the spec sale and how there were a handful of big sales in 2024. Well, it’s looking like 2025 is going to be even better for screenwriters who have written original screenplays.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.finaldraft.com/the-return-of-the-spec-screenplay-sale</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Last Looks</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/last-looks-2</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>John and Craig welcome back producer Megana Rao, who has a question: how do you polish a script before sending it out? From obvious things like typos and title pages to tougher choices like cutting and transitions, they look at what to consider on a final pass so you can email your script with confidence. [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/last-looks-2">Last Looks</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23415</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the 31st Annual IFComp!</title>
      <link>https://blog.ifcomp.org/post/793498286286864384</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h1><b>Welcome to the 31st Annual IFComp!</b></h1><p>The <a href="https://ifcomp.org/">2025 Interactive Fiction Competition</a> has officially begun!</p><p>For the next six weeks, players and judges around the world will be diving into this year’s crop of brand-new interactive fiction. We’re delighted to share that <i><b>85 entries(!!) </b></i>have been submitted this year. We&rsquo;re excited to see so many authors tossing their hat into the ring.</p><p>As always, you don’t need to play every entry to be a judge. You only need to <b>play and rate </b><i><b>at least five </b></i><b>entries</b> to submit a ballot. Whether you’re a seasoned IFComp veteran or joining us for the very first time, we welcome you and hope you’ll find plenty to discover and enjoy!</p><p><b>What&rsquo;s New for 2025<br/></b>You can now choose whether or not to see content warnings. Authors still provide them, and they&rsquo;ll be shown by default, but if you’d prefer not to see them (to avoid spoilers or for any other reason), you’ll find a setting at the top of the ballot that lets you hide them.</p><p><b>The Colossal Fund<br/></b>We’re excited to share that this year’s Colossal Fund is already halfway to its goal! Thanks to the generosity of donors, we’re well on our way to ensuring a strong pool of prizes. If you’d like to learn more about the Fund and how to contribute cash (or other prizes), visit h<a href="https://ifcomp.org/about/prizes">ttps://ifcomp.org/about/prizes</a></p><p><b>Our Awards Ceremony<br/></b>As in years past, we will celebrate the conclusion of this year’s competition with a virtual awards ceremony, where we announce the results and recognize the authors. The awards ceremony will be held on T<a href="https://www.twitch.tv/interactivefictioncomp">witch </a>at 4:00 PM Eastern Oct 18. To confirm what time the awards stream will be for you in your time zone, c<a href="https://everytimezone.com/s/4849cb8d">heck here.</a></p><p><b>On the Topic of the UK&rsquo;s Online Safety Act<br/></b>This year brings change for many authors and all of our UK judges: the United Kingdom’s O<a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/publications/online-safety-act-explainer/online-safety-act-explainer">nline Safety Act </a>(OSA), which restricts access to a wide range of content that could be harmful to children. We spent considerable time investigating whether a third-party provider could offer age verification for our UK users without us needing to retain sensitive information, but we were not able to implement a workable solution before launch. We are still pursuing that possibility, but it may not be in place until next year’s competition.</p><p>Until earlier this week, we thought we’d need to geoblock all entries for UK users. That was something we very much wanted to avoid. Fortunately, we were able to put in place a more limited, case-by-case approach. With 85 entries, over two dozen of which arrived after we learned of this option, it was not possible to thoroughly play every entry beforehand. Instead, we based initial geoblock decisions on a mix of author-provided content warnings and notes from our Curation Team.</p><p>Ofcom has <a href="https://www.ofcom.org.uk/siteassets/resources/documents/consultations/category-1-10-weeks/statement-protecting-children-from-harms-online/main-document/guidance-on-content-harmful-to-children.pdf">published guidance</a> to help organizations navigate the OSA, including exceptions to the law. At the recommendation of our attorney, we are utilizing their guidance to inform our decisions as we review entries. All authors whose entries were selected for geoblocking in the UK were notified and invited to discuss their entry with us if they felt their work was acceptable for all ages under the OSA. After reviewing additional text from entries, and weighing that text against exceptions provided by the OSA, we lifted geoblocks for several authors.</p><p>We do not love restricting content and we understand that many in the community are frustrated, but we are obligated to comply with the law for UK users. For transparency: as of the time of this post, 24 of 85 entries are geoblocked in the UK. It is possible that this number may shift slightly in the coming days as more authors reach out to us.</p><p>In response to a question we’ve already received, we do not intend to make a new Author Rule to address the OSA. It is a law external to the IFComp, and it does not affect all users. As case law develops, and as the broader internet learns to navigate the OSA, authors will likely get a clearer sense of what may or may not be restricted. We may also be able to implement age verification for users who wish to take advantage of it. Regardless, our preference remains the same: authors should write whatever they want to write to tell the stories that they wish to tell for the audiences they wish to reach.</p><p><b>Generative AI in IFComp<br/></b>Another evolving area is the use of generative artificial intelligence (GAI). The community remains divided on its role in interactive fiction, and the technology itself continues to change rapidly. Our stance for the past two years has been to require transparency but to otherwise allow GAI. On the entry form, authors are asked to declare most uses of GAI in their work. After last year’s competition, we expected to see a flood of feedback about AI in the post-comp survey. In reality, only about 10 percent of respondents mentioned it. Based on that, we kept the same policy for 2025.</p><p>We plan to use this year’s post-competition survey to float some ideas about new approaches on GAI in the competition, including possible rule changes, and invite your input. The survey will also include space for you to share rule ideas of your own. We recognize that it is unlikely that we’ll land in a place that makes everyone happy, but we’ll endeavor to do our best to find common ground. We intend to finalize decisions for 2026 by the end of this calendar year, so that authors have plenty of time to plan.</p><p>Anything we haven’t covered? Still got questions? Email us at ifcomp@ifcomp.org</p><p>Thank you in advance for judging!<br/>– Jacqueline Ashwell,<br/>September 2025</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.ifcomp.org/post/793498286286864384</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
