<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <atom:link href="https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/writing.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <channel>
    <title>Writing</title>
    <link>https://rsdoiel.github.io/antenna/writing.xml</link>
    <lastBuildDate>24 Sep 25 15:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>antenna/0.0.8</generator>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Writing for microdramas, aka verticals</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/writing-for-microdramas-aka-verticals</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Over the last six months, we’ve discussed microdramas (aka verticals) several times on Scriptnotes. For readers who don’t know, microdramas are a format originating in Asia in which a filmed narrative is broken into very short episodes intended to be watched on your phone. They’re often called verticals because they’re shot to be watched on [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/writing-for-microdramas-aka-verticals">Writing for microdramas, aka verticals</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23471</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Use Custom Document Templates in Scrivener</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/how-to-create-and-use-custom-document-templates-in-scrivener</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7954</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Short Films and Existential Threats</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/short-films-and-existential-threats</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>John and Craig discuss short films: what makes a great short, when should you make one, and what should you realistically expect out of it? We also update our predictions on whether the career of “screenwriter” can survive potential global catastrophes. We then answer listener questions on staff writer wages and using URLs in a [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/short-films-and-existential-threats">Short Films and Existential Threats</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <enclosure url="http://media.blubrry.com/scriptnotes/traffic.libsyn.com/scriptnotes/705standard.mp3" length="5242880" type="audio/mpeg" />
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23466</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Are Copyright Anxiety and Legal Chill Hampering Your Work?</title>
      <link>https://www.authorsalliance.org/2025/09/18/are-copyright-anxiety-and-legal-chill-hampering-your-work/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[This is guest post by Amanda Wakaruk, Jane Secker, and Chris Morrison. Amanda Wakaruk has worked as a copyright librarian [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.authorsalliance.org/?p=12175</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>BookTok and Beyond: How Young Readers Are Reviving Physical Bookstores</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/booktok-and-beyond-how-young-readers-are-reviving-physical-bookstores</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7932</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Robert Redford, RIP</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/robert-redford-rip</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Robert Redford’s remarkable career as an actor and director enabled his biggest triumph, the Sundance Institute. I was lucky to be part of it.</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/robert-redford-rip">Robert Redford, RIP</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23458</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Places, Everyone</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/places-everyone</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>John welcomes back Liz Hannah (The Post, The Girl from Plainville) to discuss how to construct and communicate setting in a script. They talk about the balance between establishing a sense of space while avoiding the beginner’s mistake of over-blocking. We also follow up on accountability groups, last looks, and French composers. Then, we answer [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/places-everyone">Places, Everyone</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23449</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How To Write Dialogue in a Story</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/how-to-write-dialogue-in-a-story</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7909</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Thank you! Stretch Goal for the 2025 Colossal Fund</title>
      <link>https://blog.ifcomp.org/post/794594738802196480</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Thanks to the incredible generosity of our community, the 2025 Colossal Fund has already reached its $8,000 goal! We are deeply grateful to everyone who has contributed so far. </p><p>As always, 80% of Colossal Fund proceeds will be distributed among the top two-thirds of IFComp finishers. This year marked the second-highest number of entries in IFComp history! That means more authors will receive a share of the cash prize pool, but with the funds spread across more recipients, each individual prize is a little smaller than we anticipated.</p><p><b>That’s why we’re setting a stretch goal of $10,000.</b> Reaching this new milestone will boost the prize amounts.</p><p>If you haven’t yet donated and would like to help us reach our stretch goal, please visit <a href="https://ifcomp.org/">IFComp.org</a> and click the big blue Donate button. You can choose to be recognized on our donor page or listed anonymously. Every contribution, large or small, strengthens the prize pool and directly supports the authors who make IFComp possible.</p><p>As ever, the remaining 20% of Colossal Fund proceeds support the management of IFComp and other programs of the Interactive Fiction Technology Foundation, which you can learn more about <a href="https://iftechfoundation.org/programs/">here</a>.</p><p>Thank you once again for your generosity, and for helping us celebrate the creativity and dedication of the interactive fiction community!</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.ifcomp.org/post/794594738802196480</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Spike Lee’s &#39;Highest 2 Lowest&#39; and 6 Other Akira Kurosawa Adaptations</title>
      <link>https://blog.finaldraft.com/spike-lees-highest-2-lowest-and-6-other-akira-kurosawa-adaptations</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"> 
         <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/spike-lees-highest-2-lowest-and-6-other-akira-kurosawa-adaptations" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"> <img src="https://blog.finaldraft.com/hubfs/Denzel%20Washington%20in%20Highest%202%20Lowest.png" alt="Denzel Washington in Highest 2 Lowest" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"> </a> 
        </div> 
        <p>With Spike Lee’s newest film, <em>Highest 2 Lowest</em>, the acclaimed New York director not only reteams for the fifth time with his Academy Award-winning muse, the great Denzel Washington, but joins a lineage of distinguished filmmakers who have adapted the works of legendary Japanese filmmaker Akira Kurosawa.&nbsp;<br><br>The new film is a reimagining of Kurosawa’s 1963 classic, <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0057565/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">High and Low</a>, about a business tycoon thrown into a moral crisis when his chauffeur’s son is kidnapped and held for an enormous ransom. Kurosawa adapted the original film from a police procedural book written by New York crime author Evan Hunter, reinterpreting the text to add a deeper pathos and exploration of class in a changing post-war Japan.&nbsp;<br><br>But this was far from the first time Kurosawa had adapted a film from previous works of western pop culture. Frequently collaborating with screenwriters like Hideo Oguni, Shinobu Hashimoto and Ryûzô Kikushima, Kurosawa found influence for his samurai films, dramas and contemporary thrillers alike in American suspense yarns, John Ford westerns and the plays of William Shakespeare (<a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0050613/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">Throne Of Blood</a> (1957), <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0054460/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">The Bad Sleep Well</a> (1960) and <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0089881/?ref_=ext_shr_lnk" style="font-style: italic;">Ran</a> (1985) all owe a debt to The Bard). While Kurosawa was always generous in crediting his influences from across the globe, his acclaimed films are unique in how often and in what a broad range of filmmaking styles they’ve been reinterpreted as well.<br><br>From a star-making 1960s spaghetti western to a recent low-key British Oscar nominee, Kurosawa’s storytelling fingerprints have echoed through history, across countries and genres. Even filmmakers who haven’t remade his films explicitly, like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?si=sWjOwucg28eP3HZC&amp;v=E9V2T1ONA2I&amp;feature=youtu.be">George Lucas</a> and <a href="http://youtube.com/watch?si=sDe_axLe2K5ASD_K&amp;v=ErelcWcNelQ&amp;feature=youtu.be">Martin Scorsese</a>, are still quick to acknowledge the extraordinary influence his cinema has had on their work.&nbsp;<br><br>By filtering aspects of Hollywood genre cinema and western literature through his own culture and distinct cinematic language, Kurosawa became an international star, and subsequently reinvigorated countless western storytellers. In studying Kurosawa’s influence, one finds an ever-lengthening daisy chain of inspirations and remakes whose links have traveled the better part of a century to arrive at one of this year’s most high profile films by a modern master in his own right.&nbsp;<br><br>Here are 7 English-language reinterpretations of the great Japanese master, Akira Kurosawa.&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.finaldraft.com/spike-lees-highest-2-lowest-and-6-other-akira-kurosawa-adaptations</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Scriptnotes, Episode 701: Connections, Transcript</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-701-connections-transcript</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The original post for this episode can be found here. John August: Hello, and welcome. My name is John August. Craig Mazin: My name is Craig Mazin. John: You’re listening to Episode 701 of Scriptnotes. It’s a podcast about screenwriting and things that are interesting to screenwriters. Today on the show, how do you leverage [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-701-connections-transcript">Scriptnotes, Episode 701: Connections, Transcript</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23445</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How To Use Final Draft: The Outline Editor</title>
      <link>https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-use-final-draft-the-outline-editor</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"> 
         <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-use-final-draft-the-outline-editor" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"> <img src="https://blog.finaldraft.com/hubfs/Image%20of%20people%20sitting%20in%20a%20circle%20working%20on%20computers%20with%20the%20words%20Tech%20Tips%20off%20to%20the%20side.png" alt="Image of people sitting on the floor in a circle working on their computers" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"> </a> 
        </div> 
        <h2>Outlining for Screenwriting Success</h2> 
        <p>Have an idea for a movie or TV pilot and want to write a screenplay, but you don’t know where to begin?&nbsp;<br><br>Whether you’re a professional screenwriter or a beginner, it’s best to <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/to-outline-or-not-to-outline-your-screenplay-that-is">outline beforehand</a>. Outlining helps you figure out how you’re going to tell your story and structure it appropriately (e.g. most feature scripts follow the classic <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/three-act-structure-the-foundation-of-screenwriting">three-act structure</a>).&nbsp;<br><br>Not only does Final Draft offer <a href="https://www.finaldraft.com/company/why-screenwriting-software/">industry standard formatting</a> for feature and TV scripts, but it also has various <span style="font-weight: bold;">outlining tools</span> that can help you construct and piece together your story at the earliest stages — one of the most important being <span style="font-weight: bold;">the Outline Editor</span>.</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-use-final-draft-the-outline-editor</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Scriptnotes, Episode 700: The Live Call-In Show, Transcript</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-700-the-live-call-in-show-transcript</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The original post for this episode can be found here. John August: Hello, and welcome. My name is John August. Craig Mazin: My name is Craig Mazin. John: You’re listening to episode 700 of Scriptnotes, a podcast about screenwriting and things that are interesting to screenwriters. Today on the show, we are doing something we [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/scriptnotes-episode-700-the-live-call-in-show-transcript">Scriptnotes, Episode 700: The Live Call-In Show, Transcript</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23441</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Mystery in a Screenplay</title>
      <link>https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-write-a-mystery-in-a-screenplay</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"> 
         <a href="https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-write-a-mystery-in-a-screenplay" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"> <img src="https://blog.finaldraft.com/hubfs/Brad%20Pitt%20and%20Morgan%20Freeman%20in%20Se7en%20(1).png" alt="Brad Pitt and Morgan Freeman sit around a coffee table studying evidence in Se7en" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"> </a> 
        </div> 
        <p>Mysteries are one of the oldest and most effective storytelling devices. Audiences are drawn to &nbsp;them because they are challenging and engaging. It’s a step above a normal story narrative because a good mystery is not just entertaining - it’s interactive. The audience lives vicariously through the protagonist(s), creating an even more visceral cinematic experience.<br><br>When we watch movies full of mystery, we become detectives ourselves. We’re tasked with looking at the clues, finding the most obvious suspects, and solving the mystery. But writing a mystery isn’t just about withholding information. It’s about <em>how</em> and <em>when</em> you reveal it. It’s about giving the audience just enough to keep them invested and guessing.&nbsp;<br><br>Then there’s the added thrill of anticipation and expectation. The best mysteries play with audience anticipation, and do all they can to subvert their expectations to create new, unique, memorable, and cathartic cinematic experiences.&nbsp;<br><br>Here we offer a beginner’s guide to writing mysteries in your screenplays. Let’s see if we can anticipate your questions, subvert your expectations with pro writing tips on the subject, and offer you a new outlook on how to write effective mystery.&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://blog.finaldraft.com/how-to-write-a-mystery-in-a-screenplay</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>How to Create and Work with Poetry Projects in Scrivener</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/how-to-create-and-work-with-poetry-projects-in-scrivener</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7753</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Getting Period Right</title>
      <link>https://johnaugust.com/2025/getting-period-right</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>John and Craig ask, how do you keep your period films from being a boring history lesson? They offer ten tips to keep your setting from taking over your story, defining the scope of your research, and how to balance the reality of the era with what’s relevant to audiences today. We also follow up [&#8230;]</p>
        The post <a href="https://johnaugust.com/2025/getting-period-right">Getting Period Right</a> first appeared on <a href="https://johnaugust.com">John August</a>.]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://johnaugust.com/?p=23434</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>The Anthropic Settlement – what it is and isn’t (and who could get paid)</title>
      <link>https://www.authorsalliance.org/2025/09/07/the-anthropic-settlement-what-it-is-and-isnt-and-who-could-get-paid/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[EDIT: On Sunday evening, Judge Alsup granted the motion for a hearing on Monday, September 8th, but expressed disappointment over [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.authorsalliance.org/?p=12155</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Bartz v. Anthropic: A Preliminary Look at What LibGen Books May Be Included in the Class Action</title>
      <link>https://www.authorsalliance.org/2025/09/05/bartz-v-anthropic-a-preliminary-look-at-what-libgen-books-may-be-included-in-the-class-action/</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[For this post, we relied heavily on the help of Charles Horn, self-described “metadata wrangler,” for data analysis.&#160; As readers [&#8230;]]]>
      </description>
      <guid>cid://https://www.authorsalliance.org/?p=12144</guid>
    </item>    <item>
      <title>Write Now with Scrivener, Episode no. 54: Tim Queeney, Author of a History of Rope</title>
      <link>https://www.literatureandlatte.com/blog/write-now-with-scrivener-episode-no-54-tim-queeny-author-of-a-history-of-rope</link>
      <guid>cid://https://www.literatureandlatte.com/?p=7558</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
